<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/bodleian/consolidated-tei-schema/master/msdesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/bodleian/consolidated-tei-schema/master/msdesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="manuscript_1">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>MS Add. 3303(3)</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Cambridge University Library</publisher>

                <availability default="false" status="restricted" xml:id="displayImageRights">
                    <p part="N">Zooming image © Cambridge University Library, All rights
                        reserved.</p>
                </availability>
                <availability default="false" status="restricted" xml:id="downloadImageRights">
                    <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/">Images made
                        available for download are licensed under a Creative Commons
                        Attribution-NonCommercial 3.0 Unported License (CC BY-NC 3.0)</licence>
                </availability>
                <availability default="false" status="restricted" xml:id="metadataRights">
                    <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/">This
                        metadata is licensed under a Creative Commons
                        Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivs 3.0 Unported License.</licence>
                </availability>

            <availability xml:id="watermark" status="restricted"><licence>Cambridge University Library (CC BY-NC 4.0)</licence></availability></publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc default="false">
                <msDesc status="draft" xml:id="MS-ADD-03303-00003" xml:lang="en">
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <institution>Cambridge University</institution>
                        <repository>Cambridge University Library</repository>
                        <collection>Medieval Manuscripts</collection>
                        <idno type="shelfmark">MS Add. 3303(3)</idno>

                    </msIdentifier>
                    <head>A leaf from a folding almanac</head>
                    <msContents>

                        <summary>
                            <seg type="para">Cambridge, University Library, MS Add. 3303(3) is a
                                single leaf of parchment that once formed part of a late medieval
                                English folding almanac, of the kind described and analysed by
                                Hilary Carey and J.P. Gumbert. It is not recorded among their
                                published lists, though it is noted in part in the <bibl><hi rend="italic">Catalogue of incipits of mediaeval scientific
                                        writings in Latin</hi></bibl>. Thanks to the data assembled
                                by Carey and Gumbert concerning manuscripts of this kind, and to the
                                digitisation of many by the libraries that hold them, it is a
                                straightforward undertaking to place this further example in
                                context.</seg>
                            <seg type="para">The presence of both the Vein Man and Zodiac Man
                                schematic diagrams, which are not found among the contents of
                                continental folding calendars, confirms that this leaf is English,
                                bringing the total number of such almanacs to 31. All of the
                                evidence points to Add. 3303(3) belonging among the earlier
                                manuscripts in the corpus. Most examples that date to before c. 1450
                                fold – like this one – into 2 x 3 compartments, whereas most later
                                ones folded into 2 x 4 compartments. Without the accompanying
                                calendars and astronomic tables and canons, precise dating is not
                                possible, but the style of decoration suggests that it was made at
                                the very end of the 14th century or at the very beginning of the
                                15th century, perhaps in London.</seg>
                            <seg type="para">The tab that once connected Add. 3303(3) to other
                                leaves is still visible beneath the feet of Zodiac Man. Since the
                                leaf has been flattened and is mounted on a paper guard along its
                                left-hand edge, it is not now possible to reconstruct the pattern of
                                folding (as Gumbert has done for other examples). Its dimensions
                                when open are 290 x 205-210mm and when closed approximately 145 x
                                65-72mm, placing it among the larger of the surviving examples. It
                                bears no evidence of having been trimmed along any edge. The
                                measurements of height, both open and closed, fall in the middle of
                                the range, but Add. 3303(3) is wider than most other almanacs: only
                                    <bibl subtype="external" type="MS"><ref target="http://searcharchives.bl.uk/IAMS_VU2:LSCOP_BL:IAMS040-002051157">British Library, Harley MS 5311</ref></bibl> is larger,
                                which has compartments of 76 mm width, and also folds 2 x 3. Add.
                                3303(3) is blank on the verso, though this need not undermine the
                                hypothesis that it was once accompanied by other leaves: the
                                calendar leaves of <bibl subtype="external" type="MS"><ref target="https://i-share-nby.primo.exlibrisgroup.com/permalink/01CARLI_NBY/i5mcb2/alma991820368805867">Chicago, Newberry Library, MS Case 127</ref></bibl> contain
                                titles on the verso, but those bearing various tables (f. 5) and the
                                unexecuted Zodiac and Vein Man diagrams (f. 6) do not.</seg>
                            <seg type="para">Add. 3303(3) joins nine other almanacs in containing
                                both the Vein Man and Zodiac Man diagrams. A further two have the
                                accompanying text, with spaces for the diagrams left unfilled. Three
                                other examples feature only the Vein Man, and three only the Zodiac
                                Man, plus a further one where that diagram was not executed. Twelve
                                almanacs feature neither diagram. Most of those that contain both
                                date from the second half of the century, so Add. 3303(3) joins only
                                two other survivals from the early 15th century: <bibl subtype="external" type="MS">Harley MS 5311</bibl> and the
                                privately owned almanac studied by C.H. Talbot in 1961.</seg>
                            <seg type="para">As is typical, Vein Man is a drawing, here executed in
                                black ink, with slight shading in places and splotches on the nose
                                and shoulder. Again typically, the image occupies a rectangular
                                field with the text in columns on all four sides, rather than in
                                roundels floating or arranged into a circular pattern as in other
                                instances. It is common too, albeit mostly among the earlier
                                examples, for Zodiac Man to be painted, as here, and to occupy an
                                arrow-shaped space. The figure of Zodiac Man is now very dark: was
                                this once silver, which has now oxidised? Whether oxidised silver or
                                simply a dark pigment, this is unique among the corpus of English
                                almanacs and may be unusual among depictions of Zodiac Man in other
                                manuscripts besides almanacs. The figure is on a coloured ground
                                with hatched pattern, and surrounded by a gold border, in similar
                                style to the 'Talbot' almanac, <bibl subtype="external" type="MS">Cambridge, Magdalene College, Pepys MS 1662</bibl>, and <bibl subtype="external" type="MS">Harley MS 5311</bibl>. In its
                                complete form, and given the quality of decoration, Add. 3303(3)
                                would probably have belonged among Gumbert’s 'luxury group': like
                                those examples, it may have been accompanied by another leaf showing
                                the Ring of Urines, as well as the usual calendars and lunar tables,
                                featuring illuminated initials and other decorative flourishes.
                                Given the expense lavished on this leaf, it seems fair to echo Peter
                                Jones' judgement that the almanac to which it belonged would have
                                been 'owned with pride and [was] not just [a] working tool'.</seg>
                            <seg type="para">Both the Vein Man and Zodiac Man diagrams belong to a
                                much broader visual tradition, in both folding calendars and
                                manuscripts, to say nothing of their continued transmission in
                                print. Further stylistic comparisons within this small corpus would
                                probably not be instructive; wider analysis of the figures,
                                variations in their gestures, the emblematic zodiac signs and other
                                features would benefit from art-historical expertise. It was a more
                                than purely ornamental object, however. The accompanying
                                instructional texts, which tailored the diagrams for the correct
                                application and appropriate timing of blood-letting, indicate the
                                intention to put it to practical use. This is in all likelihood a
                                further example of Carey’s 'specialist medical almanacs', designed
                                to aid the practice of lunar medicine at a simple level.</seg>
                            <seg type="para">Finally, and perhaps most significantly, MS Add.
                                3303(3) is one of only two examples in which Vein Man and Zodiac Man
                                are directly juxtaposed with one another on the same leaf. Besides
                                concentrating the artist's work on a single leaf, which may have
                                been more convenient to execute, this arrangement makes visually
                                explicit the conceptual connection between the two diagrams: that
                                blood-letting from a particular part of the body was determined by
                                the ailment to be addressed (Vein Man) and its timing governed by
                                the position of the moon in relation to specific constellations
                                (Zodiac Man). This is one step from 'fused' diagrams, with Vein and
                                Zodiac Man are overlain one another in a single figure and the
                                accompanying texts brought together. </seg>
                            <p>Dr James Freeman<lb/> Medieval Manuscripts Specialist<lb/> Cambridge
                                University Library</p>
                        </summary>

                        <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>

                        <msItem n="1">
                            <locus from="recto" to="recto">Recto</locus>
                            <title>Guide to locations of veins for blood-letting</title>
                            <incipit><locus from="recto" to="recto">Recto</locus>: Uena cardiaca id
                                est cordis uel corallis inciditur pro passionibus
                                spiritualium</incipit>
                            <explicit><locus from="recto" to="recto">Recto</locus>: Uena sub genu ab
                                extra incisa inuat craticam et uescaticam [sic: for nefreticam] et
                                crura</explicit>
                            <listBibl>
                                <bibl>TK 1680g</bibl>
                                <bibl>eTK t0319930000</bibl>
                            </listBibl>

                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="2">
                            <locus from="recto" to="recto">Recto</locus>
                            <title>Guide to the correct timing of blood-letting</title>
                            <incipit><locus from="recto" to="recto">Recto</locus>: Aries. Caue ab
                                incisione in capite uel in facie et ne incidas uenam
                                capitalem</incipit>
                            <explicit><locus from="recto" to="recto">Recto</locus>: Pisces: Caue ne
                                incidaris in pedibus</explicit>
                            <listBibl>
                                <bibl>TK 129m</bibl>
                                <bibl>eTK t0024680000</bibl>
                                <bibl>eTK t0024690000</bibl>
                            </listBibl>

                            <note>Verso is blank.</note>
                        </msItem>

                    </msContents>

                    <physDesc>

                        <objectDesc form="faltbuch">
                            <supportDesc material="perg">
                                <support>
                                    <material>Parchment</material>
                                </support>

                                <extent>
                                    <seg type="leaf">
                                        <measure quantity="1" type="leaf">1 leaf</measure>. </seg>
                                    <seg type="dimensions"> Unfolded dimensions: <dimensions type="leaf" unit="mm">
                                            <height quantity="290">290</height>
                                            <width max="210" min="205">205-210</width>
                                        </dimensions> Folded dimensions: <dimensions type="other" unit="mm">
                                            <height quantity="145">145</height>
                                            <width max="72" min="65">65-72</width>
                                        </dimensions>
                                    </seg>
                                </extent>

                                <condition>
                                    <p>Folded into 2 x 3 compartments, with some wear and grime
                                        along the folds. Occasional small losses at the corners of
                                        folds. Two small symmetrical worm holes on either side of
                                        the horizontal fold, which suggest that the leaf was stored
                                        folded in half for a sustained period. The more grimy
                                        condition of the verso of the lower half indicates that it
                                        was facing outwards.</p>
                                </condition>

                            </supportDesc>

                            <layoutDesc>

                                <layout rulingMedium="ink">
                                    <seg type="ruling">Ruled in ink.</seg>
                                </layout>
                            </layoutDesc>
                        </objectDesc>


                        <handDesc>
                            <handNote script="textualisNorthern">
                                <p>Written in a <term type="script">littera textualis</term>
                                    bookhand.</p>
                            </handNote>
                        </handDesc>

                        <decoDesc>

                            <decoNote type="miniature">
                                <p>Two large miniatures: <list>
                                        <item><term ref="http://www.iconclass.org/rkd/49G6223/" type="iconography">Vein Man</term>: drawing in
                                            black, with lines drawn in red ink connecting the
                                            locations of key veins with relevant captions.</item>
                                        <item><term ref="http://www.iconclass.org/rkd/23O5/" type="iconography">Zodiac Man</term>: in an
                                            arrow-shaped field, a painted figure in ?oxidised silver
                                            or dark pigment, bearing the emblems of the zodiac on
                                            various parts of his body, on a checkered ground in red
                                            and green, with an illuminated border. </item>
                                    </list> The style of decoration suggests that it was made at the
                                    very end of the 14th century or at the very beginning of the
                                    15th century, perhaps in London. The style of hair and beady
                                    eyes of the two figures may be a late reflection of the
                                    Westminster style of the Litlyngton Missal (ex inf. Nicholas
                                    Rogers and Lynda Dennison).</p>
                            </decoNote>
                            <decoNote type="flourInit">
                                <p>One-line initials in blue, with red pen infill and limited
                                    marginal flourishing, at the beginning of each caption.</p>
                            </decoNote>

                            <decoNote type="rubrication">Names of the signs of the zodiac written in
                                red in the text accompanying Zodiac Man.</decoNote>
                        </decoDesc>
                    </physDesc>

                    <history>
                        <origin>
                            <origDate calendar="Gregorian" cert="medium" notAfter="1410" notBefore="1390"> Late 14th or early 15th century.</origDate>
                            <origPlace cert="medium" key="place_g7011781">England, perhaps
                                London.</origPlace>
                            <p>See the introductory Summary and Decoration for further details.</p>
                            <listBibl>
                                <bibl>Gumbert (2016)</bibl>
                                <bibl>Carey (2003)</bibl>
                            </listBibl>
                        </origin>

                        <provenance notAfter="1914" notBefore="1914"> </provenance>

                        <acquisition notAfter="1914" notBefore="1914">
                            <p>The fragment is bound into an album with other fragments. It was
                                bound by Wilson and Son of Cambridge in 1914, according to a stamp
                                and note on the front pastedown. According to an unpublished
                                description by Basil Atkinson (see Sources), the leaf came 'from [a]
                                binding in the Library', though there are reasons to doubt this (see
                                Summary).</p>
                        </acquisition>
                    </history>

                    <additional>
                        <adminInfo>
                            <recordHist>
                                <source>This catalogue entry refers to an unpublished description of
                                    the manuscript composed between 1924 and 1960 by <name>
                                        <persName type="display">Basil Atkinson</persName>
                                        <persName type="standard">Atkinson, Basil Ferris
                                            Campbell</persName></name>, now held in the University
                                    Archives (UA ULIB 7/3/72/21).</source>
                            </recordHist>

                            <availability default="false" status="restricted">
                                <p part="N">Entry to read in the Library is permitted only on
                                    presentation of a valid reader's card. For information on
                                    eligibility and admissions procedures, see <ref target="https://www.lib.cam.ac.uk/using-library/joining-library">Joining the Library</ref>). For further information on the
                                    availability of the manuscript, please contact the <ref target="mss@lib.cam.ac.uk">Manuscripts Reading
                                    Room</ref>.</p>
                            </availability>
                        </adminInfo>

                        <listBibl default="false" type="WRAPPER">
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/users/2420388/items/NL82YDRL" type="journalArticle" xml:id="Bober1948">
                                <analytic>
                                    <title level="a">The Zodiacal Miniature of the Très Riches
                                        Heures of the Duke of Berry: Its Sources and Meaning</title>
                                    <idno type="DOI">10.2307/750460</idno>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>Harry</forename>
                                        <surname>Bober</surname>
                                    </author>
                                </analytic>
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="j">Journal of the Warburg and Courtauld
                                        Institutes</title>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
                                        <biblScope unit="page">1-34</biblScope>
                                        <date>1948</date>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                            </biblStruct>

                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/users/2420388/items/DQ5LV366" type="journalArticle" xml:id="Talbot1961">
                                <analytic>
                                    <title level="a">A Mediaeval Physician's Vade Mecum</title>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>C.H.</forename>
                                        <surname>Talbot</surname>
                                    </author>
                                </analytic>
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="j">Journal of the History of Medicine and Allied
                                        Sciences</title>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
                                        <biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
                                        <biblScope unit="page">213-33</biblScope>
                                        <date>1961</date>
                                        <note type="url">https://www.jstor.org/stable/24620678</note>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                            </biblStruct>

                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/users/2420388/items/QEJ9QPKW" type="journalArticle" xml:id="Carey2003">
                                <analytic>
                                    <title level="a">What is the folded almanac? The form and
                                        function of a key manuscript source for astro-medical
                                        practice in later medieval England</title>
                                    <idno type="DOI">10.1093/shm/16.3.481</idno>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>Hilary M.</forename>
                                        <surname>Carey</surname>
                                    </author>
                                </analytic>
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="j">Social History of Medicine</title>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
                                        <biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
                                        <biblScope unit="page">481-509</biblScope>
                                        <date>2003</date>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                            </biblStruct>

                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/users/2420388/items/SFDX9B8L" type="journalArticle" xml:id="Carey2004">
                                <analytic>
                                    <title level="a">Astrological medicine and the medieval English
                                        folded almanac</title>
                                    <idno type="DOI">10.1093/shm/17.3.345</idno>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>Hilary M.</forename>
                                        <surname>Carey</surname>
                                    </author>
                                </analytic>
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="j">Social History of Medicine</title>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
                                        <biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
                                        <biblScope unit="page">345-363</biblScope>
                                        <date>2004</date>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                            </biblStruct>

                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/users/2420388/items/MPPEKICF" type="book" xml:id="Gumbert2016">
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="m">Bat books: a catalogue of folded manuscripts
                                        containing almanacs or other texts</title>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>J.P.</forename>
                                        <surname>Gumbert</surname>
                                    </author>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <pubPlace>Turnhout</pubPlace>
                                        <publisher>Brepols</publisher>
                                        <date>2016</date>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                                <series>
                                    <title level="s">Bibliologia</title>
                                    <biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
                                </series>
                            </biblStruct>
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/HTNSUZUI" type="journalArticle" xml:id="Freeman2022">
                                <analytic>
                                    <title level="a">An Unrecorded Fragment of a Folding
                                        Almanac</title>
                                    <idno type="DOI">10.1093/notesj/gjac079</idno>
                                    <author><forename>James</forename><surname>Freeman</surname></author>
                                </analytic>
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="j">Notes and Queries</title>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
                                        <biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
                                        <biblScope unit="page">198-200</biblScope>
                                        <date>2022</date>
                                        <note type="accessed">2023-01-09T17:13:34Z</note>
                                        <note type="url">https://doi.org/10.1093/notesj/gjac079</note>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                            </biblStruct>
                        </listBibl>
                    </additional>

                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass default="false">
                <keywords scheme="#LCSH">
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <term key="subject_sh85015033">Phlebotomy</term>
                            <term key="subject_sh86005784">Almanacs, English</term>
                            <term key="subject_sh85009003">Astronomy</term>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc status="draft">
            <change status="draft" when="2021-08-20">
                <persName>Dr James Freeman, Medieval Manuscripts Specialist, Cambridge University
                    Library</persName>
            </change>

        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <facsimile>
        <graphic decls="#document-thumbnail" rend="portrait" url="MS-ADD-03303-00003-000-00001"/>
        <surface n="recto" xml:id="page-surface-1">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8329px" rend="portrait" url="MS-ADD-03303-00003-000-00001" width="5899px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="verso" xml:id="page-surface-2">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8329px" rend="portrait" url="MS-ADD-03303-00003-000-00002" width="5899px"/>
        </surface>
    </facsimile>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-1" n="recto" xml:id="page-pb-1"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-2" n="verso" xml:id="page-pb-2"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>