<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/msDesc/consolidated-tei-schema/master/msdesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/msDesc/consolidated-tei-schema/master/msdesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="manuscript_1">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>

                <title>Cambridge, Pembroke College, MS 258</title>
                <funder>Wellcome</funder>
                <principal>James Freeman</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Cambridge University Library</publisher>

                <availability status="restricted" xml:id="displayImageRights">
                    <p>Zooming image © University Library, All rights reserved.</p>
                </availability>
                <availability status="restricted" xml:id="downloadImageRights">
                    <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/">Images made available for download are licensed under a Creative
                        Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 3.0 Unported License (CC BY-NC 3.0)</licence>
                </availability>
                <availability status="restricted" xml:id="metadataRights">
                    <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/">This metadata is licensed under a Creative Commons
                        Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivs 3.0 Unported License.</licence>
                </availability>
                <availability status="restricted" xml:id="watermark">
                    <licence>The Master and Fellows of Pembroke College, Cambridge (CC BY-NC 4.0)</licence>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <msDesc xml:id="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258" xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">

                    <msIdentifier>
                        <institution>Pembroke College, Cambridge</institution>
                        <repository>Pembroke College Library</repository>
                        <collection>Manuscripts</collection>
                        <idno type="shelfmark">Cambridge, Pembroke College, MS 258</idno>
                    </msIdentifier>

                    <head>Miscellany</head>

                    <msContents>
                        <summary>
                            <seg type="para">Cambridge, Pembroke College, MS 258 is a composite manuscript comprised of several originally separate
                                parts created in England between the 12th and 15th centuries. Among the many and various texts in the manuscript are
                                stories about Christian saints, texts on theology, confession and penance, Alexander the Great, natural history,
                                Christian apocrypha, moral fables, penance, short poems, and brief medical recipes. </seg>
                            <seg type="para">Among the many interesting features of Cambridge, Pembroke College, MS 258 is its medieval binding: the
                                volume does not have a typical medieval binding where the quires have been laced into hard boards covered with
                                leather, limp-parchment or tawed skin, but instead has a home-made binding of an envelope of limp-parchment and linen
                                stuffed with documents. The binding was constructed by taking a piece of semi-limp parchment a little more than twice
                                the width of a leaf in the volume, laying it flat, placing several mid-15th century documents pasted together on top
                                of the semi-limp parchment, then placing a piece of linen on top of the documents and sewing all three layers together
                                with a linen thread. The three-layered cover was then folded in half (with the linen on the inside), and the quires
                                were attached to the binding by <locus from="spine" to="spine">stab-sewing through the full-thickness of the
                                    binding</locus>. The sewing to close the fore edge of the rear cover came apart after the cover was finished and
                                the various layers of the cover are now loose at the rear of the manuscript. Some of the <locus
                                    from="binding leaf ii recto - paper" to="binding leaf ii recto - paper">documents that were pasted
                                    together</locus> to line the cover have become separate in the intervening centuries and contain dating clauses
                                for the reign of King Edward IV (reg. 1461-1470 and 1471-1483). The unusual format of the cover suggests that it may
                                have been assembled by a former owner of the manuscript. A likely candidate for the former owner and binder is an
                                otherwise unknown 'Goodwyn' who wrote his name on the <locus from="outside front cover - parchment"
                                    to="outside front cover - parchment">outside of the front cover</locus>, and the <locus
                                    from="rear binding lining recto - linen" to="rear binding lining recto - linen">inside of the rear cover</locus>
                                and may have also written his name on the <locus from="front binding lining - linen" to="front binding lining - linen"
                                    >inside of the front cover</locus> where it is rendered as 'Goodwin 1496' in what may actually be a slightly later
                                hand.</seg>
                            <seg type="para">Little is known about the provenance of the manuscript, since it does not appear in any records of the
                                holdings of Pembroke College library before 1898. It may have arrived a little earlier than that, since an 1879
                                Pembroke College bookplate is found on the <locus from="front binding lining - linen"
                                    to="front binding lining - linen">inside of the front cover</locus>, but as bookplates were often used for several
                                years after they were printed, the bookplate alone is not sufficient to establish an earlier date of acquisition. </seg>
                            <seg type="para">Dr Sarah Gilbert<lb/> Project Cataloguer for the Curious Cures in Cambridge Libraries Project<lb/>
                                Cambridge University Library</seg>
                        </summary>

                    </msContents>



                    <physDesc>

                        <p>
                            <secFol>
                                <locus from="2r" to="2r">2r</locus>: Quidam rex </secFol>
                        </p>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc material="mixed">
                                <support>The book-block is comprised of medieval parchment leaves deriving from seven originally separate sources. The
                                    outer surface of the cover is semi-limp parchment. The inner surface of the cover is woven linen cloth stitched
                                    onto the semi-limp parchment and forming a pocket or envelope structure. The space between the semi-limp parchment
                                    outer cover and the cloth inner cover has been lined with documents made of medieval paper and parchment. </support>

                                <extent>
                                    <seg type="object">Codex: </seg>
                                    <seg type="leaf">
                                        <measure quantity="20" type="leaf">20</measure> | <measure quantity="23" type="leaf">23</measure> | <measure
                                            quantity="8" type="leaf">8</measure> | <measure quantity="6" type="leaf">6</measure> | <measure
                                            quantity="34" type="leaf">34</measure> | <measure quantity="31" type="leaf">31</measure> | <measure
                                            quantity="19" type="leaf">19</measure> | <measure quantity="3" type="endleaf">3</measure> leaves. </seg>
                                    <seg type="dimensions">
                                        <dimensions type="leaf" unit="mm">
                                            <height max="245" min="230">230-245</height>
                                            <width max="195" min="150">150-195</width>
                                        </dimensions>
                                    </seg>
                                </extent>



                                <foliation notAfter="2000" notBefore="1900">
                                    <p>20th century foliation</p>
                                    <p>1-20 | 21-43 | 44-51 | 52-57 | 58-91 | 92-122 | 123-141 | [binding document i] - [binding document iii]</p>
                                    <note>Foliated in the upper outer corner of each recto in pencil in Hindu-Arabic numerals. </note>
                                </foliation>


                                <collation mainStructures="10 8 6">
                                    <p>Composite manuscript comprised of several parchment booklets of separate origin now bound together. Leaves in
                                        Quires 14 and 15 are misbound. Quire 14, a quire of four leaves (ff. 123-126), consists of two sequential
                                        rather than nested bifolia, and the second bifolium, the present ff. <locus from="125r" to="126v"
                                            >125r-126v</locus> has been bound inside out; the leaves in Quire 14 should be read ff. 123, 124, 126,
                                        125. Quire 15 is a quire of 7 leaves (ff. 127-133), three nested bifolia and a singleton (f. 133) after the
                                        6th leaf; the singleton is misbound and should be the first leaf in the quire; the leaves in Quire 15 should
                                        be read ff. 133, 127-132.<list>
                                            <item>Quire 1<hi rend="superscript">20</hi> (ff. <locus from="1r" to="20v">1-20</locus>) |</item>
                                            <item>Quire 2<hi rend="superscript">10</hi> (ff. <locus from="21r" to="30v">21-30</locus>)</item>
                                            <item>Quire 3<hi rend="superscript">10-2</hi> (ff. <locus from="31r" to="38v">31-38</locus>: 9th and 10th
                                                leaves cancelled)</item>
                                            <item>Quire 4<hi rend="superscript">8-3</hi> (ff. <locus from="39r" to="43v">39-43</locus>: 6th, 7th, and
                                                8th leaves cancelled) |</item>
                                            <item>Quire 5<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> (ff. <locus from="44r" to="51v">44-51</locus>) |</item>
                                            <item>Quire 6<hi rend="superscript">six</hi>(ff. <locus from="52r" to="57v">52-57</locus>: gap between the
                                                3rd and 4th leaf) |</item>
                                            <item>Quires 7-8<hi rend="superscript">10</hi> (ff. <locus from="58r" to="77v">58-77</locus>) </item>
                                            <item>Quire 9<hi rend="superscript">14</hi> (ff. <locus from="78r" to="91v">78-91</locus>) |</item>
                                            <item>Quire 10<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> (ff. <locus from="92r" to="99v">92-99</locus>)</item>
                                            <item>Quire 11<hi rend="superscript">8-2</hi> (ff. <locus from="100r" to="105v">100-105</locus>: 6th and
                                                7th leaves cancelled)</item>
                                            <item>Quire 12<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> (ff. <locus from="106r" to="113v">106-113</locus>)</item>
                                            <item>Quire 13<hi rend="superscript">8+1</hi> (ff. <locus from="114r" to="122v">114-122</locus>: 1 leaf
                                                added after the 8th leaf) |</item>
                                            <item>Quire 14<hi rend="superscript">4</hi> (ff. <locus from="123r" to="126v">123-126</locus>)</item>
                                            <item>Quire 15<hi rend="superscript">6+1</hi> (ff. <locus from="127r" to="133v">127-133</locus>: 1 leaf
                                                added after the 6th leaf)</item>
                                            <item>Quire 16<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> (ff. <locus from="134r" to="141v">134-141</locus>)</item>
                                        </list>
                                    </p>
                                    <p><formula> 1<hi rend="superscript">20</hi> | 2<hi rend="superscript">10</hi> 3<hi rend="superscript">10-2</hi>
                                            (9th and 10th cancelled) 4<hi rend="superscript">8-3</hi> (6th, 7th, and 8th cancelled) | 5<hi
                                                rend="superscript">8</hi> | 6<hi rend="superscript">six</hi> (gap between the 3rd and 4th leaf) |
                                                7-8<hi rend="superscript">10</hi> 9<hi rend="superscript">14</hi> | 10<hi rend="superscript">8</hi>
                                                11<hi rend="superscript">8-2</hi> (6th and 7th cancelled) 12<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> 13<hi
                                                rend="superscript">8+1</hi>(1 leaf added after the 8th) | 14<hi rend="superscript">4</hi> 15<hi
                                                rend="superscript">6+1</hi> (1 leaf added after the 6th) 16<hi rend="superscript">8</hi>
                                        </formula></p>
                                </collation>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>

                        <additions><note><p>Quires numbered 1-16 in the lower outer corner of the first recto of each quire in pencil in Hindu-Arabic
                                    numerals; this quire designation sequence probably added in the 19th century.</p></note></additions>

                        <bindingDesc>
                            <binding notAfter="1550" notBefore="1461">
                                <p>Late-15th or early-16th century binding. The binding of Pembroke College MS 258 consists of three layers, each
                                    slightly larger than the largest bifolium in the volume, so that when the layers were stacked, sewn together, and
                                    folded in half, they formed a simple cover for the book-block. From outside to inside the cover, the three layers
                                    consist of: 1) a layer of semi-limp parchment; 2) a 'lining' layer made from layers of parchment documents from
                                    the reign of Edward IV pasted together; 3) a layer of linen cloth. The three layers are arranged a little like a
                                    quilted blanket, with the limp-parchment layer serving as the outer cover, the document layer functioning as the
                                    'padding' or 'wadding' in the quilt, and the linen cloth layer serving as the 'backing', and forming the layer in
                                    contact with the text leaves. The three layers were originally sewn together all the way around the border of the
                                    cover with a linen thread; the sewing at the rear of the volume has since broken, and the various layers of the
                                    cover-structure are now exposed.</p>
                                <p>The quires of Pembroke College MS 258 are stab-sewn to the composite cover with vertical tacking stitches through
                                    the full thickness of the <locus from="spine" to="spine">spine</locus>. Two paper labels fixed to the spine with
                                    an adhesive: a paper label with the Pembroke shelfmark '258' handwritten in ink, and a paper label with a
                                    handwritten list of some of the texts the spine.</p>
                                <p>The <locus from="front binding lining  - linen" to="front binding lining  - linen">inside of the front
                                        cover</locus> contains: <list>
                                        <item>The name 'Goodwin' and the date '1496' in dark ink (this name also appears faintly on the <locus
                                                from="outside front cover - parchment" to="outside front cover - parchment">front cover</locus>, and
                                            on the <locus from="rear binding lining recto - linen" to="rear binding lining recto - linen">linen cover
                                                layer at the rear of the volume</locus>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>A note in ink 'bonum est Missam celebrare pro defunctis'</item>
                                        <item>The number '120' struck out and the number '258' written in bright pink ink</item>
                                        <item>A note in ink 'Evang: Iohannis Lat: cum Comm: Bedae et Augustini'</item>
                                        <item>A Pembroke College bookplate, mounted horizontally, dated 1879</item>
                                        <item>Residue of a small oval wax seal or dark book label</item>
                                    </list></p>
                                <p>The documents used as the inner padding for the binding date from the reign of Edward IV (reg. 4 March 1461 to 3
                                    October 1470 and 11 April 1471 to 9 April 1483). The documents mention the building of a chamber in Pety Alley
                                    (now Petty Wales), and also Blakmanstrete, Suthwerk, and Kenstrete. Blakmanstrete, Suthwerk, and Kenstrete are all
                                    places in London on the south bank of the river Thames. These documents are described in more detail in Part 8 in
                                    this record. </p>
                                <p>This binding is similar in construction to <bibl subtype="internal" type="MS">Cambridge, University Library, Add.
                                        MS 6866</bibl>, although Add. MS 6866 has an inner layer of parchment rather than linen around a pad of
                                    documents.</p>
                                <p>For further reading on this binding see <bibl>N. Hadgraft, 'English Fifteenth Century Book Structures', unpubl. PhD
                                        thesis (University College London, 1998), esp. p. 250 and n. 162</bibl>. </p>
                            </binding>
                        </bindingDesc>
                    </physDesc>

                    <history>
                        <provenance notBefore="1450"><p>In the upper margin of f. <locus from="85r" to="85r">85r</locus> there is a note in a
                                ?mid-15th century hand: 'Alexander presbiter constat istum librum'.</p></provenance>

                        <provenance when="1496"><p>The name 'Goodwyn' appears 3 times: as 'Goodwyn' on the <locus
                                    from="outside front cover - parchment" to="outside front cover - parchment">front cover</locus>; as 'Goodwin' on
                                the <locus from="front binding lining  - linen" to="front binding lining  - linen">inside of the left cover</locus>
                                with the date '1496'; and 'Goodwyn' on the <locus from="rear binding lining recto - linen"
                                    to="rear binding lining recto - linen">cloth cover layer at the rear of the volume</locus>, probably a former
                                owner, or perhaps the original compiler of the volume.</p>
                        </provenance>

                        <acquisition notAfter="1895">
                            <p>It is not known when or from whom Pembroke College obtained MS 258. The manuscript appears in H. Schenkl's <hi
                                    rend="italic">Bibliotheca Patrum Latinorum Britannica</hi> (1898), no. 2490, but does not appear in any of the
                                earlier inventories of Pembroke's library holdings.</p>
                        </acquisition>
                    </history>

                    <additional>
                        <adminInfo>
                            <recordHist>
                                <source>This catalogue entry draws on M.R. James, <hi rend="italic">A descriptive catalogue of the manuscripts in the
                                        library of Pembroke College, Cambridge</hi> (1905), and R.M. Thomson, <hi rend="italic">A Descriptive
                                        Catalogue of the Medieval Manuscripts of Pembroke College Cambridge</hi> (2022) by kind permission of the
                                    author. Readers of this record are encouraged to consult Thomson's <hi rend="italic">Catalogue</hi> for further
                                    information about this manuscript.</source>
                            </recordHist>

                            <availability status="restricted">
                                <p>Researchers should note that Pembroke College's western European medieval manuscripts are housed at Cambridge
                                    University Library (CUL). Scholars who wish to consult Pembroke College manuscripts should contact the <ref
                                        target="mss@lib.cam.ac.uk">Manuscripts Reading Room</ref> at CUL to arrange their visit; all CUL admissions
                                    procedures will apply. For information on eligibility and admissions procedures, see <ref
                                        target="https://www.lib.cam.ac.uk/using-library/joining-library">Joining the Library</ref>. For further
                                    information on the availability of the manuscript, please contact the <ref target="mss@lib.cam.ac.uk">Manuscripts
                                        Reading Room</ref>.</p>
                            </availability>
                        </adminInfo>

                        <listBibl>
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/7J52JH77" type="journalArticle" xml:id="Ross1956">
                                <analytic>
                                    <title level="a">A check-list of manuscripts of three Alexander texts: The Julius Valerius Epitome, the Epistola
                                        ad Aristotelem and the Collatio cum Dindimo</title>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>D.J.A.</forename>
                                        <surname>Ross</surname>
                                    </author>
                                </analytic>
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="j">Scriptorium: Revue internationale des études relatives aux manuscrits / International Review of
                                        Manuscript Studies</title>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
                                        <biblScope unit="page">127-132</biblScope>
                                        <date>1956</date>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                                <note>p. 129. </note>
                            </biblStruct>
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/2QTXXE6X" type="book" xml:id="Boer1973">
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="m">Epistola Alexandri ad Aristotelem ad codicum fidem edidit et commentario critico
                                        instruxit</title>
                                    <editor>
                                        <forename>W. Walther</forename>
                                        <surname>Boer</surname>
                                    </editor>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <pubPlace>Meisenheim am Glan</pubPlace>
                                        <publisher>A. Hain</publisher>
                                        <date>1973</date>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                                <series>
                                    <title level="s">Beiträge zur klassischen Philologie</title>
                                    <biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
                                </series>
                                <note>MS Pem. </note>
                            </biblStruct>
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/9C8WHDG5" type="book" xml:id="McIntosh1986">
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="m">A Linguistic Atlas of Late Mediaeval English</title>
                                    <extent>4</extent>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>Angus</forename>
                                        <surname>McIntosh</surname>
                                    </author>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>M.L.</forename>
                                        <surname>Samuels</surname>
                                    </author>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>Michael</forename>
                                        <surname>Benskin</surname>
                                    </author>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <pubPlace>Aberdeen</pubPlace>
                                        <publisher>Aberdeen University Press</publisher>
                                        <date>1986</date>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                                <note>f. 136r: two couplets possibly in NME, on the degeneracy of the times (IMEV 3560). NME. </note>
                            </biblStruct>
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/KSGLAIPG" type="thesis" xml:id="Hadgraft1997">
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="m">English Fifteenth Century Book Structures</title>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>Nicholas</forename>
                                        <surname>Hadgraft</surname>
                                    </author>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
                                        <date>1997</date>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                            </biblStruct>
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/ZPGG9QD6" type="book" xml:id="Dean1999">
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="m">Anglo-Norman literature: a guide to texts and manuscripts</title>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>Ruth J.</forename>
                                        <surname>Dean</surname>
                                    </author>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>Maureen Barry McCann</forename>
                                        <surname>Boulton</surname>
                                    </author>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
                                        <publisher>Anglo-Norman Text Society</publisher>
                                        <date>1999</date>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                                <series>
                                    <title level="s">Anglo-Norman Text Society occasional publications series</title>
                                    <biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
                                </series>
                                <note>nos 591, 629, 635. </note>
                            </biblStruct>
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/3GHJYTY2" type="book" xml:id="Thomson2022">
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="m">A descriptive catalogue of the medieval manuscripts of Pembroke College, Cambridge</title>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>Rodney M.</forename>
                                        <surname>Thomson</surname>
                                    </author>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
                                        <publisher>D.S. Brewer</publisher>
                                        <date>2022</date>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                                <note>pp. 144-146 </note>
                            </biblStruct>
                        </listBibl>

                    </additional>


                    <msPart n="1">
                        <msIdentifier>
                            <idno>Cambridge, Pembroke College, MS 258, ff. 1-20</idno>
                            <msName>Part 1 - Theological texts</msName>
                        </msIdentifier>

                        <msContents>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>

                            <msItem n="1">
                                <locus from="1r" to="6v">1r-6v</locus>
                                <title>Extracts from lives or legends of saints</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <incipit defective="true">
                                    <locus from="1r" to="1r">1r</locus> .n. celcitudinis unum beati . q . h . i . d . t . d . </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="6v" to="6v">6v</locus> est in laudibus saluatoris</explicit>
                                <note>Hugh of Lincoln, Anian, Bertin, Giles, John of Beverley, Wilfrid, Bridget of Ireland, Germanus, Swithun,
                                    Machutus, Gregory, John, Euphemia, Lucy, Clement, Simon and Iuda, Raphael. </note>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="2">
                                <locus from="7r" to="8v">7r-8v</locus>
                                <title>De confessione</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="7r" to="7r">7r</locus> Sacerdos debet humiliter se habere in confessione </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="8v" to="8v">8v</locus> et fortassis peiora feci quam tu </explicit>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>Bloomfield, <hi rend="italic">Incipits</hi>, no. 5229</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="3">
                                <locus from="8v" to="8v">8v</locus>
                                <title>Unidentified text</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="8v" to="8v">8v</locus> Sequitur videre qualiter dissoluuntur sponsalia </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="8v" to="8v">8v</locus> de fide uel permissione ?mentitura </explicit>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="3">
                                <locus from="9r" to="12v">9r-12v</locus>
                                <title key="work_4765">De articulis fidei et ecclesiae sacramentis [simplified extracts]</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="9r" to="9r">9r</locus> Primus articulus fidei est quod unus Deus est in essencia </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="12v" to="12v">12v</locus> opus prauum dicit Paulus </explicit>
                                <note>See P. Glorieux, <hi rend="italic">Répertoire des maitres en théologie de Paris au XIIIe siècle</hi>
                                    (1933-1934), no. 14h</note>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="4">
                                <locus from="13r" to="20v">13r-20v</locus>
                                <title>Extracts from lives or legends of saints</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="13r" to="13r">13r</locus> Mulier quedam peccata multa </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="20v" to="20v">20v</locus> loqui de illo </explicit>
                                <note>Germanus, on confession, of Judas, Edmund of East Anglia, <hi rend="italic">Vitas patrum</hi>, Clement, Martin,
                                    Simon and Jude, Cornelius, Etheldreda, Crispin, Felix and Adauctus, Elisabeth, Gregory, Euphemia, Benedict,
                                    Apollinaris, Thomas, Agatha, Invention of the Cross, Apollinaris, Hugh of Lincoln, Ignatius.</note>
                            </msItem>
                        </msContents>

                        <physDesc>
                            <p><secFol>
                                    <locus from="2r" to="2r">2r</locus> Quid rex habuit .iii. filios </secFol>
                            </p>

                            <objectDesc form="codex">
                                <supportDesc material="perg">
                                    <support>
                                        <material>Parchment (<term type="disposition">HFFH</term>).</material>
                                    </support>

                                    <extent>
                                        <seg type="object">Codex: </seg>
                                        <seg type="leaf">
                                            <measure quantity="20" type="leaf">20</measure> leaves. </seg>
                                        <seg type="dimensions">
                                            <dimensions type="leaf" unit="mm">
                                                <height quantity="210">210</height>
                                                <width quantity="160">160</width>
                                            </dimensions>
                                        </seg>
                                    </extent>

                                    <collation mainStructures="20">
                                        <p>1 quire of 20 leaves: <list>
                                                <item>Quire 1<hi rend="superscript">20</hi> (ff. 1-20) </item>
                                            </list>
                                        </p>
                                    </collation>

                                    <condition> Some minor staining to parchment, but no text lost to liquid damage. </condition>

                                </supportDesc>

                                <layoutDesc>
                                    <layout columns="1" rulingMedium="leadpoint" topLine="mixed" writtenLines="31">
                                        <dimensions type="written" unit="mm">
                                            <height quantity="170">c. 170</height>
                                            <width quantity="135">c. 135</width>
                                        </dimensions>
                                        <seg type="ruling"> Written in single-column format, typically 31 lines to the page. Most leaves are unruled,
                                            or ruling is frame only, but ff. <locus from="7r" to="8v">7r-8v</locus> are ruled frame and lines in
                                            leadpoint. Writing is mixed above and below top line. </seg>
                                    </layout>
                                </layoutDesc>

                            </objectDesc>

                            <handDesc>
                                <handNote script="cursivaAntiquior">
                                    <p> Written in the <term type="script">anglicana</term> form of cursiva antiquior. </p>
                                </handNote>
                            </handDesc>

                            <decoDesc>
                                <decoNote type="decInit">
                                    <p>Inhabited initial with faces amid floral and foliate motifs on f. <locus from="7r" to="7r">7r</locus>. Puzzle
                                        initial, red and brown on f. <locus from="9r" to="9r">9r</locus>.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                                <decoNote type="rubrication">
                                    <p>Occasional rubrication throughout ff. <locus from="1r" to="20v">1r-20v</locus>, typically mminor initials
                                        touched with red, and the use of red to underline particular sections of text.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                            </decoDesc>


                            <additions>
                                <note>In the upper margin of f. <locus from="1r" to="1r">1r</locus> in ink: 'Jesus Maria + 1528'</note>
                            </additions>

                        </physDesc>

                        <history>
                            <origin>
                                <origDate calendar="Gregorian" cert="high" notAfter="1330" notBefore="1360">Mid-14th century. </origDate>
                                <origPlace cert="high" key="place_g7002445">England, ?London. </origPlace>
                            </origin>
                        </history>
                    </msPart>


                    <msPart n="2">
                        <msIdentifier>
                            <idno>Cambridge, Pembroke College, MS 258, ff. 21-43</idno>
                            <msName>Part 2 - Works about Alexander the Great</msName>
                        </msIdentifier>

                        <msContents>
                            <msItem n="1">
                                <locus from="21r" to="32v">21r-32v</locus>
                                <title key="work_12220">Epitome of the Historia Alexandri Magni with Epitaphium [Latin]</title>
                                <author key="person_v12398599" role="trl">Julius Valerius (trans.)</author>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <msItem n="1.1">
                                    <locus from="21r" to="32v">21r-32v</locus>
                                    <title>Text</title>
                                    <incipit>
                                        <locus from="21r" to="21r">21r</locus> Egypti sapientes fati genere diuino</incipit>
                                    <explicit>
                                        <locus from="32v" to="32v">32v</locus> ueneno superatus atque extinctus occubuit </explicit>
                                </msItem>
                                <msItem n="1.2">
                                    <locus from="32v" to="32v">32v</locus>
                                    <title key="">Epitaphum</title>
                                    <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                    <rubric>
                                        <locus from="32v" to="32v">32v</locus> Epitaphium </rubric>
                                    <incipit>
                                        <locus from="32v" to="32v">32v</locus> Primus Alexander Pillea natus in urbe </incipit>
                                    <explicit>
                                        <locus from="32v" to="32v">32v</locus> Succubuit leto sumpto cum melle ueneno </explicit>
                                </msItem>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>WIC 15990</bibl>
                                    <bibl>Edited (not from this MS) in J. Zacher, <hi rend="italic">Iulii Valerii Epitome</hi> (Halle, 1867)</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="2">
                                <locus from="33r" to="38v">33r-38v</locus>
                                <title key="work_11709">Epistola Alexandri ad Aristotelem de situ Indiae [Latin]</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <rubric>
                                    <locus from="33r" to="33r">33r</locus> Incipit epistola Alexandri regis magni Macedonum ad magistrum suum
                                    Aristotilem </rubric>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="33r" to="33r">33r</locus> Semper memor tui etiam inter dubia bellorum </incipit>
                                <explicit defective="true">
                                    <locus from="38v" to="38v">38v</locus> et ut presto essem ad </explicit>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>Edited (not from this MS) by W. W. Boer, <hi rend="italic">Beitrage zur klassischen Philologie</hi>
                                        (1973)</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="3">
                                <locus from="39r" to="43v">39r-43v</locus>
                                <title key="work_11056">Collatio Alexandri et Dindimi</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="39r" to="39r">39r</locus> Sepius ad aures meas fando peruenit </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="43v" to="43v">43v</locus> aut invidiae quod a meliore prestantuR </explicit>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>Edited (not from this MS) in B. G. A. Kuebler, <hi rend="italic">Iulii Valerii Alexandri Polemi Res Gestae
                                            Alexandri Macedonis Translate Ex Aesopo Graeco</hi> (Leipzig, 1888), pp. 169-189</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="4">
                                <locus from="43v" to="43v">43v</locus>
                                <title>Five short poems</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <msItem n="4.1">
                                    <locus from="43v" to="43v">43v</locus>
                                    <title>Verses on how Aristotle prevented a war that Alexander declared in Athens</title>
                                    <author key="person_282035032">Hildebert of Lavardin</author>
                                    <incipit>
                                        <locus from="43v" to="43v">43v</locus> Magnus Alexander bellum mandarat athenis </incipit>
                                    <explicit>
                                        <locus from="43v" to="43v">43v</locus> Dat pacem . lusus calliditate viri </explicit>
                                    <note><p>Also in <bibl subtype="internal" type="MS"><ref
                                                    target="https://cudl.lib.cam.ac.uk/view/MS-GG-00006-00042/339">Cambridge, University Library, MS
                                                    Gg.6.42, f. <locus from="167r" to="167r">167r</locus></ref>
                                            </bibl>. </p></note>
                                    <listBibl>
                                        <bibl>WIC 10603</bibl>
                                    </listBibl>
                                </msItem>
                                <msItem n="4.2">
                                    <locus from="43v" to="43v">43v</locus>
                                    <title>Poem</title>
                                    <incipit>
                                        <locus from="43v" to="43v">43v</locus> Cum sis petre breuis </incipit>
                                    <explicit>
                                        <locus from="43v" to="43v">43v</locus> magna breui </explicit>
                                    <listBibl>
                                        <bibl>WIC 3788</bibl>
                                    </listBibl>
                                </msItem>
                                <msItem n="4.3">
                                    <locus from="43v" to="43v">43v</locus>
                                    <title>Poem</title>
                                    <note><p>Full transcription <lb/> Fama repleta malis leuibus circumuolat alis <lb/> Fama boni lente <hi
                                                rend="superscript">uolat</hi> inuida retinente</p></note>
                                    <listBibl>
                                        <bibl>WIC 6260</bibl>
                                    </listBibl>
                                </msItem>
                                <msItem n="4.4">
                                    <locus from="43v" to="43v">43v</locus>
                                    <title>Poem</title>
                                    <note>
                                        <p>Full transcription:<lb/> Nescio si scis quo pacto mereatur episco <lb/> Pus . norwicensis . ut fiat
                                            Wintoniensis </p>
                                    </note>
                                    <listBibl>
                                        <bibl>WIC 11747</bibl>
                                    </listBibl>
                                </msItem>
                                <msItem n="4.5">
                                    <locus from="43v" to="43v">43v</locus>
                                    <title>Poem</title>
                                    <note>
                                        <p>Full transcription: <lb/> Mittitur in disco mihi piscis ab archiepisco<lb/> Po . non inclino . quia missio
                                            fit sine uino </p>
                                    </note>
                                    <listBibl>
                                        <bibl>WIC 11136</bibl>
                                    </listBibl>
                                </msItem>
                                <note><p>It is possible that poems 4 and 5 should be read as a single poem, i.e.,<lb/> Nescio si scis quo pacto
                                        mereatur episco <lb/> Pus . norwicensis . ut fiat Wintoniensis<lb/> Mittitur in disco mihi piscis ab
                                        archiepisco<lb/> Po . non inclino . quia missio fit sine uino<lb/> Both the fourth and fifth poem have the
                                        word for archbishop in Latin (archiepiscopus -i) as the final word in the first line of a couplet, and add an
                                        unusual break in the word so that the final syllable begins the second line of the couplet. </p></note>
                            </msItem>

                        </msContents>



                        <physDesc>
                            <p><secFol>
                                    <locus from="22r" to="22r">22r</locus> nam sedenti super ueniet </secFol>
                            </p>

                            <objectDesc form="Codex">
                                <supportDesc material="perg">
                                    <support>
                                        <material>Parchment (<term type="disposition">HFFH</term>).</material>
                                    </support>

                                    <extent>
                                        <seg type="object">Codex: </seg>
                                        <seg type="leaf">
                                            <measure quantity="23" type="leaf">23</measure> leaves. </seg>
                                        <seg type="dimensions">
                                            <dimensions type="leaf" unit="mm">
                                                <height quantity="240">240</height>
                                                <width quantity="170">170</width>
                                            </dimensions>
                                        </seg>
                                    </extent>

                                    <collation mainStructures="10 8">
                                        <p>Three quires (Quires 2-4), the second and third quires with cancelled leaves. <list>
                                                <item>Quire 2<hi rend="superscript">10</hi> (ff. 21-30)</item>
                                                <item>Quire 3<hi rend="superscript">10-2</hi> (ff. 31-38: 9th and 10th leaves cancelled)</item>
                                                <item>Quire 4<hi rend="superscript">8-3</hi> (ff. 39-43: 6th, 7th, and 8th leaves cancelled)</item>
                                            </list>
                                        </p>
                                        <catchwords><seg type="para">Catchwords on f. <locus from="30v" to="30v">30v</locus> at the end of Quire
                                                2</seg>
                                        </catchwords>
                                    </collation>

                                    <condition> Some minor staining to parchment, but no text lost to liquid damage. </condition>

                                </supportDesc>

                                <layoutDesc>
                                    <layout columns="1" rulingMedium="crayon" topLine="above" writtenLines="39">
                                        <dimensions type="written" unit="mm">
                                            <height quantity="165">165</height>
                                            <width quantity="95">95</width>
                                        </dimensions>
                                        <seg type="ruling"> Ruled in single-column format, in crayon, frame and lines, with pricking still visible in
                                            outer and inner margins. Typically 39 lines to the page, written above top line. </seg>
                                    </layout>

                                </layoutDesc>

                            </objectDesc>

                            <handDesc>
                                <handNote script="northernTextualis">
                                    <p> Written in a northern textualis <term type="script">rotunda</term>. </p>
                                </handNote>
                            </handDesc>

                            <decoDesc>
                                <decoNote type="flourInit">
                                    <p>Red initials with blue pen flourishing or green initials with red flourishing at the major and minor divisions
                                        of the text.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                            </decoDesc>

                        </physDesc>

                        <history>
                            <origin>
                                <origDate calendar="Gregorian" cert="medium" notAfter="1300" notBefore="1200">13th century. </origDate>
                                <origPlace cert="high" key="place_g7002445">England. </origPlace>
                            </origin>

                        </history>
                    </msPart>

                    <msPart n="3">
                        <msIdentifier>
                            <idno>Cambridge, Pembroke College, MS 258, ff. 44-51</idno>
                            <msName>Part 3 - Hugh of Fouilloy, Auicularius</msName>
                        </msIdentifier>

                        <msContents>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>

                            <msItem n="1">
                                <locus from="44r" to="44r">44r</locus>
                                <title key="">Prologue to the Auicularius (De natura auium et animalium)</title>
                                <author key="person_v4944345">Hugh of Fouilloy</author>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="44r" to="44r">44r</locus> [D]esiderii tui karissime peticionibus satisfacere</incipit>
                                <note>Ends imperfectly. </note>
                                <note><p>Folio <locus from="44v" to="44v">44v</locus> originally blank and subsequently filled with annotations in the
                                        15th and 16th centuries. </p></note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>Text edited (not from this MS) in PL 177, pp. 13-164, esp. pp. 13-30</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="2">
                                <locus from="44v" to="44v">44v</locus>
                                <title key="">Note on the humoral qualities of the planets</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <note>
                                    <p>Full transciption: Saturnus est frigidus et siccus . <sic>Iubiter</sic> calidus et humidus <lb/> Mars calidus
                                        et siccus et <unclear>combureus</unclear> . Sol calidus et siccus et luceus <lb/> Venus frigida et humida .
                                        Mercurius mobilis et cum calido calidus <lb/> et cum frigido frigidus luna frigida et humida etc</p>
                                    <p>Written in an early 16th century hand. </p>
                                </note>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="3">
                                <locus from="44v" to="44v">44v</locus>
                                <title key="">Note on purgatives</title>
                                <note><p>Written in the same hand as the note on the humoral qualities of the planets on the same leaf. </p></note>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="4">
                                <locus from="44v" to="44v">44v</locus>
                                <title key="">Medical recipe</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <note><p> Full transcription: ℞. V.cum.S. Et iterum cum A. et pet. cum Borum. Et fac nucis . cum . tar. M. et ou . Pro
                                        stomaco et dolore dentium . etcetera . Allumya </p>
                                    <p>Written in a mid-15th century hand.</p>
                                </note>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="5">
                                <locus from="45r" to="51v">45r-51v</locus>
                                <title key="">Main text of the Auicularius (De natura auium et animalium)</title>
                                <author key="person_v4944345">Hugh of Fouilloy</author>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <rubric>
                                    <locus from="45r" to="45r">45r</locus> Incipit libellus cuiusdam ad raineRum conuersum cognomine corde benignum .
                                    Incipit de tribus columbis </rubric>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="45r" to="45r">45r</locus> [S]i dormiatis inter medios cleros penne columbe </incipit>
                                <explicit defective="true">
                                    <locus from="51v" to="51v">51v</locus> mistice nicticorax Christum significat</explicit>
                                <note>Ends imperfectly. </note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>Text edited (not from this MS) in PL 177, pp. 13-164, esp. pp. 13-30</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>
                        </msContents>

                        <physDesc>
                            <p><secFol>
                                    <locus from="45r" to="45r">45r</locus> Incipit libellus cuiusdam ad Rainerum </secFol>
                            </p>

                            <objectDesc form="codex">
                                <supportDesc material="perg">

                                    <support>
                                        <material>Parchment (<term type="disposition">HFFH</term>).</material>
                                    </support>

                                    <extent>
                                        <seg type="object">Codex: </seg>
                                        <seg type="leaf">
                                            <measure quantity="8" type="leaf">8</measure> leaves. </seg>
                                        <seg type="dimensions">
                                            <dimensions type="leaf" unit="mm">
                                                <height quantity="240">240</height>
                                                <width quantity="185">185</width>
                                            </dimensions>
                                        </seg>
                                    </extent>

                                    <collation mainStructures="8">
                                        <p>One quire of 8 leaves: <list>
                                                <item>Quire 5<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> (ff. <locus from="44r" to="51v">44-51</locus>)</item>
                                            </list></p>
                                    </collation>

                                    <condition> Lower margin of f. 44 trimmed away - text lost. Marginal annotations in pencil and crayon washed (or
                                        rubbed) off. </condition>

                                </supportDesc>

                                <layoutDesc>
                                    <layout columns="2" rulingMedium="crayon" topLine="above" writtenLines="38">
                                        <dimensions type="written" unit="mm">
                                            <height quantity="170">170</height>
                                            <width quantity="120">120</width>
                                        </dimensions>
                                        <seg type="ruling"> Ruled mostly in double-column format, in crayon, frame and lines, pricking visible in
                                            margins. Typically 38 lines to the column, written above top line. </seg>
                                    </layout>
                                </layoutDesc>

                            </objectDesc>

                            <handDesc>
                                <handNote script="northernTextualis">
                                    <p> Written in a northern textualis <term type="script">rotunda</term>. </p>
                                </handNote>

                                <handNote script="cursiva">
                                    <p>Medical recipes on f. <locus from="44v" to="44v">44v</locus> added in a 16th century <term type="script"
                                            >secretary</term> hand.</p>
                                </handNote>
                            </handDesc>


                            <decoDesc>
                                <decoNote type="unfilled">
                                    <p>Frames left for decoration throughout.</p>
                                </decoNote>

                                <decoNote type="rubrication">
                                    <p>Rubricated headings (red only) and titles for (unfinished) illustrations throughout.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                            </decoDesc>


                            <additions>
                                <note>Annotations in a large hand in pencil or crayon in most margins. Annotations have been washed or rubbed off and
                                    are now very faint.</note>
                            </additions>

                        </physDesc>

                        <history>
                            <origin>
                                <origDate calendar="Gregorian" cert="medium" notAfter="1300" notBefore="1200">13th century. </origDate>
                                <origPlace cert="high" key="place_g7002445">England. </origPlace>
                            </origin>
                        </history>
                    </msPart>


                    <msPart n="4">
                        <msIdentifier>
                            <idno>Cambridge, Pembroke College, MS 258, ff. 52-57 </idno>
                            <msName>Part 4 - Visio Pauli, exemplary stories, treatise on penance</msName>

                        </msIdentifier>

                        <msContents>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>

                            <msItem n="1">
                                <locus from="52r" to="53r">52r-53r</locus>
                                <title key="work_16173">Visio Pauli [Latin]</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="52r" to="52r">52r</locus> Dies dominicus dies letus in quo gaudent angeli</incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="53r" to="53r">53r</locus> ut uiuamus cum ipso in sua gloria in secula seculorum amen</explicit>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>Edited (not from this MS) in L. Jiroušková (2006), pp. 651, 654-857</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="2">
                                <locus from="53r" to="55r">53r-55r</locus>
                                <title>Legendary stories</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="53r" to="53r">53r</locus> Legimus de beata uirgine quod postquam ad celum ascendit pro nobis
                                    peccatoribus </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="55r" to="55r">55r</locus> Et sicut possit viam deum pervenire</explicit>
                                <finalRubric>
                                    <locus from="55r" to="55r">55r</locus> Explicit tractatus penitentie </finalRubric>
                                <note>Thomson draws attention to similarities between this text and Caesarius of Heisterbach, Miracula 3. 20; ed. A.
                                    Hilka (Bonn, 1937), pp. 187-888. See Thomson, Pembroke, no. 258 for further information.</note>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="3">
                                <locus from="55r" to="57v">55r-57v</locus>
                                <title key="">Treatise on Penance</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="55r" to="55r">55r</locus> Scire debent sacerdotes qui non habent potestatem absoluendi </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="57v" to="57v">57v</locus> et uiuamus memoria sanctorum </explicit>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>M. W. Bloomfield, et al., <hi rend="italic">Incipits of Latin Works on the Virtues and the Vices, 1100-1500
                                            (MA: Cambridge, 1979), no. 5336</hi></bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                        </msContents>



                        <physDesc>
                            <p><secFol>
                                    <locus from="53r" to="53r">53r</locus> -dium est gaudia </secFol>
                            </p>
                            <objectDesc form="codex">
                                <supportDesc material="perg">
                                    <support>
                                        <material>Parchment (<term type="disposition">HFFH</term>).</material>
                                    </support>

                                    <extent>
                                        <seg type="object">Codex: </seg>
                                        <seg type="leaf">
                                            <measure quantity="6" type="leaf">6</measure> leaves. </seg>
                                        <seg type="dimensions">
                                            <dimensions type="leaf" unit="mm">
                                                <height quantity="240">240</height>
                                                <width quantity="165">165</width>
                                            </dimensions>
                                        </seg>
                                    </extent>



                                    <collation mainStructures="6"> One quire with 6 extant leaves, at least 2 leaves probably lost. <p>
                                            <list>
                                                <item>Quire 6<hi rend="superscript">six</hi> (ff. 52-57: gap after 3rd leaf)</item>
                                            </list>
                                        </p>
                                    </collation>

                                    <condition> Good condition, text on f. <locus from="57v" to="57v">57v</locus> a little rubbed. </condition>

                                </supportDesc>

                                <layoutDesc>
                                    <layout columns="2" rulingMedium="leadpoint" topLine="above" writtenLines="50">
                                        <dimensions type="written" unit="mm">
                                            <height quantity="225">225</height>
                                            <width quantity="130">130</width>
                                        </dimensions>
                                        <seg type="ruling"> Written in double-column format, typically 50 lines to the column. Ruled in leadpoint,
                                            usually frame only, occasional line ruling. </seg>
                                    </layout>
                                </layoutDesc>


                            </objectDesc>

                            <handDesc>
                                <handNote script="cursivaAntiquior">
                                    <p>Written in <term type="script">Anglicana</term>. </p>
                                </handNote>
                            </handDesc>


                            <decoDesc>
                                <decoNote type="plainInit">
                                    <p>Plain red initials on f. <locus from="52r" to="52r">52r</locus>, dark brown enlarged initial on f. <locus
                                            from="54r" to="54r">54r</locus></p>
                                </decoNote>
                                <decoNote type="other">
                                    <p>Red paraphs on f. <locus from="52r" to="52r">52r</locus>. </p>
                                </decoNote>
                            </decoDesc>
                        </physDesc>

                        <history>
                            <origin>
                                <origDate calendar="Gregorian" cert="medium" notAfter="1300" notBefore="1250">Late 13th century. </origDate>
                                <origPlace cert="high" key="place_g7002445">England. </origPlace>
                            </origin>

                        </history>
                    </msPart>

                    <msPart n="5">
                        <msIdentifier>
                            <idno>Cambridge, Pembroke College, MS 258, ff. 58-91 </idno>
                            <msName>Part 5 - Richard Wetheringsett, Summa qui bene presunt; sermon on the host</msName>
                        </msIdentifier>
                        <msContents>

                            <textLang mainLang="la" otherLangs="fro">Latin and Old French</textLang>

                            <msItem n="1">
                                <locus from="58r" to="90v">58r-90v</locus>
                                <title key="work_4302">Summa qui bene presunt [Latin]</title>
                                <author key="person_v37314703">Richardus de Wetheringsett</author>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <rubric><locus from="58r" to="58r">58r</locus> Hic incipit Liber pastoralis Gregorii </rubric>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="58r" to="58r">58r</locus> Qui bene presunt presbiteri</incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="90v" to="90v">90v</locus> Explicit summa magistri Ricardi de Weressete de hiis que pertinent ad eos
                                    qui bene presunt Deo gracias . Ex quo omnia per quem omnia in quo omnia ipsi gloria in secula amen</explicit>
                                <finalRubric><locus from="90v" to="90v">90v</locus> Amen</finalRubric>
                                <note>Notes in the margins in the main hand and other hands in ink and in crayon. </note>
                                <note>Unprinted, but see Thomson, <hi rend="italic">Pembroke</hi> for further bibliography. </note>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="2">
                                <locus from="90v" to="90v">90v</locus>
                                <title>Note</title>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="90v" to="90v">90v</locus> Ier<supplied>emias</supplied> de excelso misit dominus ignem </incipit>
                                <explicit defective="true">
                                    <locus from="90v" to="90v">90v</locus> timor et dilecto uerbum </explicit>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="3">
                                <locus from="91r" to="91v">91rv</locus>
                                <title>Sermon in verse on the Host</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="fro" otherLangs="la">Old French and Latin</textLang>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="90r" to="90r">90r</locus> En lubble dunt le corps est fest </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="91v" to="91v">91v</locus> peche qe laye gent </explicit>
                                <note>See Dean and Boulton, <hi rend="italic">Anglo-Norman Literature</hi> (1999), no. 591. </note>
                            </msItem>
                        </msContents>

                        <physDesc>
                            <p><secFol>
                                    <locus from="59r" to="59r">59r</locus> efficientia ut baptismum </secFol>
                            </p>
                            <objectDesc form="codex">
                                <supportDesc material="perg">
                                    <support>
                                        <material>Parchment (<term type="disposition">HFFH</term>).</material>
                                    </support>

                                    <extent>
                                        <seg type="object">Codex: </seg>
                                        <seg type="leaf">
                                            <measure quantity="34" type="leaf">34</measure> leaves. </seg>
                                        <seg type="dimensions">
                                            <dimensions type="leaf" unit="mm">
                                                <height quantity="240">240</height>
                                                <width quantity="180">180</width>
                                            </dimensions>
                                        </seg>
                                    </extent>

                                    <collation mainStructures="10 14">Three quires, the first two of 10 leaves, the third of 14 leaves. <p>
                                            <list>
                                                <item>Quires 7-8<hi rend="superscript">10</hi> (ff. 58-77)</item>
                                                <item>Quire 9<hi rend="superscript">14</hi> (ff. 78-91)</item>
                                            </list>
                                        </p>
                                        <catchwords><seg type="para">Catchwords on ff. <locus from="67v" to="67v">67v</locus> and <locus from="77v"
                                                    to="77v">77v</locus>.</seg></catchwords>
                                    </collation>

                                    <condition> archment trimmed for binding with minor losses to marginalia and decoration. </condition>

                                </supportDesc>

                                <layoutDesc>
                                    <layout columns="2" rulingMedium="leadpoint" topLine="below" writtenLines="55">
                                        <dimensions type="written" unit="mm">
                                            <height quantity="190">190</height>
                                            <width quantity="140">140</width>
                                        </dimensions>
                                        <seg type="ruling">Arranged in double-column format, typically 55 lines to the column. Ruled in leadpoint,
                                            frame only, and written below top line. </seg>
                                    </layout>
                                </layoutDesc>

                            </objectDesc>

                            <handDesc>
                                <handNote script="cursivaAntiquior">
                                    <p>Written in <term type="script">Anglicana</term>. </p>
                                </handNote>
                            </handDesc>

                            <decoDesc>
                                <decoNote type="miniature">
                                    <p>Sketches of mythical beasts (e.g. mermaid on f. <locus from="66v" to="66v">66v</locus>, centaur on f. <locus
                                            from="67v" to="67v">67v</locus>), grotesques, animals, human figures and other drolleries, in crayon, in
                                        the lower and outer margins of ff. <locus from="58r" to="90v">58r-90v</locus>. Many overwritten by subsequent
                                        marginal notes.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                                <decoNote type="flourInit">
                                    <p>Puzzle initial with a face in the counterspace and pen-flourishing on f. <locus from="58r" to="58r"
                                        >58r</locus>.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                                <decoNote type="flourInit">
                                    <p>Flourished initials in red at the major and minor divisions of the text ff. <locus from="58r" to="90v"
                                            >58r-90v</locus>.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                                <decoNote type="rubrication">
                                    <p>Rubrication (red only) specifying headings and topics in the margins of ff. <locus from="58r" to="90v"
                                            >58r-90v</locus>.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                                <decoNote type="instructions"><p>Guide letters for decorative initials in the margins of ff. <locus from="58r"
                                            to="90v">58r-90v</locus>. </p></decoNote>
                                <decoNote type="other">
                                    <p>Paraph marks in red ff. <locus from="58r" to="90v">58r-90v</locus>.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                            </decoDesc>


                            <additions>
                                <note>Marginal notes in several hands, including the main scribe ff. <locus from="58r" to="90v"
                                    >58r-90v</locus>.</note>
                            </additions>

                        </physDesc>

                        <history>
                            <origin>
                                <origDate calendar="Gregorian" cert="medium" notAfter="1400" notBefore="1300">14th century, probably second half. </origDate>
                                <origPlace cert="high" key="place_g7002445">England. </origPlace>
                            </origin>
                        </history>
                    </msPart>

                    <msPart n="6">
                        <msIdentifier>
                            <idno>Cambridge, Pembroke College, MS 258, ff. 92-122 </idno>
                            <msName>Part 6 - Gospel of John with gloss</msName>
                        </msIdentifier>

                        <msContents>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>

                            <msItem n="1">
                                <locus from="92r" to="122r">92r-122r</locus>
                                <title key="work_12077">Gospel of John [with gloss, Latin]</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <msItem n="1.1">
                                    <locus from="92r" to="92r">92r</locus>
                                    <title key="">Prologue to the Gospel</title>
                                    <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                    <incipit>
                                        <locus from="92r" to="92r">92r</locus> [H]ic Iohannes est ewangelista unus ex discipulis domini</incipit>
                                    <explicit>
                                        <locus from="92r" to="92r">92r</locus> et quarentibus fructum laboris et deo magisterii doctrina seruetur
                                    </explicit>
                                </msItem>
                                <msItem n="1.2">
                                    <locus from="92v" to="122r">92v-122r</locus>
                                    <title key="">Gospel of John</title>
                                    <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                    <incipit>
                                        <locus from="92v" to="92v">92v</locus> In principio erat uerbum et uerbum erat apud deum </incipit>
                                    <explicit>
                                        <locus from="122r" to="122r">122r</locus> nec ipsum <sic>arbritror</sic> mundum capere eos qui scribendi sunt,
                                        libRoS </explicit>
                                    <finalRubric>
                                        <locus from="122r" to="122r">122r</locus> In hoc libro beda et agustinus sunt expositores </finalRubric>
                                </msItem>
                                <msItem n="1.3">
                                    <locus from="92r" to="122r">92r-122r</locus>
                                    <title key="">Gloss to the Gospel of John</title>
                                    <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                    <incipit>
                                        <locus from="92r" to="92r">92r</locus> Omnibus diuine scripture paganis </incipit>
                                    <explicit>
                                        <locus from="122r" to="122r">122r</locus> neque nubentur </explicit>
                                    <note><p>Theological notes in the empty space below the end of the gospel-text on f. <locus from="122r" to="122r"
                                                >122r</locus>, some in the same hand as the gloss. </p></note>
                                    <listBibl>
                                        <bibl>Stegmüller, Bibl. 11830</bibl>
                                    </listBibl>
                                </msItem>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="2">
                                <locus from="122v" to="122v">122v</locus>
                                <title>Responsory for the Commemoration of Thomas Becket with music notation</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <incipit defective="true">
                                    <locus from="122v" to="122v">122v</locus> encium illuderet aspectus hinc uiuens heremitam illinc
                                        <unclear>inc</unclear> episcopum </incipit>
                                <explicit defective="true">
                                    <locus from="122v" to="122v">122v</locus> totus mundus miser orbis <unclear>hebeb</unclear>
                                </explicit>
                                <note><p>4-line stave.</p>
                                    <p>Begins and ends abruptly. </p></note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>J. Toy, 'The Liturgical Commemmoration of Thomas of Canterbury in Scandinavia: The First Thirty Years,
                                        1173-1203' in <hi rend="italic">Of Chronicles and Kings: National Saints and the Emergence of Nation States in
                                            the High Middle Ages</hi>, ed. by J. Bergsagel, D. Hiley and T. Riis (Copenhagen, 2015), pp. 223-250, esp.
                                        p. 233</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                        </msContents>



                        <physDesc>
                            <p><secFol>
                                    <locus from="93r" to="93r">93r</locus> factus est quia prior me erat . et </secFol>
                            </p>

                            <objectDesc form="codex">
                                <supportDesc material="perg">
                                    <support>
                                        <material>Parchment (<term type="disposition">HFFH</term>).</material>
                                    </support>

                                    <extent>
                                        <seg type="object">Codex: </seg>
                                        <seg type="leaf">
                                            <measure quantity="31" type="leaf">31</measure> leaves. </seg>
                                        <seg type="dimensions">
                                            <dimensions type="leaf" unit="mm">
                                                <height quantity="185">185</height>
                                                <width quantity="175">175</width>
                                            </dimensions>
                                        </seg>
                                    </extent>



                                    <collation mainStructures="8">
                                        <p>4 quires of 8 leaves - 6th and 7th leaves cancelled from Quire 11, a leaf added after the 8th leaf of Quire
                                            13: <list>
                                                <item>Quire 10<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> (ff. 92-99)</item>
                                                <item>Quire 11<hi rend="superscript">8-2</hi> (ff. 100-105; 6th and 7th leaves cancelled)</item>
                                                <item>Quire 12<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> (ff. 106-113)</item>
                                                <item>Quire 13<hi rend="superscript">8+1</hi> (ff. 114-122; 1 leaf added after the 8th leaf) |</item>
                                            </list>
                                        </p>
                                    </collation>

                                    <condition>Leaves trimmed; minor losses to text and music on f. <locus from="122v" to="122v">122v</locus>
                                    </condition>

                                </supportDesc>

                                <layoutDesc>
                                    <layout columns="1" rulingMedium="leadpoint" topLine="above" writtenLines="25 26">
                                        <dimensions type="written" unit="mm">
                                            <height max="185" min="180">180-185</height>
                                            <width max="110" min="65">65-110</width>
                                        </dimensions>
                                        <seg type="ruling">Ruled in leadpoint, frame and lines. Text is glossed and each page is divided into three
                                            unequal columns. Main text is written in a single central column on alternate lines, typically 25-26 lines
                                            to the column. Written above top line. </seg>
                                    </layout>

                                    <layout columns="2" rulingMedium="leadpoint" topLine="above" type="gloss" writtenLines="50 60">
                                        <dimensions type="written" unit="mm">
                                            <height max="190" min="185">185-190</height>
                                            <width max="70" min="30">30-70</width>
                                        </dimensions>
                                        <seg type="ruling">Ruled in leadpoint, frame and lines. Text is glossed and each page is divided into three
                                            unequal columns. Gloss is written in two columns, one either side of the central column of main text.
                                            Ruling, and particularly column width varies per leaf, and gloss occasionally extends into non-ruled
                                            spaces and interlinearly into the main text. </seg>
                                    </layout>
                                </layoutDesc>


                            </objectDesc>

                            <handDesc>
                                <handNote script="protogothic">
                                    <p>Main text is written in an English <term type="script">protogothic bookhand</term>, gloss is written in both a
                                        libraria and a more current form of the script by at least two scribes. </p>
                                </handNote>
                            </handDesc>

                            <decoDesc>
                                <decoNote type="unfilled">
                                    <p>Unfilled space for a decorative initial on f. <locus from="92r" to="92r">92r</locus>.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                            </decoDesc>

                        </physDesc>

                        <history>
                            <origin>
                                <origDate calendar="Gregorian" cert="medium" notAfter="1200" notBefore="1173">Second half of the 12th century, almost
                                    certainly after <date when="1173">1173</date>
                                </origDate>
                                <origPlace cert="high" key="place_g7002445">England</origPlace>
                                <p>Likely terminus ante quem non provided by the music on f. <locus from="122v" to="122v">122v</locus>, a responsory
                                    for the commemmoration of Thomas Becket. As the responsory chant is the final item in this section, it could have
                                    been added after the other texts, but all texts were probably added within a quarter-century of one another. </p>
                            </origin>

                        </history>
                    </msPart>

                    <!-- Note for James - this msPart was really complicated. I've identified 4 or 5 texts
                        that MRJ and Thomson missed, but since this msPart is mostly excerpts and redactions in French and Latin
                        and since Quires 14 and 15 are misbound, working out where to start a new msItem was (to put it mildly) a bit
                        of a challenge sometimes -->



                    <msPart n="7">
                        <msIdentifier>
                            <idno>Cambridge, Pembroke College, MS 258, ff. 123-141 </idno>
                            <msName>Part 7 - Miscellaneous texts including notes on the sacraments</msName>
                        </msIdentifier>


                        <msContents>
                            <textLang mainLang="fro" otherLangs="enm la">Old French, Latin and Middle English</textLang>

                            <msItem n="1">
                                <locus from="123r" to="126r">123r-124v 126r</locus>
                                <title>Excerpts from the 'Si scienter' variant of a treatise on confession</title>
                                <author key="person_v86920837">Robert Grosseteste</author>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <rubric><locus from="123r" to="123r">123r</locus> Iste circumstancie circa confessionem sunt inquirenda De quibus
                                    penitencie sunt arbitrarie etc etc </rubric>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="123r" to="123r">123r</locus> Item si <unclear>scienter</unclear> fuisti superbus transgrediendo
                                    mandata Dei</incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="126r" to="126r">126r</locus> Item si maledixeris patri compatri seu commatri </explicit>
                                <note><p>Quire 14 (ff. 123-126) comprises two folded bifolia that have been sewn together sequentially rather than in
                                        a typical 'nested bifolia' arrangement. The second bifolium, comprising the present ff. 125-126, has been sewn
                                        to the first bifolium (ff. 123-124) 'inside out', reversing the original copying sequence of the leaves in the
                                        bifolium; the correct arrangement for the leaves in Quire 14 should be ff. 123, 124, 126, 125.</p>
                                    <p>See Goering and Mantello 'Early Penitential Writings of Robert Grosseteste' for discussion of this text and its
                                        complex transmission. In the article, Goering and Mantello state that the text in MS 258 has been 'heavily
                                        interpolated with extraneous materials' in comparison to the standard form of the text. </p>
                                </note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>J. Goering and F. A. C. Mantello, 'The Early Penitential Writings of Robert Grosseteste', <hi rend="italic"
                                            >Recherches de Théologie Ancienne et Médiévale</hi>, vol. 54, 1987, pp. 52–112</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="2">
                                <locus from="126r" to="126r">126r</locus>
                                <title key="">Notes on the seven deadly sins </title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <rubric>
                                    <locus from="126r" to="126r">126r</locus> Primum </rubric>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="126r" to="126r">126r</locus> Superbia <lb/> Est non habere pudorem de malo aperto </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="126r" to="126r">126r</locus> corpore et corde et de uerbis et tales vocabuntur filii dei </explicit>
                                <finalRubric>
                                    <locus from="126r" to="126r">126r</locus> septimus </finalRubric>
                                <note><p>Superbia, inuidia, ira, accidia, auaricia, gulositas (for gula), luxuria</p>
                                    <p>Quire 14 (ff. 123-126) comprises two folded bifolia that have been sewn together sequentially rather than in a
                                        typical 'nested bifolia' arrangement. The second bifolium, comprising the present ff. 125-126, has been sewn
                                        to the first bifolium (ff. 123-124) 'inside out', reversing the original copying sequence of the leaves in the
                                        bifolium; the correct arrangement for the leaves in Quire 14 should be ff. 123, 124, 126, 125.</p></note>

                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="3">
                                <locus from="126v" to="126v">126v</locus>
                                <title key="">Excerpts from a sermon on the decalogue attributed to Robert Grosseteste</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="126v" to="126v">126v</locus> Non habebis deos alienos quia homo debet adorare solam maiestatem
                                    diuinam </incipit>
                                <explicit defective="true">
                                    <locus from="126v" to="126v">126v</locus> proximi violare cum non solum sit prohibitum mecari sed et illius
                                        concupis<unclear>...</unclear>
                                </explicit>
                                <note><p>Text ends abruptly. </p>
                                    <p>See McEvoy, 'Edition of a Sermon' for discussion of this text (not this MS) and its complex transmission.</p>
                                    <p>Quire 14 (ff. 123-126) comprises two folded bifolia that have been sewn together sequentially rather than in a
                                        typical 'nested bifolia' arrangement. The second bifolium, comprising the present ff. 125-126, has been sewn
                                        to the first bifolium (ff. 123-124) 'inside out', reversing the original copying sequence of the leaves in the
                                        bifolium; the correct arrangement for the leaves in Quire 14 should be ff. 123, 124, 126, 125.</p></note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>James McEvoy, 'The Edition of a Sermon on the Decalogue Attributed to Robert Grosseteste, <hi rend="italic"
                                            >Recherches de Théologie et Philosophie Médiévales</hi>, vol. 68, no. 2, 2001, pp. 228–44 </bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="4">
                                <locus from="125r" to="125v">125r-125v</locus>
                                <title key="">Text on vices</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <incipit defective="true">
                                    <locus from="125r" to="125r">125r</locus> Exultatio in adversis proximi<lb/> afflictio in prosperis proximi <lb/>
                                    periurium super librium <lb/>
                                    <sic>blasphefare</sic> proximium </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="125v" to="125v">125v</locus> si volentes seruicium dei audire impeduisti </explicit>
                                <note><p>Begins abruptly, perhaps incomplete at the beginning.</p>
                                    <p>Mise-en-page typical for verse; two columns on f. 125r, one column on f. 125v.</p>
                                    <p>Quire 14 (ff. 123-126) comprises two folded bifolia that have been sewn together sequentially rather than in a
                                        typical 'nested bifolia' arrangement. The second bifolium, comprising the present ff. 125-126, has been sewn
                                        to the first bifolium (ff. 123-124) 'inside out', reversing the original copying sequence of the leaves in the
                                        bifolium; the correct arrangement for the leaves in Quire 14 should be ff. 123, 124, 126, 125.</p></note>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="5">
                                <locus from="125v" to="125v">125v</locus>
                                <title key="work_3839">Excerpt from chapter 4 of the Similitudines Anselmi</title>
                                <author key="person_v280344084">pseud-Anselm of Canterbury</author>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <rubric>
                                    <locus from="125v" to="125v">125v</locus> Sensus humani generis </rubric>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="125v" to="125v">125v</locus> Uisus ad <sic>recta</sic> uidenda </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="125v" to="125v">125v</locus> Pedes ad ambulanda quo debent </explicit>
                                <note><p>Longer version in <bibl subtype="external" type="MS"><ref
                                                target="https://medieval.bodleian.ox.ac.uk/catalog/manuscript_7304">Oxford, Bodleian Library, MS Laud
                                                Misc. 502, ff. 5r-51r, esp. f. 5rb</ref>
                                        </bibl></p>
                                    <p>Quire 14 (ff. 123-126) comprises two folded bifolia that have been sewn together sequentially rather than in a
                                        typical 'nested bifolia' arrangement. The second bifolium, comprising the present ff. 125-126, has been sewn
                                        to the first bifolium (ff. 123-124) 'inside out', reversing the original copying sequence of the leaves in the
                                        bifolium; the correct arrangement for the leaves in Quire 14 should be ff. 123, 124, 126, 125.</p></note>
                            </msItem>


                            <msItem n="6">
                                <locus from="127r" to="133v">133rv, 127r-129r, 131rv</locus>
                                <title key="work_1446">Extracts from the Mirour de seinte eglise [French]</title>
                                <author key="person_v315944519">Edmund Riche (Edmund of Abingdon)</author>
                                <textLang mainLang="fro" otherLangs="la enm">Old French with occasional Latin and Middle English</textLang>
                                <incipit defective="true">
                                    <locus from="133r" to="133r">133r</locus> Les vii morteus peches sount iceus . Orgoyl . Enuye . Ire . Accide .
                                    Auarice . Glotonye . e . Lecherie </incipit>
                                <explicit defective="true">
                                    <locus from="131v" to="131v">131v</locus> e tes leures en le sauter . e tonn quer en marche chaitiuement es diuise
                                    etc </explicit>
                                <note><p>Cambridge, Pembroke College, MS 258 is 'MS C5' in Wilshere's discussion of the text, and contains extracts
                                        from the so-called 'lay version' of the text. Note that MS 258 was not used in Wilshere's edition of this
                                        text.</p>
                                    <p>Extracts from chapters 8, 11, 13, 14, 21-27, 17. </p>
                                    <p>This text contains a verse fragment in Middle English (IMEV 2320 / DIMEV 3742), present in this manuscript on
                                        f. <locus from="129r" to="129r">129r</locus>:<lb/> Nou goht sunne wnder wode <lb/> ond me rewez marie þi
                                        bricte rude <lb/> Nou goz sunne vnder tre <lb/> ond me rewez marie þi sone ant þe etc</p>
                                    <p>Quire 15 is misbound. The present f. 133, a singleton, is now bound as the last leaf in the quire, but was
                                        originally the first leaf in the quire. </p>
                                </note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>Text edited in A.D. Wilshere, <hi rend="italic">Mirour de seinte eglyse (St Edmund of Abingdon's</hi>
                                        Speculum Eclesie<hi rend="italic">)</hi>, Anglo-Norman Texts 40 (London, 1982)</bibl>
                                    <bibl>Dean and Boulton, <hi rend="italic">Anglo-Norman Literature</hi>, no. 629</bibl>
                                    <bibl>IMEV 2320</bibl>
                                    <bibl>DIMEV 3742</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="7">
                                <locus from="129v" to="130v">129v-130v</locus>
                                <title key="">Theological notes in Latin</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="129v" to="129v">129v</locus> Primum ordinat ad patrem sed non habebis deos alienos </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="130v" to="130v">130v</locus> Postea queritur quid sit affinitas Respondet non affinitas est
                                    personarium proximitas ex carnali copula proueniens omni carens parentela </explicit>
                                <note><p>Notes on the ten commandments, on the eucharist, on penance, on excommunication, extreme unction, and
                                        consanguinity. Seemingly not excerpts from the Speculum ecclesiae (the base text for the Mirour de saint
                                        eglise). </p></note>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="8">
                                <locus from="131v" to="131v">131v</locus>
                                <title key="">Theological note in Latin</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <note><p>Full transcription:<lb/> Propter hoc ergo dicendum est quod orationes atque suffragia
                                            <unclear>etiam</unclear> non prosunt dampnatis et ad illud quod <unclear>...</unclear> quod cantamus ut
                                        liberentur a penis <sic>infernis</sic> . dicendum quod pene inferni ibi non supp<unclear>...</unclear> pro
                                        penis inferni dampnatoris . set accipitur ibi infernus pro purgatorio igne . qui <unclear>dicitur</unclear>
                                        tartarus uel infernus propter conformitatem cuiusdam acerbitatis pene quod est in purgatorio quae maior est
                                        quam maxima quae possit excogitari in hoc mundo bonum est cum semper ut pro omnibus fiant orationes atque
                                        suffragia quia et si non valent eis pro quibus fiunt in valent cum eius qui faciunt amen</p></note>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="9">
                                <locus from="131v" to="131v">131v</locus>
                                <title key="">Diagrammatic note on the meaning of various lines of the Pater noster</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="10">
                                <locus from="131v" to="132v">131v-132v</locus>
                                <title key="">Theological notes in Latin</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <note><p>Notes on baptism. </p></note>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="11">
                                <locus from="134r" to="134v">134r-134v</locus>
                                <title key="work_5104">Manuel des péchés [French]</title>
                                <author key="person_v38264089">William de Wadington</author>
                                <textLang mainLang="xno">Anglo-Norman</textLang>
                                <incipit defective="true">
                                    <locus from="134r" to="134r">134r</locus> Seynte Gregorii pape de Rome </incipit>
                                <explicit defective="true">
                                    <locus from="134v" to="134v">134v</locus> Ceo dist le prestre tauerner etc </explicit>
                                <note><p>The poem was edited (not from this MS) for the Roxburghe Club by F. J. Furnivall (London, 1862); the lines of
                                        the poem in Pembroke College MS 258 correspond with ll. 4446-4475, 5106-5143, 5264-5293, 5336-5361 in the
                                        edition. </p>
                                    <p>The text on f. <locus from="134r" to="134r">134r</locus> is badly damaged due to rubbing. </p></note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>Furnivall (1862)</bibl>
                                    <bibl>Dean and Boulton, <hi rend="italic">Anglo-Norman Literature</hi> (1999), no. 635.</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="12">
                                <locus from="134v" to="141v">134v-141v</locus>
                                <title>Miscellaneous notes and extracts, mostly on confession</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="enm" otherLangs="la">Middle English and Latin</textLang>
                                <msItem n="12.1">
                                    <locus from="134v" to="134v">134v</locus>
                                    <title>The Three Sorrowful Things [Middle English verse]</title>
                                    <textLang mainLang="enm">Middle English</textLang>
                                    <incipit>
                                        <locus from="134v" to="134v">134v</locus> Heuerei day me comeȝ tiþinge þre </incipit>
                                    <explicit>
                                        <locus from="134v" to="134v">134v</locus> þe þridde is mi moste kare <lb/> þat I . ne woot woder I scal fare </explicit>
                                    <listBibl>
                                        <bibl>DIMEV 1157</bibl>
                                    </listBibl>
                                </msItem>
                                <msItem n="12.2">
                                    <locus from="135r" to="136r">135r-136r</locus>
                                    <title key="">Notes on the virtues, vices and sacraments</title>
                                    <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                    <incipit>
                                        <locus from="135r" to="135r">135r</locus> Superbia . bona naturalia </incipit>
                                    <explicit>
                                        <locus from="136r" to="136r">136r</locus> fit mortale peccarum </explicit>
                                </msItem>
                                <msItem n="12.3">
                                    <locus from="135v" to="135v">135v</locus>
                                    <title>Three things it been that I hold price [Middle English verse]</title>
                                    <textLang mainLang="enm">Middle English</textLang>
                                    <incipit>
                                        <locus from="135v" to="135v">135v</locus> þre þingges it ben þat I holde pris </incipit>
                                    <explicit>
                                        <locus from="135v" to="135v">135v</locus> þe þridde to love þe lawe þat in þe lond is </explicit>
                                    <listBibl>
                                        <bibl>DIMEV 5903 (misidentified as belonging to <hi rend="italic">Oxford</hi>, Pembroke College, MS
                                            258)</bibl>
                                    </listBibl>
                                </msItem>
                                <msItem n="12.4">
                                    <locus from="136r" to="136r">136r</locus>
                                    <title>This world him plaineth of mickle untrue [Middle English verse]</title>
                                    <textLang mainLang="enm" otherLangs="la">Middle English and Latin</textLang>
                                    <note><p> Heus plebs conqueritur quod pauca fides reperitur <lb/> Lex uiris moritur fraus regnat amor sepelitur
                                            <lb/> þis world hym pleyneȝ of mikel ontrewe <lb/> Ryt is ded ant þat is reweze <lb/> Falsnesse regnez ant
                                            is aboue <lb/> Non is biried trew loue </p></note>
                                    <listBibl>
                                        <bibl>DIMEV 5787</bibl>
                                    </listBibl>
                                </msItem>
                                <msItem n="12.5">
                                    <locus from="136v" to="141v">136v-141v</locus>
                                    <title>Exemplary stories including the story of Egyptius and Baldath</title>
                                    <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                    <incipit>
                                        <locus from="136v" to="136v">136v</locus> Relatum est mihi de duobus negotiatoribus </incipit>
                                    <explicit>
                                        <locus from="141v" to="141v">141v</locus> solebant coronari etc </explicit>
                                    <note><p>This text appears to derive from Petrus Alfonsi</p></note>
                                </msItem>
                                <msItem n="12.6">
                                    <locus from="141v" to="141v">141v</locus>
                                    <title>Merry a time I tell in May [Middle English verse]</title>
                                    <textLang mainLang="enm" otherLangs="la">middle English and Latin</textLang>
                                    <note><p> Full transcription: <lb/> Cantus occidentalis<lb/> Myrie a tyme I telle In may<lb/> Wan bricte blosmen
                                            brekez on tre<lb/> þeise foules singez nyt ant day<lb/> In ilche grene is gamen an gle </p>
                                    </note>
                                    <listBibl>
                                        <bibl>DIMEV 3486</bibl>
                                    </listBibl>
                                </msItem>
                                <note><p>It is not easy to distinguish the boundaries between some of the texts on ff. <locus from="134v" to="141v"
                                            >134v-141v</locus> - a selection of the identifiable texts are listed here. </p></note>
                            </msItem>

                        </msContents>

                        <physDesc>
                            <p><secFol>
                                    <locus from="124r" to="124r">124r</locus>
                                </secFol>
                            </p>
                            <objectDesc form="codex">
                                <supportDesc material="perg">
                                    <support>
                                        <material>Parchment (<term type="disposition">HFFH</term>)</material>
                                    </support>

                                    <extent>
                                        <seg type="object">Codex: </seg>
                                        <seg type="leaf">
                                            <measure quantity="19" type="leaf">19</measure> leaves. </seg>
                                        <seg type="dimensions">
                                            <dimensions type="leaf" unit="mm">
                                                <height quantity="235">235</height>
                                                <width quantity="185">185</width>
                                            </dimensions>
                                        </seg>
                                    </extent>

                                    <collation mainStructures="4 6 8"> Three quires of differing size. Leaves in Quires 14 and 15 are misbound. Quire
                                        14, a quire of four leaves (ff. 123-126), consists of two sequential rather than nested bifolia, and the
                                        second bifolium, the present ff. <locus from="125r" to="126v">125r-126v</locus> has been bound inside out; the
                                        leaves in Quire 14 should be read ff. 123, 124, 126, 125. Quire 15 is a quire of 7 leaves (ff. 127-133),
                                        comprising three nested bifolia and a singleton (f. 133) after the 6th leaf; the singleton is misbound and
                                        should be the first leaf in the quire; the leaves in Quire 15 should be read ff. 133, 127-132. <p>
                                            <list>
                                                <item>Quire 14<hi rend="superscript">4</hi> (ff. <locus from="123r" to="126v">123-126</locus>)</item>
                                                <item>Quire 15<hi rend="superscript">6+1</hi> (ff. <locus from="127r" to="133v">127-133</locus>; 1
                                                    leaf added after the 6th)</item>
                                                <item>Quire 16<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> (ff. <locus from="134r" to="141v">134-141</locus>)</item>
                                            </list>
                                        </p>
                                    </collation>

                                    <condition>Leaves are lightly stained and torn and some text is faded due to rubbing and liquid damage. </condition>

                                </supportDesc>

                                <layoutDesc>
                                    <layout columns="1" rulingMedium="leadpoint" topLine="below" writtenLines="30 50">
                                        <dimensions type="written" unit="mm">
                                            <height quantity="200">200</height>
                                            <width quantity="160">160</width>
                                        </dimensions>
                                        <seg type="ruling">Typically arranged in single-column format, although ff. <locus from="125r" to="125r"
                                                >125r</locus> and <locus from="134r" to="136r">134r-136r</locus> are in double-columns. Ruling, where
                                            present, is in leadpoint, and is usually frame and lines. Script size and page use is informal: 35-50
                                            lines to the column or page on most leaves. Written below top line. </seg>
                                    </layout>
                                </layoutDesc>

                            </objectDesc>

                            <handDesc>
                                <handNote script="cursivaAntiquior">
                                    <p>Written in several <term type="script">anglicana</term> hands.</p>
                                </handNote>
                            </handDesc>

                            <decoDesc>
                                <decoNote type="miniature">
                                    <p>Head of a dog sketched on f. <locus from="140v" to="140v">140v</locus>. </p>
                                </decoNote>
                                <decoNote type="rubrication"><p>Rubrication (red only) by underlining to highlight particular letters or passages.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                            </decoDesc>

                            <additions>
                                <note>
                                    <p>At the bottom of f. <locus from="129r" to="129r">129r</locus> a note in Latin about why people must be baptised
                                        in water rather than wine, milk, or any other fluid. </p>
                                </note>
                            </additions>
                        </physDesc>

                        <history>
                            <origin>
                                <origDate calendar="Gregorian" cert="low" notAfter="1400" notBefore="1300"> 14th century. </origDate>
                                <origPlace cert="high" key="place_g7002445">England. </origPlace>
                            </origin>

                        </history>
                    </msPart>

                    <msPart n="8">
                        <msIdentifier>
                            <idno>Cambridge, Pembroke College, MS 258 - binding and binding lining</idno>
                            <msName>Part 8 - binding and binding lining</msName>
                        </msIdentifier>

                        <msContents>

                            <textLang mainLang="la" otherLangs="">Latin</textLang>

                            <msItem n="1">
                                <locus from="binding leaf i verso - paper" to="binding leaf iii recto - paper">binding leaf i verso - paper - binding
                                    leaf iii recto - paper</locus>
                                <title key="">Notes of miscellaneous fees and fines</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <note><p>These leaves were once used as a lining to strengthen and supply structure to the binding of Pembroke
                                        College, MS 258. The leaves were originally pasted together, but have become partially separated and some of
                                        the leaves are now free. Some of the text on the leaves is legible, but much is either badly damaged or
                                        obscured by overlapping fragments of other text.</p>
                                    <p>The leaves contain dating clauses for various regnal years in the reign of <name key="person_v286746619">
                                            <persName type="display">Edward IV, King of England, (b. 1442, d. 1483)</persName>
                                            <persName type="standard">Edward IV, King of England, (b. 1442, d. 1483)</persName>
                                        </name> (r. 4 March 1461 - 3 October 1470, then again 11 April 1471 - 9 April 1483)</p>
                                    <p>Several names are visible on the leaves including: <list>
                                            <item>John Gilberd</item>
                                            <item>Agnes Quable</item>
                                            <item>Doctor Uske</item>
                                            <item>John Ffostar</item>
                                            <item>John Wotton</item>
                                            <item>Jacobus Gossope</item>
                                            <item>Rogerus Pemberton</item>
                                            <item>Thomas Marsshall</item>
                                            <item><add>Ric</add> Garreys sadelor</item>
                                            <item>Georgius Saverey</item>
                                            <item>R. Stile</item>
                                            <item>John Child</item>
                                            <item>Henricus Drawewett</item>
                                            <item>Willelmus Wrothe</item>
                                            <item>John Crowche smyth</item>
                                            <item>John Undebynton</item>
                                            <item>William Rede</item>
                                            <item>Simon peyntor</item>
                                            <item>John Curteys</item>
                                            <item>Edmundus Kyrcheley</item>
                                            <item>Johannes Barbor</item>
                                            <item>Willelmus Carpenter</item>
                                        </list></p>
                                    <p>Several places in London on the south bank of the Thames are mentioned including Blakmanstrete, Kenstrete (Kent
                                        Street), Pety Aley (?Pepper Alley), Piper Aley (Pepper Alley), Suthwerk (Southwark). </p>
                                </note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl/>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>


                        </msContents>



                        <physDesc>

                            <objectDesc form="other">
                                <supportDesc material="mixed">

                                    <support>
                                        <material>A mix of paper, parchment and linen. All text-leaves in this Part are paper. No watermarks
                                            visible.</material>
                                    </support>


                                    <extent>
                                        <seg type="object">Fragments. </seg>
                                    </extent>

                                    <collation>
                                        <signatures type="leaf"><p>No leaf signatures particular to this Part. </p></signatures>
                                        <signatures type="quire"><p>No quire signatures particular to this Part. </p></signatures>
                                        <catchwords><seg type="para">No catchwords particular to this Part. </seg></catchwords>
                                    </collation>

                                    <condition> Stable, but in poor condition. The leaves in this Part were originally pasted together and used to
                                        line the binding of Cambridge, Pembroke College, MS 258. Some of the leaves used for lining the binding of
                                        Cambridge, Pembroke College, MS 258 have been partially separated and it is possible to read portions of the
                                        text on those leaves, but the leaves are oriented in several directions, are coated in adhesive and paper
                                        residue, and are often partially obscured by scraps of smaller paper fragments. The volume was conserved in
                                        2024 and significant work was done to stabilise the binding and the binding lining leaves. The layers of the
                                        section of the binding over the rear of the volume, i.e., linen, lining fragments, limp-parchment are held in
                                        place with an acetate band when the volume is not in use. </condition>

                                </supportDesc>



                            </objectDesc>

                            <handDesc>
                                <handNote script="cursivaAntiquior">
                                    <p>Written in a a chancery <term type="script">Anglicana</term> by several scribes.</p>
                                </handNote>
                            </handDesc>

                            <decoDesc>

                                <decoNote type="none">
                                    <p>No significant decoration in this Part. </p>
                                </decoNote>
                            </decoDesc>

                        </physDesc>

                        <history>
                            <origin>
                                <origDate calendar="Gregorian" cert="high" notAfter="1483" notBefore="1461">Probably 1461×1483. </origDate>
                                <origPlace cert="high" key="place_g7002445">England, probably London. </origPlace>
                                <p>Date of production based on the presence of several regnal dating clauses in the text that refer to the reign of
                                    Edward IV. </p>
                            </origin>

                        </history>



                    </msPart>

                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <classDecl>
                <taxonomy xml:id="LCSH">
                    <bibl>
                        <ref target="https://authorities.loc.gov/">Library of Congress Subject Headings</ref>
                    </bibl>
                </taxonomy>
            </classDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="#LCSH">
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <term key="subject_sh85058659">Handbook, vade mecum</term>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc status="draft">
            <change status="draft" when="20221214">
                <persName>Sarah Gilbert, Project Cataloguer, Curious Cures Project, Cambridge University Library</persName>
            </change>

        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>


    <facsimile>
        <graphic decls="#document-thumbnail" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00001"/>
        <surface n="outside front cover - parchment" xml:id="page-surface-1">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8967px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00001" width="6946px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="front binding lining - linen" xml:id="page-surface-2">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8967px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00002" width="6725px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="1r" xml:id="page-surface-3">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7953px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00003" width="5693px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="1v" xml:id="page-surface-4">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7953px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00004" width="5693px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="2r" xml:id="page-surface-5">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7933px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00005" width="5560px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="2v" xml:id="page-surface-6">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7933px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00006" width="5560px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="3r" xml:id="page-surface-7">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7933px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00007" width="5560px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="3v" xml:id="page-surface-8">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7933px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00008" width="5560px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="4r" xml:id="page-surface-9">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7933px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00009" width="5560px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="4v" xml:id="page-surface-10">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7933px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00010" width="5477px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="5r" xml:id="page-surface-11">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7933px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00011" width="5560px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="5v" xml:id="page-surface-12">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7933px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00012" width="5560px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="6r" xml:id="page-surface-13">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7933px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00013" width="5560px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="6v" xml:id="page-surface-14">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8120px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00014" width="5443px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="7r" xml:id="page-surface-15">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7992px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00015" width="5560px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="7v" xml:id="page-surface-16">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7992px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00016" width="5560px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="8r" xml:id="page-surface-17">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8085px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00017" width="5560px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="8v" xml:id="page-surface-18">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8085px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00018" width="5560px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="9r" xml:id="page-surface-19">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8297px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00019" width="5524px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="9v" xml:id="page-surface-20">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8297px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00020" width="5524px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="10r" xml:id="page-surface-21">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8137px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00021" width="5360px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="10v" xml:id="page-surface-22">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8137px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00022" width="5360px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="11r" xml:id="page-surface-23">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8177px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00023" width="5581px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="11v" xml:id="page-surface-24">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8177px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00024" width="5581px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="12r" xml:id="page-surface-25">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8177px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00025" width="5581px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="12v" xml:id="page-surface-26">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8177px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00026" width="5581px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="13r" xml:id="page-surface-27">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7988px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00027" width="5478px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="13v" xml:id="page-surface-28">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7988px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00028" width="5478px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="14r" xml:id="page-surface-29">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7992px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00029" width="5447px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="14v" xml:id="page-surface-30">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7992px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00030" width="5447px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="15r" xml:id="page-surface-31">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7881px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00031" width="5447px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="15v" xml:id="page-surface-32">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7881px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00032" width="5447px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="16r" xml:id="page-surface-33">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7903px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00033" width="5447px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="16v" xml:id="page-surface-34">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7903px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00034" width="5447px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="17r" xml:id="page-surface-35">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7992px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00035" width="5423px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="17v" xml:id="page-surface-36">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7992px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00036" width="5423px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="18r" xml:id="page-surface-37">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7992px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00037" width="5447px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="18v" xml:id="page-surface-38">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7992px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00038" width="5447px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="19r" xml:id="page-surface-39">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7992px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00039" width="5447px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="19v" xml:id="page-surface-40">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7992px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00040" width="5576px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="20r" xml:id="page-surface-41">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7992px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00041" width="5447px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="20v" xml:id="page-surface-42">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7992px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00042" width="5568px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="21r" xml:id="page-surface-43">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9031px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00043" width="5953px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="21v" xml:id="page-surface-44">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8950px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00044" width="5877px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="22r" xml:id="page-surface-45">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9031px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00045" width="5953px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="22v" xml:id="page-surface-46">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8983px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00046" width="5877px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="23r" xml:id="page-surface-47">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9031px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00047" width="6081px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="23v" xml:id="page-surface-48">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8983px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00048" width="5877px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="24r" xml:id="page-surface-49">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9031px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00049" width="6081px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="24v" xml:id="page-surface-50">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8982px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00050" width="5942px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="25r" xml:id="page-surface-51">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9031px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00051" width="6081px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="25v" xml:id="page-surface-52">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9121px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00052" width="5942px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="26r" xml:id="page-surface-53">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9031px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00053" width="6081px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="26v" xml:id="page-surface-54">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9121px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00054" width="5942px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="27r" xml:id="page-surface-55">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9031px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00055" width="6081px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="27v" xml:id="page-surface-56">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9121px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00056" width="5942px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="28r" xml:id="page-surface-57">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9031px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00057" width="6081px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="28v" xml:id="page-surface-58">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9121px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00058" width="5942px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="29r" xml:id="page-surface-59">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9031px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00059" width="6081px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="29v" xml:id="page-surface-60">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9121px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00060" width="5942px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="30r" xml:id="page-surface-61">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9031px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00061" width="6081px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="30v" xml:id="page-surface-62">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9031px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00062" width="5932px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="31r" xml:id="page-surface-63">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8947px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00063" width="6006px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="31v" xml:id="page-surface-64">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9031px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00064" width="5914px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="32r" xml:id="page-surface-65">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9047px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00065" width="5902px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="32v" xml:id="page-surface-66">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9047px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00066" width="5834px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="33r" xml:id="page-surface-67">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8947px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00067" width="5902px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="33v" xml:id="page-surface-68">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8947px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00068" width="5902px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="34r" xml:id="page-surface-69">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8947px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00069" width="5902px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="34v" xml:id="page-surface-70">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8947px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00070" width="5902px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="35r" xml:id="page-surface-71">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8947px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00071" width="5902px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="35v" xml:id="page-surface-72">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8947px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00072" width="5902px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="36r" xml:id="page-surface-73">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8947px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00073" width="5902px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="36v" xml:id="page-surface-74">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8947px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00074" width="5902px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="37r" xml:id="page-surface-75">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8947px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00075" width="5902px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="37v" xml:id="page-surface-76">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8947px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00076" width="5902px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="38r" xml:id="page-surface-77">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8947px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00077" width="5902px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="38v" xml:id="page-surface-78">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8947px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00078" width="5902px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="39r" xml:id="page-surface-79">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8947px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00079" width="5902px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="39v" xml:id="page-surface-80">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8947px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00080" width="5902px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="40r" xml:id="page-surface-81">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9094px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00081" width="5902px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="40v" xml:id="page-surface-82">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9094px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00082" width="5902px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="41r" xml:id="page-surface-83">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9094px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00083" width="5902px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="41v" xml:id="page-surface-84">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9094px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00084" width="5902px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="42r" xml:id="page-surface-85">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9051px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00085" width="5902px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="42v" xml:id="page-surface-86">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9051px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00086" width="5902px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="43r" xml:id="page-surface-87">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9051px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00087" width="5902px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="43v" xml:id="page-surface-88">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9051px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00088" width="5902px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="44r" xml:id="page-surface-89">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7470px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00089" width="5828px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="44v" xml:id="page-surface-90">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="7470px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00090" width="5828px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="45r" xml:id="page-surface-91">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00091" width="6305px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="45v" xml:id="page-surface-92">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00092" width="6305px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="46r" xml:id="page-surface-93">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00093" width="6305px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="46v" xml:id="page-surface-94">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00094" width="6250px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="47r" xml:id="page-surface-95">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00095" width="6305px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="47v" xml:id="page-surface-96">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00096" width="6197px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="48r" xml:id="page-surface-97">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00097" width="6305px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="48v" xml:id="page-surface-98">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00098" width="6173px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="49r" xml:id="page-surface-99">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00099" width="6305px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="49v" xml:id="page-surface-100">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00100" width="6051px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="50r" xml:id="page-surface-101">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00101" width="6305px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="50v" xml:id="page-surface-102">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00102" width="6238px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="51r" xml:id="page-surface-103">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00103" width="6199px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="51v" xml:id="page-surface-104">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00104" width="6199px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="52r" xml:id="page-surface-105">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00105" width="6199px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="52v" xml:id="page-surface-106">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00106" width="6199px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="53r" xml:id="page-surface-107">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00107" width="6081px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="53v" xml:id="page-surface-108">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00108" width="5971px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="54r" xml:id="page-surface-109">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00109" width="6081px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="54v" xml:id="page-surface-110">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00110" width="5826px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="55r" xml:id="page-surface-111">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00111" width="5894px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="55v" xml:id="page-surface-112">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00112" width="5826px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="56r" xml:id="page-surface-113">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00113" width="5894px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="56v" xml:id="page-surface-114">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00114" width="5826px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="57r" xml:id="page-surface-115">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9115px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00115" width="5997px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="57v" xml:id="page-surface-116">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9092px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00116" width="6010px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="58r" xml:id="page-surface-117">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9115px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00117" width="6489px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="58v" xml:id="page-surface-118">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9115px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00118" width="6489px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="59r" xml:id="page-surface-119">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9067px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00119" width="6489px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="59v" xml:id="page-surface-120">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9115px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00120" width="6489px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="60r" xml:id="page-surface-121">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9067px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00121" width="6489px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="60v" xml:id="page-surface-122">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9115px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00122" width="6489px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="61r" xml:id="page-surface-123">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00123" width="6489px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="61v" xml:id="page-surface-124">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00124" width="6489px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="62r" xml:id="page-surface-125">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00125" width="6489px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="62v" xml:id="page-surface-126">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00126" width="6429px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="63r" xml:id="page-surface-127">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00127" width="6489px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="63v" xml:id="page-surface-128">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00128" width="6429px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="64r" xml:id="page-surface-129">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00129" width="6489px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="64v" xml:id="page-surface-130">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00130" width="6429px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="65r" xml:id="page-surface-131">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00131" width="6489px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="65v" xml:id="page-surface-132">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00132" width="6429px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="66r" xml:id="page-surface-133">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00133" width="6489px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="66v" xml:id="page-surface-134">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00134" width="6429px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="67r" xml:id="page-surface-135">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9059px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00135" width="6399px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="67v" xml:id="page-surface-136">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00136" width="6429px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="68r" xml:id="page-surface-137">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9059px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00137" width="6399px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="68v" xml:id="page-surface-138">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00138" width="6429px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="69r" xml:id="page-surface-139">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9059px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00139" width="6399px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="69v" xml:id="page-surface-140">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00140" width="6429px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="70r" xml:id="page-surface-141">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9059px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00141" width="6399px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="70v" xml:id="page-surface-142">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00142" width="6429px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="71r" xml:id="page-surface-143">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9059px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00143" width="6399px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="71v" xml:id="page-surface-144">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00144" width="6429px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="72r" xml:id="page-surface-145">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9059px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00145" width="6399px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="72v" xml:id="page-surface-146">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00146" width="6429px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="73r" xml:id="page-surface-147">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9059px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00147" width="6399px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="73v" xml:id="page-surface-148">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00148" width="6429px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="74r" xml:id="page-surface-149">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9059px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00149" width="6399px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="74v" xml:id="page-surface-150">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00150" width="6429px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="75r" xml:id="page-surface-151">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9059px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00151" width="6399px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="75v" xml:id="page-surface-152">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00152" width="6429px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="76r" xml:id="page-surface-153">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9059px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00153" width="6399px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="76v" xml:id="page-surface-154">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00154" width="6429px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="77r" xml:id="page-surface-155">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9059px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00155" width="6399px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="77v" xml:id="page-surface-156">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00156" width="6429px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="78r" xml:id="page-surface-157">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9059px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00157" width="6519px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="78v" xml:id="page-surface-158">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00158" width="6429px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="79r" xml:id="page-surface-159">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8974px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00159" width="6519px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="79v" xml:id="page-surface-160">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8974px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00160" width="6519px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="80r" xml:id="page-surface-161">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9120px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00161" width="6481px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="80v" xml:id="page-surface-162">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9120px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00162" width="6481px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="81r" xml:id="page-surface-163">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9120px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00163" width="6481px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="81v" xml:id="page-surface-164">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9120px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00164" width="6303px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="82r" xml:id="page-surface-165">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9120px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00165" width="6306px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="82v" xml:id="page-surface-166">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9120px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00166" width="6303px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="83r" xml:id="page-surface-167">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9120px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00167" width="6306px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="83v" xml:id="page-surface-168">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9120px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00168" width="6303px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="84r" xml:id="page-surface-169">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9120px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00169" width="6306px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="84v" xml:id="page-surface-170">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9064px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00170" width="6303px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="85r" xml:id="page-surface-171">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9120px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00171" width="6306px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="85v" xml:id="page-surface-172">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9064px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00172" width="6303px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="86r" xml:id="page-surface-173">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9120px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00173" width="6306px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="86v" xml:id="page-surface-174">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9064px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00174" width="6303px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="87r" xml:id="page-surface-175">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9120px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00175" width="6306px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="87v" xml:id="page-surface-176">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9064px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00176" width="6303px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="88r" xml:id="page-surface-177">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9120px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00177" width="6306px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="88v" xml:id="page-surface-178">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9064px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00178" width="6303px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="89r" xml:id="page-surface-179">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9120px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00179" width="6306px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="89v" xml:id="page-surface-180">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9064px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00180" width="6303px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="90r" xml:id="page-surface-181">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9017px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00181" width="6206px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="90v" xml:id="page-surface-182">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8977px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00182" width="6163px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="91r" xml:id="page-surface-183">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9017px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00183" width="6206px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="91v" xml:id="page-surface-184">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8977px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00184" width="6163px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="92r" xml:id="page-surface-185">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9017px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00185" width="6682px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="92v" xml:id="page-surface-186">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00186" width="6509px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="93r" xml:id="page-surface-187">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9017px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00187" width="6682px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="93v" xml:id="page-surface-188">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9014px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00188" width="6509px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="94r" xml:id="page-surface-189">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9140px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00189" width="6682px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="94v" xml:id="page-surface-190">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9096px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00190" width="6471px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="95r" xml:id="page-surface-191">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9140px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00191" width="6682px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="95v" xml:id="page-surface-192">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9096px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00192" width="6471px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="96r" xml:id="page-surface-193">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9140px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00193" width="6609px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="96v" xml:id="page-surface-194">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9096px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00194" width="6471px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="97r" xml:id="page-surface-195">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9140px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00195" width="6609px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="97v" xml:id="page-surface-196">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9096px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00196" width="6471px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="98r" xml:id="page-surface-197">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9140px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00197" width="6609px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="98v" xml:id="page-surface-198">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9096px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00198" width="6471px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="99r" xml:id="page-surface-199">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9140px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00199" width="6609px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="99v" xml:id="page-surface-200">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9096px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00200" width="6471px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="100r" xml:id="page-surface-201">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9140px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00201" width="6799px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="100v" xml:id="page-surface-202">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9096px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00202" width="6471px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="101r" xml:id="page-surface-203">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9140px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00203" width="6799px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="101v" xml:id="page-surface-204">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9096px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00204" width="6471px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="102r" xml:id="page-surface-205">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9140px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00205" width="6799px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="102v" xml:id="page-surface-206">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9096px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00206" width="6471px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="103r" xml:id="page-surface-207">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9140px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00207" width="6565px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="103v" xml:id="page-surface-208">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9096px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00208" width="6471px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="104r" xml:id="page-surface-209">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9140px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00209" width="6565px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="104v" xml:id="page-surface-210">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9096px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00210" width="6471px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="105r" xml:id="page-surface-211">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9140px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00211" width="6725px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="105v" xml:id="page-surface-212">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9096px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00212" width="6471px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="106r" xml:id="page-surface-213">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9183px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00213" width="6945px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="106v" xml:id="page-surface-214">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9096px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00214" width="6471px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="107r" xml:id="page-surface-215">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9183px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00215" width="6755px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="107v" xml:id="page-surface-216">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9096px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00216" width="6471px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="108r" xml:id="page-surface-217">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9183px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00217" width="6755px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="108v" xml:id="page-surface-218">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9138px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00218" width="6471px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="109r" xml:id="page-surface-219">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9183px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00219" width="6755px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="109v" xml:id="page-surface-220">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9094px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00220" width="6471px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="110r" xml:id="page-surface-221">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9183px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00221" width="6592px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="110v" xml:id="page-surface-222">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9094px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00222" width="6471px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="111r" xml:id="page-surface-223">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9183px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00223" width="6592px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="111v" xml:id="page-surface-224">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9094px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00224" width="6543px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="112r" xml:id="page-surface-225">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9183px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00225" width="6592px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="112v" xml:id="page-surface-226">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9094px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00226" width="6543px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="113r" xml:id="page-surface-227">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9183px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00227" width="6592px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="113v" xml:id="page-surface-228">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9094px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00228" width="6543px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="114r" xml:id="page-surface-229">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9094px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00229" width="6458px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="114v" xml:id="page-surface-230">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9094px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00230" width="6271px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="115r" xml:id="page-surface-231">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9183px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00231" width="6592px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="115v" xml:id="page-surface-232">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9094px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00232" width="6271px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="116r" xml:id="page-surface-233">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9183px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00233" width="6592px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="116v" xml:id="page-surface-234">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9094px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00234" width="6271px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="117r" xml:id="page-surface-235">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9183px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00235" width="6682px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="117v" xml:id="page-surface-236">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9094px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00236" width="6498px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="118r" xml:id="page-surface-237">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9085px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00237" width="6716px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="118v" xml:id="page-surface-238">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9094px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00238" width="6670px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="119r" xml:id="page-surface-239">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9183px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00239" width="6682px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="119v" xml:id="page-surface-240">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9094px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00240" width="6670px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="120r" xml:id="page-surface-241">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9116px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00241" width="6589px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="120v" xml:id="page-surface-242">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9094px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00242" width="6670px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="121r" xml:id="page-surface-243">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9116px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00243" width="6589px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="121v" xml:id="page-surface-244">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9094px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00244" width="6459px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="122r" xml:id="page-surface-245">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9116px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00245" width="6589px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="122v" xml:id="page-surface-246">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9094px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00246" width="6459px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="123r" xml:id="page-surface-247">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9012px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00247" width="6589px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="123v" xml:id="page-surface-248">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9012px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00248" width="6287px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="124r" xml:id="page-surface-249">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9012px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00249" width="6443px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="124v" xml:id="page-surface-250">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9012px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00250" width="6287px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="125r" xml:id="page-surface-251">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9012px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00251" width="6443px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="125v" xml:id="page-surface-252">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8860px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00252" width="6148px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="126r" xml:id="page-surface-253">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9012px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00253" width="6443px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="126v" xml:id="page-surface-254">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8860px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00254" width="6148px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="127r" xml:id="page-surface-255">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8857px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00255" width="6443px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="127v" xml:id="page-surface-256">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8860px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00256" width="6148px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="128r" xml:id="page-surface-257">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8857px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00257" width="6443px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="128v" xml:id="page-surface-258">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8860px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00258" width="6196px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="129r" xml:id="page-surface-259">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8857px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00259" width="6532px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="129v" xml:id="page-surface-260">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8860px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00260" width="6338px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="130r" xml:id="page-surface-261">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8946px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00261" width="6532px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="130v" xml:id="page-surface-262">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8946px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00262" width="6355px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="131r" xml:id="page-surface-263">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8900px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00263" width="6532px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="131v" xml:id="page-surface-264">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8900px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00264" width="6394px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="132r" xml:id="page-surface-265">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8829px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00265" width="6491px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="132v" xml:id="page-surface-266">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8900px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00266" width="6394px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="133r" xml:id="page-surface-267">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8743px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00267" width="6491px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="133v" xml:id="page-surface-268">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8803px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00268" width="6394px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="134r" xml:id="page-surface-269">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8829px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00269" width="6658px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="134v" xml:id="page-surface-270">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8829px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00270" width="6518px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="135r" xml:id="page-surface-271">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8657px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00271" width="6658px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="135v" xml:id="page-surface-272">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8657px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00272" width="6658px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="136r" xml:id="page-surface-273">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8657px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00273" width="6658px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="136v" xml:id="page-surface-274">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8657px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00274" width="6658px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="137r" xml:id="page-surface-275">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8753px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00275" width="6658px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="137v" xml:id="page-surface-276">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8657px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00276" width="6658px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="138r" xml:id="page-surface-277">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8753px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00277" width="6658px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="138v" xml:id="page-surface-278">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8657px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00278" width="6658px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="139r" xml:id="page-surface-279">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8753px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00279" width="6658px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="139v" xml:id="page-surface-280">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8657px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00280" width="6658px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="140r" xml:id="page-surface-281">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8886px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00281" width="6658px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="140v" xml:id="page-surface-282">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8657px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00282" width="6623px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="141r" xml:id="page-surface-283">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8753px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00283" width="6658px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="141v" xml:id="page-surface-284">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8657px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00284" width="6623px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="rear binding lining recto - linen" xml:id="page-surface-285">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9342px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00285" width="7879px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="rear binding lining verso - linen" xml:id="page-surface-286">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9342px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00286" width="7879px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="binding leaf i recto - parchment" xml:id="page-surface-287">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9053px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00287" width="7701px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="binding leaf i verso - paper" xml:id="page-surface-288">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9053px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00288" width="6793px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="binding leaf ii recto - paper" xml:id="page-surface-289">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8502px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00289" width="6152px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="binding leaf ii verso - paper" xml:id="page-surface-290">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8502px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00290" width="6343px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="binding leaf iii recto - paper" xml:id="page-surface-291">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8943px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00291" width="6343px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="outside rear cover - parchment" xml:id="page-surface-292">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8950px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00292" width="7576px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="spine" xml:id="page-surface-293">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8078px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PEMBROKE-COLLEGE-00258-000-00293" width="2967px"/>
        </surface>
    </facsimile>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-1" n="outside front cover - parchment" xml:id="page-pb-1"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-2" n="front binding lining - linen" xml:id="page-pb-2"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-3" n="1r" xml:id="page-pb-3"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-4" n="1v" xml:id="page-pb-4"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-5" n="2r" xml:id="page-pb-5"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-6" n="2v" xml:id="page-pb-6"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-7" n="3r" xml:id="page-pb-7"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-8" n="3v" xml:id="page-pb-8"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-9" n="4r" xml:id="page-pb-9"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-10" n="4v" xml:id="page-pb-10"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-11" n="5r" xml:id="page-pb-11"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-12" n="5v" xml:id="page-pb-12"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-13" n="6r" xml:id="page-pb-13"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-14" n="6v" xml:id="page-pb-14"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-15" n="7r" xml:id="page-pb-15"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-16" n="7v" xml:id="page-pb-16"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-17" n="8r" xml:id="page-pb-17"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-18" n="8v" xml:id="page-pb-18"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-19" n="9r" xml:id="page-pb-19"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-20" n="9v" xml:id="page-pb-20"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-21" n="10r" xml:id="page-pb-21"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-22" n="10v" xml:id="page-pb-22"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-23" n="11r" xml:id="page-pb-23"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-24" n="11v" xml:id="page-pb-24"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-25" n="12r" xml:id="page-pb-25"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-26" n="12v" xml:id="page-pb-26"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-27" n="13r" xml:id="page-pb-27"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-28" n="13v" xml:id="page-pb-28"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-29" n="14r" xml:id="page-pb-29"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-30" n="14v" xml:id="page-pb-30"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-31" n="15r" xml:id="page-pb-31"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-32" n="15v" xml:id="page-pb-32"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-33" n="16r" xml:id="page-pb-33"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-34" n="16v" xml:id="page-pb-34"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-35" n="17r" xml:id="page-pb-35"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-36" n="17v" xml:id="page-pb-36"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-37" n="18r" xml:id="page-pb-37"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-38" n="18v" xml:id="page-pb-38"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-39" n="19r" xml:id="page-pb-39"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-40" n="19v" xml:id="page-pb-40"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-41" n="20r" xml:id="page-pb-41"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-42" n="20v" xml:id="page-pb-42"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-43" n="21r" xml:id="page-pb-43"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-44" n="21v" xml:id="page-pb-44"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-45" n="22r" xml:id="page-pb-45"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-46" n="22v" xml:id="page-pb-46"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-47" n="23r" xml:id="page-pb-47"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-48" n="23v" xml:id="page-pb-48"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-49" n="24r" xml:id="page-pb-49"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-50" n="24v" xml:id="page-pb-50"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-51" n="25r" xml:id="page-pb-51"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-52" n="25v" xml:id="page-pb-52"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-53" n="26r" xml:id="page-pb-53"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-54" n="26v" xml:id="page-pb-54"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-55" n="27r" xml:id="page-pb-55"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-56" n="27v" xml:id="page-pb-56"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-57" n="28r" xml:id="page-pb-57"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-58" n="28v" xml:id="page-pb-58"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-59" n="29r" xml:id="page-pb-59"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-60" n="29v" xml:id="page-pb-60"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-61" n="30r" xml:id="page-pb-61"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-62" n="30v" xml:id="page-pb-62"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-63" n="31r" xml:id="page-pb-63"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-64" n="31v" xml:id="page-pb-64"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-65" n="32r" xml:id="page-pb-65"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-66" n="32v" xml:id="page-pb-66"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-67" n="33r" xml:id="page-pb-67"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-68" n="33v" xml:id="page-pb-68"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-69" n="34r" xml:id="page-pb-69"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-70" n="34v" xml:id="page-pb-70"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-71" n="35r" xml:id="page-pb-71"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-72" n="35v" xml:id="page-pb-72"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-73" n="36r" xml:id="page-pb-73"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-74" n="36v" xml:id="page-pb-74"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-75" n="37r" xml:id="page-pb-75"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-76" n="37v" xml:id="page-pb-76"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-77" n="38r" xml:id="page-pb-77"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-78" n="38v" xml:id="page-pb-78"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-79" n="39r" xml:id="page-pb-79"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-80" n="39v" xml:id="page-pb-80"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-81" n="40r" xml:id="page-pb-81"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-82" n="40v" xml:id="page-pb-82"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-83" n="41r" xml:id="page-pb-83"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-84" n="41v" xml:id="page-pb-84"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-85" n="42r" xml:id="page-pb-85"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-86" n="42v" xml:id="page-pb-86"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-87" n="43r" xml:id="page-pb-87"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-88" n="43v" xml:id="page-pb-88"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-89" n="44r" xml:id="page-pb-89"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-90" n="44v" xml:id="page-pb-90"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-91" n="45r" xml:id="page-pb-91"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-92" n="45v" xml:id="page-pb-92"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-93" n="46r" xml:id="page-pb-93"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-94" n="46v" xml:id="page-pb-94"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-95" n="47r" xml:id="page-pb-95"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-96" n="47v" xml:id="page-pb-96"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-97" n="48r" xml:id="page-pb-97"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-98" n="48v" xml:id="page-pb-98"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-99" n="49r" xml:id="page-pb-99"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-100" n="49v" xml:id="page-pb-100"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-101" n="50r" xml:id="page-pb-101"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-102" n="50v" xml:id="page-pb-102"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-103" n="51r" xml:id="page-pb-103"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-104" n="51v" xml:id="page-pb-104"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-105" n="52r" xml:id="page-pb-105"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-106" n="52v" xml:id="page-pb-106"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-107" n="53r" xml:id="page-pb-107"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-108" n="53v" xml:id="page-pb-108"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-109" n="54r" xml:id="page-pb-109"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-110" n="54v" xml:id="page-pb-110"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-111" n="55r" xml:id="page-pb-111"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-112" n="55v" xml:id="page-pb-112"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-113" n="56r" xml:id="page-pb-113"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-114" n="56v" xml:id="page-pb-114"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-115" n="57r" xml:id="page-pb-115"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-116" n="57v" xml:id="page-pb-116"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-117" n="58r" xml:id="page-pb-117"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-118" n="58v" xml:id="page-pb-118"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-119" n="59r" xml:id="page-pb-119"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-120" n="59v" xml:id="page-pb-120"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-121" n="60r" xml:id="page-pb-121"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-122" n="60v" xml:id="page-pb-122"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-123" n="61r" xml:id="page-pb-123"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-124" n="61v" xml:id="page-pb-124"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-125" n="62r" xml:id="page-pb-125"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-126" n="62v" xml:id="page-pb-126"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-127" n="63r" xml:id="page-pb-127"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-128" n="63v" xml:id="page-pb-128"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-129" n="64r" xml:id="page-pb-129"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-130" n="64v" xml:id="page-pb-130"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-131" n="65r" xml:id="page-pb-131"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-132" n="65v" xml:id="page-pb-132"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-133" n="66r" xml:id="page-pb-133"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-134" n="66v" xml:id="page-pb-134"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-135" n="67r" xml:id="page-pb-135"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-136" n="67v" xml:id="page-pb-136"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-137" n="68r" xml:id="page-pb-137"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-138" n="68v" xml:id="page-pb-138"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-139" n="69r" xml:id="page-pb-139"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-140" n="69v" xml:id="page-pb-140"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-141" n="70r" xml:id="page-pb-141"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-142" n="70v" xml:id="page-pb-142"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-143" n="71r" xml:id="page-pb-143"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-144" n="71v" xml:id="page-pb-144"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-145" n="72r" xml:id="page-pb-145"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-146" n="72v" xml:id="page-pb-146"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-147" n="73r" xml:id="page-pb-147"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-148" n="73v" xml:id="page-pb-148"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-149" n="74r" xml:id="page-pb-149"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-150" n="74v" xml:id="page-pb-150"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-151" n="75r" xml:id="page-pb-151"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-152" n="75v" xml:id="page-pb-152"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-153" n="76r" xml:id="page-pb-153"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-154" n="76v" xml:id="page-pb-154"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-155" n="77r" xml:id="page-pb-155"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-156" n="77v" xml:id="page-pb-156"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-157" n="78r" xml:id="page-pb-157"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-158" n="78v" xml:id="page-pb-158"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-159" n="79r" xml:id="page-pb-159"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-160" n="79v" xml:id="page-pb-160"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-161" n="80r" xml:id="page-pb-161"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-162" n="80v" xml:id="page-pb-162"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-163" n="81r" xml:id="page-pb-163"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-164" n="81v" xml:id="page-pb-164"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-165" n="82r" xml:id="page-pb-165"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-166" n="82v" xml:id="page-pb-166"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-167" n="83r" xml:id="page-pb-167"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-168" n="83v" xml:id="page-pb-168"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-169" n="84r" xml:id="page-pb-169"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-170" n="84v" xml:id="page-pb-170"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-171" n="85r" xml:id="page-pb-171"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-172" n="85v" xml:id="page-pb-172"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-173" n="86r" xml:id="page-pb-173"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-174" n="86v" xml:id="page-pb-174"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-175" n="87r" xml:id="page-pb-175"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-176" n="87v" xml:id="page-pb-176"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-177" n="88r" xml:id="page-pb-177"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-178" n="88v" xml:id="page-pb-178"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-179" n="89r" xml:id="page-pb-179"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-180" n="89v" xml:id="page-pb-180"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-181" n="90r" xml:id="page-pb-181"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-182" n="90v" xml:id="page-pb-182"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-183" n="91r" xml:id="page-pb-183"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-184" n="91v" xml:id="page-pb-184"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-185" n="92r" xml:id="page-pb-185"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-186" n="92v" xml:id="page-pb-186"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-187" n="93r" xml:id="page-pb-187"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-188" n="93v" xml:id="page-pb-188"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-189" n="94r" xml:id="page-pb-189"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-190" n="94v" xml:id="page-pb-190"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-191" n="95r" xml:id="page-pb-191"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-192" n="95v" xml:id="page-pb-192"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-193" n="96r" xml:id="page-pb-193"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-194" n="96v" xml:id="page-pb-194"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-195" n="97r" xml:id="page-pb-195"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-196" n="97v" xml:id="page-pb-196"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-197" n="98r" xml:id="page-pb-197"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-198" n="98v" xml:id="page-pb-198"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-199" n="99r" xml:id="page-pb-199"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-200" n="99v" xml:id="page-pb-200"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-201" n="100r" xml:id="page-pb-201"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-202" n="100v" xml:id="page-pb-202"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-203" n="101r" xml:id="page-pb-203"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-204" n="101v" xml:id="page-pb-204"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-205" n="102r" xml:id="page-pb-205"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-206" n="102v" xml:id="page-pb-206"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-207" n="103r" xml:id="page-pb-207"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-208" n="103v" xml:id="page-pb-208"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-209" n="104r" xml:id="page-pb-209"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-210" n="104v" xml:id="page-pb-210"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-211" n="105r" xml:id="page-pb-211"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-212" n="105v" xml:id="page-pb-212"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-213" n="106r" xml:id="page-pb-213"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-214" n="106v" xml:id="page-pb-214"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-215" n="107r" xml:id="page-pb-215"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-216" n="107v" xml:id="page-pb-216"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-217" n="108r" xml:id="page-pb-217"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-218" n="108v" xml:id="page-pb-218"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-219" n="109r" xml:id="page-pb-219"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-220" n="109v" xml:id="page-pb-220"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-221" n="110r" xml:id="page-pb-221"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-222" n="110v" xml:id="page-pb-222"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-223" n="111r" xml:id="page-pb-223"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-224" n="111v" xml:id="page-pb-224"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-225" n="112r" xml:id="page-pb-225"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-226" n="112v" xml:id="page-pb-226"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-227" n="113r" xml:id="page-pb-227"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-228" n="113v" xml:id="page-pb-228"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-229" n="114r" xml:id="page-pb-229"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-230" n="114v" xml:id="page-pb-230"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-231" n="115r" xml:id="page-pb-231"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-232" n="115v" xml:id="page-pb-232"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-233" n="116r" xml:id="page-pb-233"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-234" n="116v" xml:id="page-pb-234"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-235" n="117r" xml:id="page-pb-235"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-236" n="117v" xml:id="page-pb-236"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-237" n="118r" xml:id="page-pb-237"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-238" n="118v" xml:id="page-pb-238"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-239" n="119r" xml:id="page-pb-239"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-240" n="119v" xml:id="page-pb-240"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-241" n="120r" xml:id="page-pb-241"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-242" n="120v" xml:id="page-pb-242"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-243" n="121r" xml:id="page-pb-243"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-244" n="121v" xml:id="page-pb-244"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-245" n="122r" xml:id="page-pb-245"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-246" n="122v" xml:id="page-pb-246"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-247" n="123r" xml:id="page-pb-247"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-248" n="123v" xml:id="page-pb-248"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-249" n="124r" xml:id="page-pb-249"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-250" n="124v" xml:id="page-pb-250"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-251" n="125r" xml:id="page-pb-251"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-252" n="125v" xml:id="page-pb-252"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-253" n="126r" xml:id="page-pb-253"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-254" n="126v" xml:id="page-pb-254"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-255" n="127r" xml:id="page-pb-255"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-256" n="127v" xml:id="page-pb-256"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-257" n="128r" xml:id="page-pb-257"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-258" n="128v" xml:id="page-pb-258"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-259" n="129r" xml:id="page-pb-259"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-260" n="129v" xml:id="page-pb-260"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-261" n="130r" xml:id="page-pb-261"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-262" n="130v" xml:id="page-pb-262"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-263" n="131r" xml:id="page-pb-263"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-264" n="131v" xml:id="page-pb-264"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-265" n="132r" xml:id="page-pb-265"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-266" n="132v" xml:id="page-pb-266"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-267" n="133r" xml:id="page-pb-267"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-268" n="133v" xml:id="page-pb-268"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-269" n="134r" xml:id="page-pb-269"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-270" n="134v" xml:id="page-pb-270"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-271" n="135r" xml:id="page-pb-271"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-272" n="135v" xml:id="page-pb-272"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-273" n="136r" xml:id="page-pb-273"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-274" n="136v" xml:id="page-pb-274"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-275" n="137r" xml:id="page-pb-275"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-276" n="137v" xml:id="page-pb-276"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-277" n="138r" xml:id="page-pb-277"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-278" n="138v" xml:id="page-pb-278"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-279" n="139r" xml:id="page-pb-279"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-280" n="139v" xml:id="page-pb-280"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-281" n="140r" xml:id="page-pb-281"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-282" n="140v" xml:id="page-pb-282"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-283" n="141r" xml:id="page-pb-283"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-284" n="141v" xml:id="page-pb-284"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-285" n="rear binding lining recto - linen" xml:id="page-pb-285"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-286" n="rear binding lining verso - linen" xml:id="page-pb-286"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-287" n="binding leaf i recto - parchment" xml:id="page-pb-287"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-288" n="binding leaf i verso - paper" xml:id="page-pb-288"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-289" n="binding leaf ii recto - paper" xml:id="page-pb-289"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-290" n="binding leaf ii verso - paper" xml:id="page-pb-290"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-291" n="binding leaf iii recto - paper" xml:id="page-pb-291"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-292" n="outside rear cover - parchment" xml:id="page-pb-292"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-293" n="spine" xml:id="page-pb-293"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
