<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/msDesc/consolidated-tei-schema/master/msdesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/msDesc/consolidated-tei-schema/master/msdesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="manuscript_1">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Cambridge, Fitzwilliam Museum, MS McClean 89</title>
                <funder>Wellcome</funder>
                <principal>James Freeman</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Cambridge University Library</publisher>

                <availability default="false" status="restricted" xml:id="displayImageRights">
                    <p part="N">Zooming image © Cambridge University Library, All rights reserved.</p>
                </availability>
                <availability default="false" status="restricted" xml:id="downloadImageRights">
                    <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/">Images made available for download are licensed under a Creative
                        Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 3.0 Unported License (CC BY-NC 3.0)</licence>
                </availability>
                <availability default="false" status="restricted" xml:id="metadataRights">
                    <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/">This metadata is licensed under a Creative Commons
                        Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivs 3.0 Unported License.</licence>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <msDesc status="draft" xml:id="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MUSEUM-MCCLEAN-00089" xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">

                    <msIdentifier>
                        <institution>Fitzwilliam Museum, Cambridge</institution>
                        <repository>Fitzwilliam Museum Collection</repository>
                        <collection>Manuscripts</collection>
                        <idno type="shelfmark">Cambridge, Fitzwilliam Museum, MS McClean 89</idno>
                    </msIdentifier>

                    <head>Book of Hours</head>

                    <msContents>

                        <summary>
                            <seg type="para">Cambridge, Fitzwilliam Museum, MS McClean 89 (hereafter MS McClean 89) is a Book of Hours made in
                                Flanders in the late 15th century for the English market. The manuscript was in England by 1515 at the latest, since
                                several generations of the Skipwith family of South Ormsby in Lincolnshire added birth records to the calendar (ff.
                                    <locus from="27r" to="32v">27r-32v</locus>) and to some of the endleaves (ff. <locus from="128r" to="129v"
                                    >128r-129v</locus>). The Skipwith family were minor gentry, and several members of the family were involved in
                                local and national politics and also married into socially powerful families. </seg>
                            <seg type="para">The birth records in MS McClean 89 are worth close examination, not only as a primary source of new
                                biographical information about several socially and politically important figures in England in the 16th and 17th
                                centuries, but also because the records allow us to trace the transfer of the volume from one generation to another
                                through four generations of the Skipwith family. In addition, the birth records are especially important as a way to
                                highlight the family of Lyon (also known as Leo, Lionel) Skipwith, eldest son of the marriage between Sir William
                                Skipwith and Alice Dymoke, whose children seem to have been erroneously attributed to his younger brother Henry
                                Skipwith in many accounts of the family history (more information below).</seg>
                            <seg type="para">The first member of the Skipwith family to use MS McClean 89 was <name key="person_" role="fmo scr">
                                    <persName type="display">Sir William Skipwith (b. ?1488, d. 1547)</persName>
                                    <persName type="standard">Sir William Skipwith, b. ?1488, d. 1547</persName>
                                </name>, High Sheriff of Lincolnshire 1526-1527, MP for Lincolnshire in 1529 and 1539 (see <ref
                                    target="https://www.historyofparliamentonline.org/volume/1509-1558/member/skipwith-william-1487-1547">History of
                                    Parliament entry</ref> for further details), and son of Sir John Skipwith (d. ?1518), High Sheriff of Lincolnshire
                                1493 and Katherine Skipwith (née Fitzwilliam). Sir William was married twice, first to Elizabeth Tyrwhitt, by whom he
                                had one son, also named William (born c. 1510) (for whom also see <ref
                                    target="https://www.historyofparliamentonline.org/volume/1509-1558/member/skipwith-sir-william-1510-86">History of
                                    Parliament entry</ref>) before Elizabeth's death in or before the year 1514. Sir William then married Alice
                                Dymoke, daughter of Sir Lionel Dymoke; the date is not recorded, but the marriage probably took place in or before
                                mid-1514, since William recorded the births of his children with Alice Dymoke in MS McClean 89, beginning with Marie
                                (Mary), who was born 15 March 1515. Records by a number of hands record the births of a further twelve of his children
                                in the manuscript's calendar pages, summarised as follows in chronological order (for full transcriptions and
                                interpretations, see Additions): <list>
                                    <item>Marie (Mary), born 15 March 1515</item>
                                    <item>Jane, born 26 October 1516</item>
                                    <item>Lyon (also known as Leo and Lionel), born 3 December 1517</item>
                                    <item>Anna, born 30 March 1518</item>
                                    <item>John and Margaret, born 11 June 1519</item>
                                    <item>Brigida (Bridget), born 2 February 1521</item>
                                    <item>Katryn (Katheryn, Katherine), born 6 December 1523</item>
                                    <item>Elisabeth (Elizabeth), born 20 January 1524</item>
                                    <item>George, born 12 December 1526</item>
                                    <item>Dorothea, born 6 February 1527</item>
                                    <item>George, born 30 November 1529</item>
                                    <item>Henry, born 1 September 1532</item>
                                </list></seg>
                            <seg type="para">There are a number of unresolved complexities in this list of births. In three instances, it appears that
                                births occur too close together for Alice Dymoke to be the mother of both children: Lyon on 3 December 1517 and Anna
                                on 30 March 1518; Katryn on 6 December 1523 and Elisabeth on 20 January 1524; and George on 12 December 1526 and
                                Dorothea on 6 February 1527. The manner in which the dates are recorded in the manuscript varies: by regnal years,
                                calendar years, or some combination thereof. There were also at this time differing practices in reckoning the start
                                of the year: the calendar/Christian year began on 1 January, but the legal year on 25 March. The impossibly short gap
                                between the births of Katryn and Elisabeth, and between George and Dorothea, might be explained by confusion arising
                                from these different systems, if Katryn were born on 6 December 1522 not 1523, and if George were born on 6 February
                                1528, not 1527. However, no such resolution is possible for Lyon and Anna, since their birth dates are too closely
                                pre- and post-dated by their siblings Jane and twins John and Margaret. One possibility is that some of these children
                                were born out of wedlock to another mother, though the naming of Lyon (presumably in honour of his maternal
                                grandfather) and the descent of the manuscript to him suggests that he was legitimate (further details below). A
                                further question hangs over the two children named George; perhaps the first died in infancy. Further research is
                                needed to place all of these observations on firmer evidential ground. </seg>
                            <seg type="para">It is notable that the birth of Sir William's first child (William, b. ?1510), by his first wife
                                Elizabeth, is not recorded here. Furthermore, the book passed not to this William, but to the oldest son, Lyon (b.
                                1517), of Sir William's second marriage to Alice. This suggests the possibility that MS McClean 89 came into the
                                Skipwith family via Alice herself, and who wished it to remain in her side of the family. Lyon was married twice,
                                first to Margaret Barnardiston, daughter of John Barnardiston, and second to Jane Bracebridge, daughter of William
                                Bracebridge. The births of seven of his children were recorded in MS McClean 89, all in the same hand, which might
                                indicate that Lyon added the entries himself. The children of Lyon Skipwith as recorded in MS McClean 89 are as
                                follows: <list>
                                    <item>Katheryne (Katherine), born 10 July 1555</item>
                                    <item>Margaret, born 8 March 1561 (or 1562)</item>
                                    <item>Elizabeth, born 15 February 1562</item>
                                    <item>Ursula, born 30 May 1563</item>
                                    <item>William, born 12 September 1566</item>
                                    <item>George, born 4 November 1567</item>
                                    <item>John, born 9 March 1573</item>
                                </list></seg>
                            <seg type="para">Lyon Skipwith has not left a substantial trace in the historical record, and as a result some sources
                                appear to conflate details of his life with those of his youngest brother, Henry (b. 1 September 1532). For instance,
                                in <hi rend="italic">Burke's Peerage, Knightage and Baronetage</hi> ((2003), III.3641), Henry is said to have had
                                twelve children (William, Francis, Henry, George, Ursula, Catherine, Anne, Jane, Bridget, Dorothy, Elizabeth,
                                Margaret), but the records added to MS McClean 89 indicate that some of these are Lyon's children. Further suggestive
                                evidence is provided by the descent of the manuscript, which passed to William (b. 1566), since it is more likely that
                                he inherited it as Lyon's son, rather than as his nephew. </seg>
                            <seg type="para"><name key="person_" role="fmo scr">
                                    <persName type="display">William Skipwith (b. 1566, d. 1610)</persName>
                                    <persName type="standard">William Skipwith, 1566-1610</persName>
                                </name> was Sheriff of Leicestershire c. 1598, and MP for Leicestershire in 1601 and for Leicester in 1604 (see <ref
                                    target="https://www.historyofparliamentonline.org/volume/1604-1629/member/skipwith-sir-william-1564-1610">History
                                    of Parliament entry</ref>). He was knighted in 1603 and was married twice, first to Margaret Cave and second to
                                Jane Roberts, the daughter of John Roberts of Wollaston. Like his antecedents, he recorded the births of six children
                                on ff. <locus from="128r" to="128v">128r-128v</locus>, as follows: <list>
                                    <item>Jane, born 3 November 1587</item>
                                    <item>Anne, born 23 January 1588</item>
                                    <item>Henry, born 21 March 1590</item>
                                    <item>George, born 12 February 1591</item>
                                    <item>Elizabeth, born 11 February 1592</item>
                                    <item>Thomas, born 6 August 1594</item>
                                </list>
                            </seg>
                            <seg type="para">MS McClean 89 passed to William's eldest male child, <name key="person_" role="fmo scr">
                                    <persName type="display">Henry Skipwith (b. 1590)</persName>
                                    <persName type="standard">Henry Skipwith, b. 1590</persName>
                                </name>. Henry was knighted in 1609 and was married twice, first to Anne Kempe, daughter of Sir Thomas Kempe and
                                second to Blandina Pennen, daughter of John Pennen of Badgeworth, Somerset. He too recorded the births of seven
                                children on ff. <locus from="129r" to="129v">129r-129v</locus>, as follows: <list>
                                    <item>William, born 25 February 1613</item>
                                    <item>Henry, born 16 December 1615</item>
                                    <item>Elizabeth, born 6 October 1617</item>
                                    <item>Thomas, born 30 March 1618</item>
                                    <item>Diana, born 27 May 1621</item>
                                    <item>Graye, born 23 January 1622</item>
                                    <item>Anne, born 23 February 1623</item>
                                </list>
                            </seg>
                            <seg type="para">There are no further Skipwith births recorded in MS McClean 89 after this last entry, and the subsequent
                                ownership of the manuscript is unknown.</seg>
                            <seg type="para">As well as the natal records, the manuscript also includes a recipe for a 'Soverign water' also known as
                                'Dr Stephen's water' on ff. <locus from="130v" to="132v">130v-132v</locus>, a panacea medicine supposedly created by a
                                'Physician Steven' as he is so named in MS McClean 89. The recipe for a 'Soverign water' was said to cure eye
                                problems, most common ailments and was said to extend life, and was a popular recipe in 16th- and 17th-century
                                England; versions of the recipe are found in several other manuscripts and printed books, sometimes with additional
                                information about 'Steven', who apparently lived into his 90s thanks to the powers of his concoction. His identity is
                                otherwise unknown, and the version of the recipe in MS McClean 89 lacks some of the purported biographical information
                                found in other sources. </seg>
                            <seg type="para">Dr Sarah Gilbert<lb/> Project Cataloguer for the Curious Cures Project<lb/> Cambridge University
                                Library</seg>
                        </summary>

                        <textLang mainLang="la" otherLangs="enm">Latin with Middle English</textLang>

                        <msItem n="1">
                            <locus from="2r" to="3r">2r-3r</locus>
                            <title key="">Prayer of Suffrage to the Trinity</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="2r" to="2r">2r</locus> Memoria de sancta trinitate . de uota . oracio </rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="2r" to="2r">2r</locus> Domine deus omnipotens pater et filius et spirits sanctus : da michi famulo tuo et
                                uictoriam contra omnes inimicos meos </incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="3r" to="3r">3r</locus> Qui uiuis et regnas cum deo patre in unitate spiritus sancti deus per omnia secula
                                seculorum </explicit>
                            <finalRubric>
                                <locus from="3r" to="3r">3r</locus> amen </finalRubric>
                            <note>Full page miniature of the Trinity (God the Father holding the crucified Jesus, dove above) on f. <locus from="1v"
                                    to="1v">1v</locus> preceding the text. See Decoration for further information.</note>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="2">
                            <locus from="4r" to="8v">4r-8v</locus>
                            <title key="">Fifteen Oos (Prayers of Saint Bridget)</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="4r" to="4r">4r</locus> Deuota oracio ad dominum ihesum christum </rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="4r" to="4r">4r</locus> O domine ihesu christe eterna dulcedo te amancium et iubilus excedens omne gaudium
                                et omne desiderium salus et amator peccatorum confitencium </incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="8v" to="8v">8v</locus> ita laudabilis ut post huius uite terminum te <sic>laure</sic> merear cum omnibus
                                sanctis tuis ineternum </explicit>
                            <finalRubric>
                                <locus from="8v" to="8v">8v</locus> amen </finalRubric>
                            <note><p>Full page miniature of the crucifixion on f. <locus from="3v" to="3v">3v</locus> preceding the text. See
                                    Decoration for further information. </p></note>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="3">
                            <locus from="10r" to="11v">10r-11v</locus>
                            <title>Prayer on the Seven Final Words of Jesus (De septem uerbis christi)</title>
                            <author key="person_v61539765">Bede</author>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="10r" to="10r">10r</locus> Oracio uenerabilis ualde bede presbitri de septem uerbis christi in cruce
                                pendentis quam oracionem quicunque cotidie deuote dixerit flexis genuibus . nec dyabolus nec malus homo ei nocere
                                poterit nec sine confessione morietur et per triginta dies ante abitium suum uidebit gloriosam uirginem mariam in
                                auxilium sibi preparatam . Oracio</rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="10r" to="10r">10r</locus> Domine ihesu christe qui septem verba die ultimo vite tue in cruce pendens
                                dixisti</incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="11v" to="11v">11v</locus> et sanctum finem necnon gloriosam beatamque resurrectionem propter magnaminiam
                                tuam michi tribuere digneris </explicit>
                            <finalRubric>
                                <locus from="11v" to="11v">11v</locus> amen </finalRubric>
                            <note><p>Full page miniature of a pope on f. <locus from="9v" to="9v">9v</locus>. See Decoration for further information.
                                </p>
                            </note>
                            <listBibl>
                                <bibl>Leroquais (1927-43), 2:342</bibl>
                            </listBibl>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="4">
                            <locus from="12r" to="12v">12rv</locus>
                            <title key="">Three prayers</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <msItem n="4.1">
                                <locus from="12r" to="12r">12r</locus>
                                <title key="">Prayer to the Confessors at the elevation of the eucharist</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <rubric>
                                    <locus from="12r" to="12r">12r</locus> Omnibus confessis et contritis hanc oracionem dicentibus inter eleuacionem
                                    corpis <sic>xpristi</sic> . et tercium agnus dei papa bonifacius concessit .ij.<hi rend="superscript">m</hi>
                                    annorum indulgenciarum ad supplicacionem philippi regis francie </rubric>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="12r" to="12r">12r</locus> Domine ihesu chiste ; qui hanc sacratissimam carnem et precciosissimum
                                    sanguinem tuum </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="12r" to="12r">12r</locus> et ab uniuersis malis periculis presentibus preteritis et futuris </explicit>
                                <finalRubric>
                                    <locus from="12r" to="12r">12r</locus> amen </finalRubric>
                            </msItem>
                            <msItem n="4.2">
                                <locus from="12r" to="12v">12r-12v</locus>
                                <title key="">Prayer to the eucharistic sacrament</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <rubric>
                                    <locus from="12r" to="12r">12r</locus> alia deuotissima oracio ad sacramentum </rubric>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="12v" to="12v">12v</locus> Anima <sic>xpristi</sic> sanctifica me </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="12v" to="12v">12v</locus> Ut cum angelis laudem te . In secula seculorum </explicit>
                                <finalRubric>
                                    <locus from="12v" to="12v">12v</locus> amen </finalRubric>
                            </msItem>
                            <msItem n="4.3">
                                <locus from="12v" to="12v">12v</locus>
                                <title key="">Prayer to the eucharistic sacrament</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <rubric>
                                    <locus from="12v" to="12v">12v</locus> deuota oracio ad sacramentum </rubric>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="12v" to="12v">12v</locus> Aue uerum corpus <sic>xpristi</sic> natum de maria uirgine </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="12v" to="12v">12v</locus> O dulcis . o pie . o ihesu fili marie misere mei </explicit>
                                <finalRubric>
                                    <locus from="12v" to="12v">12v</locus> amen </finalRubric>
                            </msItem>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="5">
                            <locus from="13r" to="13v">13rv</locus>
                            <title key="">Suffrage to Saint John the Baptist with prayers, versicle, response, and collect</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="13r" to="13r">13r</locus> Memoria de sancto iohanne baptista </rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="13r" to="13r">13r</locus> Gaude iohannes baptista . Qui in uentus clausus cista con gaudebas domino </incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="13v" to="13v">13v</locus> et ad luce in celestis gaudij perducat per <sic>xpristum</sic> dominum nostrum </explicit>
                            <finalRubric>
                                <locus from="13v" to="13v">13v</locus> amen </finalRubric>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="6">
                            <locus from="14r" to="14v">14rv</locus>
                            <title key="">Suffrage to Saint George with prayers, versicle, response, and collect</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="14r" to="14r">14r</locus> Sequitur memoria de sancto Georgio martire </rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="14r" to="14r">14r</locus> Georgi marti inclite te decet laus et gloria predotatum milicia </incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="14v" to="14v">14v</locus> et inuisibiles ne nocere nobis ualeant precedere digneris per
                                    <sic>xpristum</sic> dominum nostrum </explicit>
                            <finalRubric>
                                <locus from="14v" to="14v">14v</locus> amen </finalRubric>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="7">
                            <locus from="15r" to="15v">15rv</locus>
                            <title key="">Suffrage to Saint Christopher with prayers, versicle, response, and collect</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="15r" to="15r">15r</locus> Memoria de sancto <sic>xpristo</sic>foro martire . ant . </rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="15r" to="15r">15r</locus> O Sancte <sic>xpristofore</sic> martir ihesu xpristi . Qui pro eius nomine
                                penas pertulisti <sic>opem</sic> confer miseris atque mundo tristi </incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="15v" to="15v">15v</locus> Qui uiuit et regnas decus per omnia secula seculorum </explicit>
                            <finalRubric>
                                <locus from="15v" to="15v">15v</locus> amen </finalRubric>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="8">
                            <locus from="16r" to="16r">16r</locus>
                            <title key="">Suffrage to Saint Anthony with antiphon, versicle, reponse and collect </title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="16r" to="16r">16r</locus> Memoria de sancto anthonio . Antiphana </rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="16r" to="16r">16r</locus> O Sanctissime pater Anthonij . qui demonum multitudinem et eorum ignem </incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="16r" to="16r">16r</locus> et corpore integros prestante per <sic>xpristum</sic> dominum nostrum </explicit>
                            <finalRubric>
                                <locus from="16r" to="16r">16r</locus> amen </finalRubric>
                            <note><p>Folio <locus from="16v" to="16v">16v</locus> blank.</p></note>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="9">
                            <locus from="17r" to="17r">17r</locus>
                            <title key="">Suffrage to Saint Erasmus with antiphon, versicle, response, and collect</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="17r" to="17r">17r</locus> Memoria de sancto Erasmo . martire . ant </rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="17r" to="17r">17r</locus> O Sancte erasme suscipe me in tuam sanctam fidem conserua me ab omni malo isto
                                die </incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="17r" to="17r">17r</locus> et omnia michi prospera concedas . Per christum dominum nostrum </explicit>
                            <finalRubric>
                                <locus from="17r" to="17r">17r</locus> amen </finalRubric>
                            <note><p>Folio <locus from="17v" to="17v">17v</locus> blank.</p></note>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="10">
                            <locus from="18r" to="18r">18r</locus>
                            <title key="">Suffrage to Saint Nicholas with antiphon, versicle, reponse, and collect</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="18r" to="18r">18r</locus> Excellentissima oracio de sancto nicholao </rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="18r" to="18r">18r</locus> O pastor eterne o clemens et bone custos qui dum deuoti gregis preces
                                attenderes uoce lapsa de celo presuli sanctissimo dignum episcopatum nicolaum </incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="18r" to="18r">18r</locus> et precibus a gehenne incendijs liberentur . Per <sic>xpristum</sic> dominum
                                nostrum </explicit>
                            <finalRubric>
                                <locus from="18r" to="18r">18r</locus> amen </finalRubric>
                            <note><p>Folio <locus from="18v" to="18v">18v</locus> blank.</p></note>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="11">
                            <locus from="19r" to="19r">19r</locus>
                            <title key="">Suffrage to Saint Giles (Egidus) with antiphons, versicle, response, and collect</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="19r" to="19r">19r</locus> Sequitur memoria de sancto egidio confessor </rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="19r" to="19r">18r</locus> Laus <sic>in mensa</sic> dei pro festiuitate diei in qua grecorum flos scandit
                                ad alta polorum inclitus egidius </incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="18r" to="18r">18r</locus> et tribue maiestatem tuam pro nobis iugiter exoret . Per <sic>xpristum</sic>
                                dominum nostrum </explicit>
                            <finalRubric>
                                <locus from="18r" to="18r">18r</locus> amen </finalRubric>
                            <note><p>Folio <locus from="19v" to="19v">19v</locus> blank.</p></note>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="12">
                            <locus from="20r" to="20v">20rv</locus>
                            <title key="">Suffrage to Saint Katherine (Catherine) with prayers, versicle, response, and collect</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="20r" to="20r">20r</locus> Sequitur memoria de sancta katherina psa </rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="20r" to="20r">20r</locus> Gaude uirgo katherina per quam doctores lex diuina traxit ab erroribus </incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="20v" to="20v">20v</locus> et intercessione ad montem qui <sic>xpristus</sic> est ualeamus peruenire . Per
                                    <sic>xpristum</sic> dominum nostrum </explicit>
                            <finalRubric>
                                <locus from="20v" to="20v">20v</locus> amen </finalRubric>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="13">
                            <locus from="21r" to="21v">21rv</locus>
                            <title key="">Suffrage to Saint Margaret with prayers, versicle, response, and collect</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="21r" to="21r">21r</locus> Sequitur memoria de sancta margareta </rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="21r" to="21r">21r</locus> Gaude uirgo margareta que nutricis gregem leta minabas ad pascua </incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="21v" to="21v">21v</locus> tue ex quacunque necessitate almiflua coNsolacionis tue beneficia consequamur .
                                Per <sic>xpristum</sic> dominum nostrum </explicit>
                            <finalRubric>
                                <locus from="21v" to="21v">21v</locus> amen </finalRubric>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="14">
                            <locus from="22r" to="22v">22rv</locus>
                            <title key="">Suffrage to Saint Barbara with prayers, versicle, response, and collect</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="22r" to="22r">22r</locus> Sequitur memoria de sancta barbara </rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="22r" to="22r">22r</locus> Gaude barbara regina . Summa pollens in doctrina angeli misterio </incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="22v" to="22v">22v</locus> quas omnibus a te promeruit specialiter imepetrare . Per <sic>xpristum</sic>
                                dominum nostrum </explicit>
                            <finalRubric>
                                <locus from="22v" to="22v">22v</locus> amen </finalRubric>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="15">
                            <locus from="23r" to="23v">23rv</locus>
                            <title key="">Suffrage to Saint Mary Magdalen with prayers, versicle, response, and collect</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="23r" to="23r">23r</locus> Memoria de sancta maria magdalena </rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="23r" to="23r">23r</locus> Gaude pia magfalena spes salutis uite uena lapsorum fiducia </incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="23v" to="23v">23v</locus> et in omnibus peticionibus propiciacionis tue clemenciam senciamus. Per
                                    <sic>xpristum</sic> dominum nostrum </explicit>
                            <finalRubric>
                                <locus from="23v" to="23v">23v</locus> amen </finalRubric>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="16">
                            <locus from="24r" to="24v">24rv</locus>
                            <title key="">Suffrage to Saint Ursula with antiphons, versicles, responses, and collect</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="24r" to="24r">24r</locus> Memoria de sancta ursula antiphana </rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="24r" to="24r">24r</locus> UIrginum undena nulia uicerunt flammas fornacis babilonis inde omnia benedicunt
                                dominum </incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="24v" to="24v">24v</locus> Vt qui eis morum qualitate sumus discimiles eandem intercedente passione in
                                celesti palacio sanctorum tuorum mereamur fieri consortes . Per <sic>xpristum</sic> dominum nostrum </explicit>
                            <finalRubric>
                                <locus from="24v" to="24v">24v</locus> amen </finalRubric>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="17">
                            <locus from="25r" to="25v">25rv</locus>
                            <title key="">Suffrage to Saint Anna (Anne) with prayers, versicle, response, and collect</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="25r" to="25r">25r</locus> Commemoracio de sancta anna Prosa </rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="25r" to="25r">25r</locus> Gaude felix anna que concepisti prolem ; que erat paritura <sic>xpristum</sic>
                                saluatorem </incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="25v" to="25v">25v</locus> et presentis uite salutem conferas et ad gaudia celorum perducas . Per
                                    <sic>xpristum</sic> dominum nostrum </explicit>
                            <finalRubric>
                                <locus from="24v" to="24v">24v</locus> amen </finalRubric>
                            <note><p>Folios <locus from="26r" to="26v">26rv</locus> blank. </p></note>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="18">
                            <locus from="27r" to="33v">27r-33v</locus>
                            <title key="">Calendar</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <msItem n="18.1">
                                <locus from="27r" to="27r">27r</locus>
                                <title key="">January</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <note><p>Incorrectly labelled 'februarii' next to the KL monogram; all of the feasts on the leaf are in January.
                                    </p></note>
                            </msItem>
                            <msItem n="18.2">
                                <locus from="27v" to="27v">27v</locus>
                                <title key="">February</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <note><p>Notable feasts:<lb/> 23 February - Milburge uirginis </p></note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>As noted in M.R. James, <hi rend="italic">A descriptive catalogue of the McClean collection of manuscripts
                                            in the Fitzwilliam Museum</hi> (Cambridge, 1912), no. 89</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>
                            <msItem n="18.3">
                                <locus from="28r" to="28r">28r</locus>
                                <title key="">March</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <note><p>Notable feasts:<lb/> 17 March - Gertrudis </p></note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>As noted in M.R. James, <hi rend="italic">A descriptive catalogue of the McClean collection of manuscripts
                                            in the Fitzwilliam Museum</hi> (Cambridge, 1912), no. 89</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>
                            <msItem n="18.4">
                                <locus from="28v" to="28v">28v</locus>
                                <title key="">April</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            </msItem>
                            <msItem n="18.5">
                                <locus from="29r" to="29r">29r</locus>
                                <title key="">May</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <note><p>Notable feasts:<lb/> 2 May - Elyzabeth </p></note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>As noted in M.R. James, <hi rend="italic">A descriptive catalogue of the McClean collection of manuscripts
                                            in the Fitzwilliam Museum</hi> (Cambridge, 1912), no. 89</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>
                            <msItem n="18.6">
                                <locus from="29v" to="29v">29v</locus>
                                <title key="">June</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <note><p>Notable feasts:<lb/> 20 June - Edmundi regis <lb/> 25 June - Eligii Episcopi (in red) </p></note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>As noted in M.R. James, <hi rend="italic">A descriptive catalogue of the McClean collection of manuscripts
                                            in the Fitzwilliam Museum</hi> (Cambridge, 1912), no. 89</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>
                            <msItem n="18.7">
                                <locus from="30r" to="30r">30r</locus>
                                <title key="">July</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <note><p>Notable feasts:<lb/> 2 July - Visitacio Marie (in red)<lb/> 7 July - Translatio Thome (in red, with octave)
                                    </p></note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>As noted in M.R. James, <hi rend="italic">A descriptive catalogue of the McClean collection of manuscripts
                                            in the Fitzwilliam Museum</hi> (Cambridge, 1912), no. 89</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>
                            <msItem n="18.8">
                                <locus from="30v" to="30v">30v</locus>
                                <title key="">August</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            </msItem>
                            <msItem n="18.9">
                                <locus from="31r" to="31r">31r</locus>
                                <title key="">September</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            </msItem>
                            <msItem n="18.10">
                                <locus from="31v" to="31v">31v</locus>
                                <title key="">October</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <note><p>Notable feasts:<lb/> 4 October - Francis <lb/> 6 October - Translatio Hugonis (in red) </p></note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>As noted in M.R. James, <hi rend="italic">A descriptive catalogue of the McClean collection of manuscripts
                                            in the Fitzwilliam Museum</hi> (Cambridge, 1912), no. 89</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>
                            <msItem n="18.11">
                                <locus from="32r" to="32r">32r</locus>
                                <title key="">November</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <note><p>Notable feasts:<lb/> 12 November - Livini Episcopi <lb/> 17 November - Hugonis Episcopi 20 November - Edmundi
                                        Episcopi (red) </p></note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>As noted in M.R. James, <hi rend="italic">A descriptive catalogue of the McClean collection of manuscripts
                                            in the Fitzwilliam Museum</hi> (Cambridge, 1912), no. 89, with additions</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>
                            <msItem n="18.12">
                                <locus from="32v" to="32v">32v</locus>
                                <title key="">December</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <note><p>Notable feasts:<lb/> 1 December - Eligii Episcopi (in red) </p></note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>As noted in M.R. James, <hi rend="italic">A descriptive catalogue of the McClean collection of manuscripts
                                            in the Fitzwilliam Museum</hi> (Cambridge, 1912), no. 89</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>
                            <note><p>M.R. James noted that the commemmorations for Saints David, Chad, and Winifred are not recorded in this calendar. </p>
                                <p>Mnemonic poem for the so-called 'Egyptian Days' recorded in the upper portion of each leaf by the KL monogram, a
                                    line per month as follows:<lb/> Prima dies mensis et septima <sic>trinitat</sic> ut ensis<lb/> Quarta subit mortem
                                    . prosternit tercia sortem <lb/> Primus mandentem . discumpit quarta bibentem <lb/> Denus et undenus . Est mortis
                                    uulnere plenus <lb/> Tercius occidit et septima ora relidit <lb/> Denus pallescit Quindenus feder uescit <lb/>
                                    Tredecimus mactat Julii denus labefactat <lb/> Prima necat sortem . Perditque secunda cohortem <lb/> Tercia
                                    septembris . Et denus fert malatuembris <lb/> Tercius et denus . Est sicut mors alienus <lb/> Scorpius est quintus
                                    . Et tercius est nece cuntus <lb/> Septimus exanguis . Dirosus denus et anguis </p><p>Many 16th century births of
                                    members of the Skipwith family of South Ormsby, Lincolnshire are recorded as additions to this calendar. The birth
                                    records are transcribed in Additions and discussed in Provenance.</p>
                            </note>
                            <listBibl>
                                <bibl>M.R. James, <hi rend="italic">A descriptive catalogue of the McClean collection of manuscripts in the
                                        Fitzwilliam Museum</hi> (Cambridge, 1912), no. 89</bibl>
                            </listBibl>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="19">
                            <locus from="33v" to="64r">33v-64r</locus>
                            <title key="">Hours of the Virgin - Use of Sarum</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="34r" to="34r">34r</locus> Incipiunt hore beate marie uirginis : Secundum usum sarum </rubric>
                            <msItem n="19.1">
                                <locus from="34r" to="38v">34r-38v</locus>
                                <title key="">Hours of the Virgin: Matins</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            </msItem>
                            <msItem n="19.2">
                                <locus from="40r" to="49r">40r-49r</locus>
                                <title key="">Hours of the Virgin: Lauds</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <note><p>Folio <locus from="39r" to="39r">39r</locus> blank.</p></note>
                            </msItem>
                            <msItem n="19.3">
                                <locus from="50r" to="52r">50r-52r</locus>
                                <title key="">Hours of the Virgin: Prime</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            </msItem>
                            <msItem n="19.4">
                                <locus from="53r" to="54r">53r-54r</locus>
                                <title key="">Hours of the Virgin: Terce</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            </msItem>
                            <msItem n="19.5">
                                <locus from="55r" to="54r">55r-56r</locus>
                                <title key="">Hours of the Virgin: Sext</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            </msItem>
                            <msItem n="19.6">
                                <locus from="57r" to="58r">57r-58r</locus>
                                <title key="">Hours of the Virgin: Nones</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            </msItem>
                            <msItem n="19.7">
                                <locus from="57r" to="57r">57r-56r</locus>
                                <title key="">Hours of the Virgin: Vespers</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            </msItem>
                            <msItem n="19.8">
                                <locus from="59r" to="60r">59r-60r</locus>
                                <title key="">Hours of the Virgin: Vespers</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            </msItem>
                            <msItem n="19.9">
                                <locus from="61r" to="64r">61r-64r</locus>
                                <title key="">Hours of the Virgin: Compline</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <note><p>Folio <locus from="64v" to="64v">64v</locus> blank.</p></note>
                            </msItem>
                            <note><p>Full page miniature of the Annunciation on f. <locus from="33v" to="33v">33v</locus>, of the Visitation on f.
                                        <locus from="39v" to="39v">39v</locus>, of the Adoration of the Shepherds on <locus from="49v" to="49v"
                                        >49v</locus>, of the Adoration of the Magi on f. <locus from="52v" to="52v">52v</locus>, of the Flight to
                                    Egypt on f. <locus from="54v" to="54v">54v</locus>, of the Resurrection of Jesus from the Tomb on f. <locus
                                        from="56v" to="56v">56v</locus>, of the Assumption of Mary on f. <locus from="58v" to="58v">58v</locus>, of
                                    the Coronation of Mary in Heaven on f. <locus from="60v" to="60v">60v</locus>. See Decoration for further
                                    information. </p>
                            </note>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="20">
                            <locus from="65r" to="68r">65r-68r</locus>
                            <title key="">Salue Regina and other prayers to Mary</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="65r" to="65r">65r</locus> Has uideas laudes qui sacra uirgine gaudes et uenerando piam studeas
                                    <sic>seruire</sic> mariam uirginis intacta cum ueneris ante figuram pretereundo <sic>cane</sic> ne taceatur aue
                                inuenies ueniam . Sic salutando mariam . Salue . </rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="65r" to="65r">65r</locus> Salue uirgo uirginum stella matutina </incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="68r" to="68r">68r</locus> ut qui uere eam dei genitricem credimu eius apud te intercessionibus adiuuemur
                                . Per <sic>xpristum</sic> dominum nostrum </explicit>
                            <finalRubric>
                                <locus from="68r" to="68r">68r</locus> amen </finalRubric>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="21">
                            <locus from="68v" to="73v">68v-73v</locus>
                            <title key="">Seven Penitential Psalms</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="69r" to="69r">69r</locus> Incipiunt septem psalmi penitenciales psalmus </rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="69r" to="69r">69r</locus> Ne reminiscans Domine </incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="73v" to="73v">73v</locus> Ne reminiscaris domine delicta nostra uel parentum nostrum neque uindictam
                                sumas de peccatis nostris </explicit>
                            <note><p>Full page miniature of Jesus seated in Judgement on f. <locus from="68v" to="68v">68v</locus>. See [Decoration]
                                    for further information. </p></note>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="22">
                            <locus from="73v" to="75r">73v-75r</locus>
                            <title key="">Fifteen Psalms of Degrees</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="73v" to="73v">73v</locus> Incipiunt quindecim psalmi </rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="73v" to="73v">73v</locus> Ad dominum cum tribularet </incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="75r" to="75r">75r</locus> Parce domine parce populo tuo quem redemisti precioso sanguine tuo ne in
                                eternum irasceris nobis </explicit>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="23">
                            <locus from="75r" to="81r">75r-81r</locus>
                            <title key="">Litany with Collect and Prayers</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="75r" to="75r">75r</locus> Letanie </rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="75r" to="75r">75r</locus> Kyrieleison <sic>Xpristeleison</sic> Kyrieleison </incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="81r" to="81r">81r</locus> et defunctis in terra uiuencium uitam et requiem eternam concede Per christum
                                dominum </explicit>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="24">
                            <locus from="81v" to="97r">81v-97r</locus>
                            <title key="">Office for the Dead with Nine Readings, Collects and Prayers</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="82r" to="82r">82r</locus> Incipiunt uigile mortuorum antiphana psalmus dauid </rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="82r" to="82r">82r</locus> Placebo . Dilexi quoniam exaudiet dominus uocem oracionis mee </incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="97r" to="97r">97r</locus> Deus qui nos patrem ut supra oracio<lb/> Fidelium deus omnium ut supra oracio </explicit>
                            <note><p>Full page miniature of a requiem mass on f. <locus from="81v" to="81v">81v</locus>. See Decoration for further
                                    information. </p></note>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="25">
                            <locus from="97v" to="107r">97v-107r</locus>
                            <title key="">Commendationes animarum</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="98r" to="98r">98r</locus> Incipiunt commendaciones animarum </rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="98r" to="98r">98r</locus> Beati immaculati in uia : qui ambulant in lege domini </incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="107r" to="107r">107r</locus> gloria manifeste contemplacionis tuo perpetuo socientur . Per
                                    <sic>xpristum</sic> dominum nostrum </explicit>
                            <finalRubric>
                                <locus from="107r" to="107r">107r</locus> amen </finalRubric>
                            <note><p>Full page miniature of a soul being carried to heaven on f. <locus from="97v" to="97v">97v</locus>. See
                                    Decoration for further information. </p></note>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="26">
                            <locus from="107v" to="111r">111r</locus>
                            <title key="">Psalms for Holy Week</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="108r" to="108r">108r</locus> Incipiunt psalterium de passione domini </rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="108r" to="108r">108r</locus> Deus deus meus respice in inequare me derelinquisti longe a salute mea uerba
                                delictorum meorum </incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="111r" to="111r">111r</locus> In manus tuas domine commendo spiritum meum redemisti me domine deus
                                ueritatis Gloria </explicit>
                            <note><p>Full page miniature of Jesus as the Man of Sorrows with <hi rend="italic">arma christi</hi> on f. <locus
                                        from="107v" to="107v">107v</locus>. See Decoration for further information. </p></note>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="27">
                            <locus from="111v" to="121r">111v-121r</locus>
                            <title key="">Psalterium beati Hieronymi</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="111v" to="111v">111v</locus> Beatus uero iheronimus in hoc modo : psalterium istud deposuit sicut angelus
                                domini docuit cum per spiritum sanctum porro propter hoc abbreuiatum est quod hii qui solicitudinem huius seculi
                                habent </rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="111v" to="111v">111v</locus> Suscipere digneris domine deus omnipotens istos psalmos consecratos quos ego
                                indignus decantare cupio in honore nominis tui domine </incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="121r" to="121r">121r</locus> et requiem eternam concede Per <sic>xpristum</sic> dominum nostrum </explicit>
                            <finalRubric>
                                <locus from="121r" to="121r">121r</locus> amen </finalRubric>
                            <note>
                                <p>Long rubric to prefatory collect on f. <locus from="111v" to="111v">111v</locus>. </p>
                                <p>Full page miniature of Jerome and lion on f. <locus from="112v" to="112v">112v</locus>. See Decoration for further
                                    information. </p>
                                <p>Folio <locus from="113r" to="113r">113r</locus>: Uerba mea auribus</p>
                                <p>Folio <locus from="121v" to="121v">121v</locus> blank. </p>
                            </note>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="28">
                            <locus from="122r" to="125r">122r-125r</locus>
                            <title key="">Prayers to the Virgin Mary</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <note>
                                <p> Folio <locus from="122r" to="122r">122r</locus>: Obsecro te</p>
                                <p> Folio <locus from="124r" to="124r">124r</locus>: O intemerata</p></note>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="29">
                            <locus from="125v" to="128r">128r</locus>
                            <title key="">Memoria de quinque vulneribus with Collects and Prayers</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            <rubric>
                                <locus from="125v" to="125v">125v</locus> Memoria de quinque uuleris Ihesu <sic>xpristi</sic>
                            </rubric>
                            <incipit>
                                <locus from="125v" to="125v">125v</locus> Salue ihesu flagellate totus ruberis sanguine </incipit>
                            <explicit>
                                <locus from="128r" to="128r">128r</locus> Salue crux digna super omnia ligna benigna . Tu me consigna moriar ne morte
                                maligna In nomine patris et filij et spiritus sancti </explicit>
                            <finalRubric>
                                <locus from="128r" to="128r">128r</locus> Amen </finalRubric>
                            <note><p>Full page miniature of the veneration of an altar topped with Jesus as the Man of Sorrows with <hi rend="italic"
                                        >arma christi</hi> on f. <locus from="125v" to="125v">125v</locus></p>
                                <p>Many 16th- and 17th-century century births of members of the Skipwith family of South Ormsby, Lincolnshire are
                                    recorded as additions on ff. <locus from="128r" to="129v">128r-129v</locus>. The birth records are transcribed in
                                    Additions and discussed in Provenance. </p>
                            </note>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="30">
                            <locus from="130v" to="132r">130v-132r</locus>
                            <title key="">Medical recipe for a 'Soverign water' attributed to a 'Doctor Steven'</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="enm">Middle English</textLang>
                            <note><p> Full transcription:<lb/> [Folio <locus from="130v" to="130v">130v</locus>] Herafter followeth the makyng of a
                                    Soueraygne water that doctor Steven physycyion and greate connyng man of long experyence dyd vse and therwith dyd
                                    many cures . Take a gallone of good gayscon wynne then take gynger , galyngayle , cannell Synomum , Nutmugges ,
                                    graynes , Cloves , mace , Annasseades , fenell seades , Carrayway seades , of euery of theym a dramme , then take
                                    sage myntes , readrses , tyme , pellytory [Folio <locus from="131r" to="131r">131r</locus>] of the walle , wylde
                                    magerom, roose marye , penyryall , peny mowntayne other wyse called wylde tyme , cammamell , lavender , Avenne ,
                                    of euery one of theym a handfull then beate the spyces small , and brusse the hearbes and put all into the wyne ,
                                    and let yt stande twelf hiyres styryng yt dyuerse tymes , then styll yt in a lymbeck and keape the ffyrst pynte of
                                    the water for yt ys beaste , then wyll comme an other water , whyche ys not so good as the ffyrste [Folio <locus
                                        from="131v" to="131v">131v</locus>] Thys water conforteth the spyryttes and <unclear>Lesneth
                                        generally</unclear> the yowth of moni , and helpeth inwarde dyseases commyng of colde , and agaynst shakyng of
                                        y<hi rend="superscript">e</hi> palsey yt cureth the contraccyon of synewis and helpeth the concepcyon of women
                                    that be barreyn , yt kylleth wormes in the belly , yt helpeth the colde [Folio <locus from="132r" to="132r"
                                        >132r</locus>] the backe, yt cyreth the canker , yt helpeth shortely a stynikyng breathe And who so vsethe
                                    thys water in a meane and not to ofte yt preseruethe hym in good lykyng and shull make one yonge very longe
                                    probatum est </p></note>
                            <listBibl>
                                <bibl>IMEP 18, item 1, pp. 66-67</bibl>
                            </listBibl>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="31">
                            <locus from="134r" to="134r">134r</locus>
                            <title key="">Account note</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="enm">Middle English</textLang>
                            <note><p>Full transcription: <lb/> Master laurance Robertson of Beyssey debet to be payde on myghelmesse xiij<hi
                                        rend="superscript">s</hi></p>
                                <p/>
                            </note>
                            <listBibl>
                                <bibl>IMEP 18, item 2, pp. 66-67</bibl>
                            </listBibl>
                        </msItem>

                        <msItem n="32">
                            <locus from="134r" to="134r">134r</locus>
                            <title key="">Account note</title>
                            <textLang mainLang="enm">Middle English</textLang>
                            <note><p>Full transcription: <lb/> + Master william Thagkker hath payde of this + yere rent at lammesse xxxiij<hi
                                        rend="superscript">s</hi> iiij di</p>
                            </note>
                            <listBibl>
                                <bibl>IMEP 18, item 3, pp. 66-67</bibl>
                            </listBibl>
                        </msItem>

                    </msContents>


                    <physDesc>
                        <p>
                            <secFol>
                                <locus from="2r" to="2r">2r</locus>: Memoria de sancta trinitate deuota oracio </secFol>
                        </p>

                        <objectDesc form="codex">
                            <supportDesc material="perg">

                                <support>
                                    <material>All medieval leaves parchment (<term type="disposition">HFFH</term>)</material>
                                </support>

                                <extent>
                                    <seg type="object">Codex: </seg>
                                    <seg type="leaf">
                                        <measure quantity="2" type="laterEndleaf">ii</measure> + <measure quantity="3" type="endleaf">3</measure> +
                                            <measure quantity="133" type="leaf">133</measure> + <measure quantity="1" type="endleaf">1</measure> +
                                            <measure quantity="2" type="laterEndleaf">ii</measure> leaves. </seg>
                                    <seg type="dimensions">
                                        <dimensions type="leaf" unit="mm">
                                            <height quantity="205">205</height>
                                            <width quantity="145">145</width>
                                        </dimensions>
                                    </seg>
                                </extent>

                                <foliation notAfter="2024">
                                    <p>Modern foliation sequence</p>
                                    <p>[a]-i + ii-iv + 1-133 + 134 + v-vi </p>
                                    <note>Foliated in pencil in Hindu-Arabic numerals in the upper outer corner of each recto. </note>
                                </foliation>

                                <foliation notAfter="2024">
                                    <p>Deprecated modern foliation sequence</p>
                                    <p>Folios 1-136 for the present ff. iii-134. </p>
                                    <note>Foliated in pencil in Hindu-Arabic numerals in the lower margin of each recto. </note>
                                </foliation>


                                <collation mainStructures="8 10 6 4">
                                    <p>The collation is difficult to establish with absolute certainty due to the extensive interference with the
                                        structure of the volume that presumably occured during the most recent rebinding. The tightness of the present
                                        binding restricts the maximum angle of opening, and the gutters are now extremely compressed, rendering the
                                        sewing almost completely inaccessible.</p>
                                    <p>Possible loss (or accidental omission) of a full-page miniature between the present ff. <locus from="121v"
                                            to="122r">121v-122r</locus>. The opening at ff. ff. <locus from="121v" to="122r">121v-122r</locus>
                                        presents the boundary between Quire 16 and Quire 17; both Quires 16 and 17 appear to have originally been
                                        6-leaf (3 bifolium) quires, but both are now lacking leaves. Quire 16 appears to be missing its original 6th
                                        leaf, probably due to cancellation as a long section of excerpts from the psalms (ff. 111v-121v) concluded on
                                        the fifth leaf, f. <locus from="121v" to="121v">121v</locus>. The original first and second leaf are missing
                                        from Quire 17, and may have been cancelled or deliberately removed. What is now the opening leaf of Quire 17
                                        (f. <locus from="122r" to="122r">122r</locus>, the original 3rd leaf) contains the start of a new group of
                                        prayers, in this case to the Virgin Mary, but this section of text lacks either an inhabited initial, or a
                                        full page miniature to introduce it. The opening initial on f. <locus from="122r" to="122r">122r</locus> is
                                        relatively modest for a new section of text in this Book of Hours; new sections of text in MS McClean 89
                                        typically begin with a full page miniature on the verso of the opening, or with a historiated or inhabited
                                        initial, rather than a 'simple' decorative initial. In most other places in the manuscript with initials of
                                        this type (blue intial on a recto, 6-7 lines high, gold counterspace with foliate decoration, pink ground),
                                        the previous verso contains a full-page miniature (see e.g., ff. <locus from="112v" to="113r"
                                            >112v-113r</locus> for just one of many examples), and so it is probably the case that there was a
                                        full-page miniature either intended or executed for the original first bifolium of Quire 17, and the miniature
                                        was either accidentally omitted, or was removed after painting, leaving a gap in the collation and a
                                        disruption in the hierarchy of decoration in the volume. </p>
                                    <p>The collation appears to be as follows: <list>
                                            <item>Two paper endleaves contemporary with the binding, the recto of the first covered with washed silk
                                                (ff. <locus from="[a] recto" to="i verso">[a] - i</locus>) +</item>
                                            <item>Three medieval parchment endleaves (ff. <locus from="ii recto" to="iv verso">ii-iv</locus>) +</item>
                                            <item>Quire 1<hi rend="superscript">10</hi> (ff. <locus from="1r" to="10v">1-10</locus>) </item>
                                            <item>Quires 2-3<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> (ff. <locus from="11r" to="26v">11-26</locus>)</item>
                                            <item>Quire 4<hi rend="superscript">6</hi> (ff. <locus from="27r" to="32v">27-32</locus>)</item>
                                            <item>Quire 5<hi rend="superscript">10</hi> (ff. <locus from="33r" to="42v">33r-42v</locus>)</item>
                                            <item>Quires 6-8<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> (ff. <locus from="43r" to="66v">43-66</locus>)</item>
                                            <item>Quire 9<hi rend="superscript">two</hi> (ff. <locus from="67r" to="68v">67-68</locus>)</item>
                                            <item>Quires 10-15<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> (ff. <locus from="69r" to="116v">69-116</locus>)</item>
                                            <item>Quire 16<hi rend="superscript">6-1</hi> (ff. <locus from="117r" to="121v">117-121</locus>; 6th leaf
                                                cancelled) </item>
                                            <item>Quire 17<hi rend="superscript">6-2</hi> (ff. <locus from="122r" to="125v">122-125</locus>; 1st and
                                                2nd leaves ?missing ?cancelled) </item>
                                            <item>Quire 18<hi rend="superscript">6</hi> (ff. <locus from="126r" to="131v">126-131</locus>) </item>
                                            <item>Quire 19<hi rend="superscript">4-1</hi> (ff. <locus from="132r" to="134v">132-134</locus>; 1st leaf
                                                cancelled)</item>
                                            <item>Two paper endleaves contemporary with the binding, the verso of the last covered with washed silk
                                                (ff. <locus from="v recto" to="vi verso">v-vi</locus>)</item>
                                        </list>
                                    </p>
                                    <formula> Two paper endleaves + three parchment endleaves + 1<hi rend="superscript">10</hi> 2-3<hi
                                            rend="superscript">8</hi> 4<hi rend="superscript">6</hi> 5<hi rend="superscript">10</hi> 6-8<hi
                                            rend="superscript">8</hi> 9<hi rend="superscript">two</hi> 10-15<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> 16<hi
                                            rend="superscript">6-1</hi> (6th cancelled) 17<hi rend="superscript">6-2</hi> (1st and 2nd ?missing
                                        ?cancelled) 18<hi rend="superscript">6</hi> 19<hi rend="superscript">4-1</hi> (1st cancelled) + two paper
                                        endleaves </formula>
                                    <signatures type="leaf"><p>No leaf signatures. </p></signatures>
                                    <signatures type="quire"><p>Quires are numbered in pencil in Hindu-Arabic numerals in the lower outer corner of
                                            the first recto of each quire. </p></signatures>
                                    <catchwords><seg type="para">No catchwords. </seg></catchwords>
                                </collation>

                                <condition> In good condition </condition>

                            </supportDesc>

                            <layoutDesc>
                                <layout columns="1" rulingMedium="ink" topLine="below" writtenLines="22"><p>
                                        <dimensions type="written" unit="mm">
                                            <height max="140" min="135">135-140</height>
                                            <width quantity="95">95</width>
                                        </dimensions>
                                        <seg type="ruling"> Folios <locus from="1r" to="133v">1-133</locus> ruled in magenta ink, frame and lines.
                                            Ruled in single-column format, typically 22 lines to the page and written below top line. Folios <locus
                                                from="130v" to="132r">130v-132r</locus> use alternate lines of the ruling and are written
                                            approximately 12 lines to the page. Folio <locus from="134r" to="134r">134r</locus> is unruled and
                                            informally written. </seg></p>
                                </layout>

                            </layoutDesc>
                        </objectDesc>

                        <handDesc>
                            <handNote script="textualisNorthern">
                                <p>The main text of the Book of Hours (ff. <locus from="2r" to="128r">2r-128r</locus> is written in a northern
                                    textualis <hi rend="italic">formata</hi>. </p>
                            </handNote>

                            <handNote script="cursivaAntiquior">
                                <p>Medical recipe on ff. <locus from="130v" to="132r">130v-132r</locus> written in a muted lavender ink in an <term
                                        type="script">anglicana</term> hand with <term type="script">secretary</term> features. </p>
                            </handNote>

                            <handNote script="cursivaAntiquior">
                                <p>Notes on f. <locus from="134r" to="134r">134r</locus> informally written in an <term type="script">Anglicana</term>
                                    hand. </p>
                            </handNote>
                        </handDesc>



                        <decoDesc>
                            <decoNote type="miniature">
                                <p>Full-page miniatures all in rectangular frame swith rounded upper edges surrounded by foliate borders (please note
                                    that these descriptions are partially based on those by M.R. James): <list>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="1v" to="1v">1v</locus>: Memoria de S. Trinitate. God the Father crowned, nimbed, and
                                            throned holds the crucified Jesus nimbed before him. The scene set in a paved room with two leaded lights. </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="3v" to="3v">3v</locus>: Fifteen Oos. The crucifixion. Jesus nimbed on the cross,
                                            flanked by the two crucified thieves who hang with contorted limbs. Mary and John the Evangelist, both
                                            nimbed, stand below</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="9v" to="9v">9v</locus>: Prayer of Bede. A nimbed Pope in blue cope and blue tiara,
                                            holding patriarchal cross, a piece of wall behind and a landscape. </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="33v" to="33v">33v</locus>: Matins of the Virgin. Annunciation scene. Mary nimbed and
                                            consulting a book in right of scene, an angel enters from without on left of scene holding scroll with
                                            text <sic>'Aue Maria plena dominus tecum'</sic>. God the Father in sky above, breath of God indicated by
                                            gold rays and supporting a white dove flying toward Mary. </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="39v" to="39v">39v</locus>Lauds of the Virgin. The Visitation. Mary nimbed on left of
                                            scene. Elizabeth nimbed on right of scene emerges from a house.</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="49v" to="49v">49v</locus>: Prime of the Virgin. Mary and Joseph in adoration of
                                            Jesus. In a garden or animal enclosure, the infant Jesus nimbed and rayed in the centre of the scene
                                            flanked by Mary nimbed and Joseph. A ray of light falls from the sky and touches the head of the infant
                                            Jesus. Joseph holds a candle and shelters the flame with his cloak. Two shepherds approach in the
                                            distance. </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="52v" to="52v">52v</locus>: Tierce of the Virgin. Adoration of the magi. In a garden
                                            or animal enclosure with building in right background and landscape scenery in left background. Mary
                                            nimbed and seated on right of scene holds the nimbed infant Jesus. The three magi or kings cluster around
                                            Jesus in centre and left of scene, two crowned and holding golden orbs, one uncrowned and kneeling before
                                            Jesus.</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="54v" to="54v">54v</locus>: Sext of the Virgin. The Flight into Egypt. Set in a rocky
                                            landscape with lake in the background. Mary nimbed and seated on donkey holds Jesus nimbed in one arm and
                                            holds a bowl out to Josep at right of scene standing at the head of the donkey. </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="56v" to="56v">56v</locus>: Nones of the Virgin. The Resurrection. Jesus nimbed
                                            emerges from a stone tomb, holding patriarchal cross in left hand and raising right hand in benediction.
                                            Two soldiers, one at each end of the tomb. Landscape scene in background. </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="58v" to="58v">58v</locus>: Verspers of the Virgin. The Assumption of Mary. Mary
                                            nimbed with hands clasped in prayer is carried into the sky by four angels with pink, green and blue
                                            wings. Landscape scenery below. </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="60v" to="60v">60v</locus>: Compline of the Virgin. The Coronation of Mary. Interior
                                            scene with tiled floor and chequered walls. Mary nimbed kneels in left of scene before Jesus nimbed and
                                            throned on right of scene holding an orb and raising his right hand in benediction. A canopy behind the
                                            throne bears a banner with the word 'MARIA' written in gold. An angel hovers above Mary holding a crown. </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="68v" to="68v">68v</locus>: Seven psalms. Landscape scene. Jesus nimbed and seated on
                                            a rainbow depicted in black and gold with his feet resting on a golden orb. Jesus has arms raised
                                            displaying the wounds in his hands, his fingertips touch a sword pointing toward his left ear and a spray
                                            of lilies emerging from his right ear. On earth below Mary and John the Evangelist, both nimbed, kneel
                                            facing one another. Three heads emerge from graves in the earth. </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="81v" to="81v">81v</locus>: Office of the Dead. Interior scene. A coffin in the centre
                                            of the illustration covered in a blue pall with gold embroidery and flanked by two tall lit candles.
                                            Members of the clergy stand to the right of the coffin. Hooded figures in black approach the coffin
                                            through a door to the left, landscape scenery visible in the distance. </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="97v" to="97v">97v</locus>: Commendations. Landscape scene. Two angels carry a white
                                            sling bearing a naked figure (a representation of a soul) to heaven. The clouds are parted above and a
                                            half-length Jesus nimbed, holding orb, and raising a hand in benediction gazes down at the soul flanked by
                                            two more angels. </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="107v" to="107v">107v</locus>: Psalms of the Passion. Man of Sorrows with the <hi
                                                rend="italic">arma christi</hi>. Landscape scene. Jesus nimbed and depicted as the Man of Sorrows sits
                                            up in his tomb, his arms crossed in front of his chest. The <hi rend="italic">arma christi</hi> are
                                            represented by the cross, crown of thorns, pillar, sponge on stick, three nails and hammer, pincers,
                                            lantern, awl, rods. </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="112v" to="112v">112v</locus>: Psalter of Saint Jerome. Interior scene. Jerome nimbed
                                            and wearing the red of a cardinal stands facing left before a low desk with two sloping faces, his hand on
                                            a book. A lion rests on a the tiled floor behind Jerome. </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="125v" to="125v">125v</locus>: Salue Ihesu. Interior scene. Pope Gregory the Great
                                            nimbed and in blue chasuble kneels at altar on right of image on which stands Jesus in front of a tomb as
                                            the Man of Sorrows flanked by the <hi rend="italic">arma christi</hi>. The <hi rend="italic">arma
                                                christi</hi> are represented by the cross, crown of thorns, sponge on stick, three nails and hammer,
                                            lance, awl, rods. Two cardinals, stand behind Gregory, one wearing a galero and holding a book and a
                                            patriarchal cross, the other tonsured and holding a papal tiara. </item>
                                    </list></p>
                            </decoNote>
                            <decoNote type="border">
                                <p>Floral and foliate borders typically around the upper, outer and lower margins of leaves with a full-page miniature
                                    or the opening of a new text. See for example ff. <locus from="9v" to="10r">9v-10r</locus>. In some cases (e.g.,
                                    f. <locus from="13r" to="13r">13r</locus>), typically when accompanying a historiated initial rather than a full
                                    page miniature, the floral and foliate borders are restricted to half the width of the upper and lower margin.
                                </p>
                            </decoNote>
                            <decoNote type="histInit">
                                <p>Historiated initials, typically 7 lines high, the letter typically painted in gold, or in blue with white
                                    patterning. Please note that these descriptions are partially based on those by M. R. James: <list>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="12r" to="12r">12r</locus>: Omnibus confessoris. Initial D. Interior scene in a church
                                            or chapel. A priest in blue chasuble, stands before an altar facing right and elevating the eucharistic
                                            bread. Chalice on altar. A woman in a divided hennin kneels on floor behind gazing at a book in front of
                                            her. </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="13r" to="13r">13r</locus>: Memorial of John the Baptist. Initial G. Landscape scene.
                                            John the Baptist nimbed holds an open book and gestures to a white lamb beside him. </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="14r" to="14r">14r</locus> Memorial of Saint George. Initial G. Landscape scene with
                                            city in distance. George with tabard and shield in argent with cross gules, seated on horse with green
                                            tack and bearing a lance pierces the mouth of the dragon lying in the foreground of the scene. Princess
                                            and lamb kneeling to right of scene. King and queen watch from city walls in the distance. </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="15r" to="15r">15r</locus>: Memorial to Saint Christopher. Initial O. Landscape scene.
                                            Christopher nimbed and holding a rod wades through water with a nimbed infant Jesus seated on his
                                            shoulders.</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="16r" to="16r">16r</locus>: Memorial to Saint Anthony. Initial O. Landscape scene.
                                            Anthony nimbed and wearing black mantle over red robe and high red hat stands in fire holding an open book
                                            and a walking stick. A small quadruped stands to Anthony's right. </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="17r" to="17r">17r</locus>: Memorial to Saint Erasmus. Initial O. Landscape scene.
                                            Erasmus nimbed and nude and stretched on a board, his entrails being wound out by a windlass being turned
                                            by a soldier. A king holding a sceptre stands in the centre of the image with a female courtier behind.
                                            White mitre on the floor below the board.</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="18r" to="18r">18r</locus>: Memorial to Saint Nicholas. Initial O. Interior scene.
                                            Nicholas on right of scene nimbed and holding crozier, hand raised in benediction toward two nude boys in
                                            wooden tub on left of scene. </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="19r" to="19r">19r</locus>: Memorial to Saint Giles. Initial L. Landscape scene. Giles
                                            numbed in black robes and holding crozier stands reading before a wall. A deer paws at Giles' leg. </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="20r" to="20r">20r</locus>: Memorial to Saint Catherine (Katherine). Initial G.
                                            Interior scene. Katherine nimbed and crowned stand over Maxentius holding book and with wheel to side. </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="21r" to="21r">21r</locus>: Memorial to Saint Margaret. Initial G. Interior scene.
                                            Margaret nimbed and hands clasped in prayer rises from the back of a dragon. The dragon is shown with some
                                            of Margaret's robe in its mouth. </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="22r" to="22r">22r</locus>: Memorial to Saint Barbara. Initial G. Landscape scene.
                                            Barbara nimbed ?and with palm stands in an enclosed garden gazing at a tower to right of image. </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="23r" to="23r">23r</locus>: Memorial to Saint Mary Magdalene. Initial G. Landscape
                                            scene. Mary Magdalene nimbed stands holding a golden reliquary.</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="24r" to="24r">24r</locus>: Memorial to Saint Ursula. Initial U. Landscape scene.
                                            Ursula nimbed stands in an enclosed garden before a blue banner, arms outstretched and holding an arrow in
                                            each hand. Ursula's face has been obliterated through either deliberate damage or possible accidental
                                            obscuration through devotional kissing. </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="25r" to="25r">25r</locus>: Memorial to Saint Anna. Initial G. Interior scene. Anna
                                            nimbed and seated with Mary nimbed and reading at her knee.</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="65r" to="65r">65r</locus>: Salue uirgo. Initial S. Interior scene. Mary nimbed stands
                                            before an altar to right with a small angel standing to her left. </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="124r" to="124r">124r</locus>: O intermerata. Initial O. Interior scene. Mary nimbed
                                            and seated holds a nimbed and nude infant Jesus. An angel kneels to the left of the image. </item>
                                    </list></p>
                            </decoNote>
                            <decoNote type="decInit">
                                <p>Decorative initials, typically 6-7 lines high at the opening of some passages of text, see e.g., f. <locus
                                        from="2r" to="2r">2r</locus>. These decorative initials are typically set in a square frame, with the ground
                                    of the initial painted blue with white patterning and the counterspace of the initial painted with floral and
                                    foliate motifs on a gold ground. Space between the initial and frame filled with a pink ground and white
                                    patterning. </p>
                                <p>Decorative initials typically 2 lines high at some minor divisions of the text. Typically a gold initial set in a
                                    square frame with blue or pink ground and white highlights. See for example, the 'L' of 'Libera me domine' on f.
                                        <locus from="2v" to="2v">2v</locus>.</p>
                            </decoNote>
                            <decoNote type="flourInit"> Flourished initials found frequently at the minor divisions of the text. Flourished initials
                                are typically 1-2 lines high, with blue or gold initial set in a square matrix defined by red or black labrynthine
                                patterning. </decoNote>
                            <decoNote type="rubrication">
                                <p>Offices, prayers, responses, and instructions introduced with rubricated text (red only) throughout the book. See
                                    for example f. <locus from="4r" to="4r">4r</locus>, 'Deuota oracio ad dominum ihesum christum' to introduce The
                                    Fifteen Oos. </p>
                            </decoNote>
                        </decoDesc>

                        <additions>
                            <note>
                                <p>Extensive additions to Fitzwilliam Museum MS McClean 89 by members of the Skipwith family of <placeName
                                        key="place_g7028116">South Ormsby</placeName>, Lincolnshire, England. The majority of the additions record
                                    dates of birth of members of the Skipwith family and can be found in two groups, an earlier group on ff. <locus
                                        from="27r" to="33v">27r-33v</locus> in the calendar, and a later group on ff. <locus from="128r" to="129v"
                                        >128r-129v</locus>.</p>
                                <p>On f. <locus from="iii recto" to="iii recto">iii recto</locus>, there are annotations in ink by <name key="person_"
                                        role="sgn">
                                        <persName type="display">Margarett Skipwithe</persName>
                                        <persName type="standard">Margaret Skipwith</persName>
                                    </name>. Margarett Skipwith wrote her name twice, and under the first appearance of her name wrote a Latin motto,
                                    'Nec temere Nec timide' (Neither rashly Nor timidly). On the same leaf are the initials 'HS' in black ink, perhaps
                                    for the Henry Skipwith who owned the volume in the early seventeenth century and recorded the births of his
                                    children on ff. <locus from="129r" to="129v">129rv</locus>. </p>
                                <p>Skipwith family additions to the calendar on ff. <locus from="27r" to="33v">27r-33v</locus>: printed below as
                                    normalised and modernised text with transcription and comments following in parentheses:<lb/>
                                    <list>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="27r" to="27r">27r</locus>: Elizabeth Skipwith daughter of Lyon Skipwith esq. born 15
                                            February 1562. ('Elizabeth Skypwith daughter of Lyon Skypwith esquyer was borne the xv<hi
                                                rend="superscript">th</hi> day of februarye a m ccccc lxij'. Despite the entry mentioning February,
                                            this entry begins on the line for 13 January).</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="27r" to="27r">27r</locus>: On this day [20 January] was born Elizabeth Skipwith
                                            daughter of William Skipwith esq. of Ormsby in the sixteenth year of the reign of King Henry VIII [1524].
                                            ('Hac die nata fuit Elisabeth Skipwith filia Willelmi Skipwith armiger de Ornysby anno regni regis henrici
                                            octaui sextodecimo')</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="27v" to="27v">27v</locus>: The 2nd of February 1521 Brigida [Bridget] Skipwith was
                                            born. ('The secund day of februarij the ȝer of our lorde gode m ccccc xxi nata fuit briggida
                                            skypwith').</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="27v" to="27v">27v</locus>: Dorothea Skipwith daughter of William Skipwith esq. of
                                            South Ormsby was born on the sixth day of this month of February in the year 1527. ('Dorothea Skipwithe
                                            filia Willelmi Skipwithe de Sowthormrsby armigeri nata fuit Sexto die huiusce mensis februarij anno domini
                                            milesimo quingentesimo Vicesimo septimo')</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="28r" to="28r">28r</locus>: Margaret Skipwith daughter of Lyon Skipwith was born the
                                            8th day of March in 1561 (?1562). ('Margaret Skypwith daughter of Lyon Skypwith was borne the viij<hi
                                                rend="superscript">th</hi> day of marche in y<hi rend="superscript">e</hi> yere of our lord god a m
                                            cccccc lxj<unclear>j</unclear>'. Writing begins on line for 6 March. Birth year has final 'j' written in a
                                            different ink.)</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="28r" to="28r">28r</locus>: This [15 March] is the date of the birth of Marie Skipwith
                                            daughter of William Skipwith esq. of Ormsby in 1515, dominical letter G, 6th year of the reign of Henry
                                            VIII. ('iste est dies natalis marie Skypwith filie Willelmi Skypwith armiger de Ormysby anno domini m<hi
                                                rend="superscript">o</hi> ccccc<hi rend="superscript">o</hi> xv<hi rend="superscript">o</hi> littera
                                            dominicalis G anno henrici Octam Sexto.' Writing begins on line for 15 March.)</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="28r" to="28r">28r</locus>: The penultimate day of March [30th] in 1518 Anna daughter
                                            of William Skipwith esq. was born. ('penultima die marcij anno domini m<hi rend="superscript">lmo</hi>
                                            ccccc <sic>xiix<hi rend="superscript">o</hi></sic> nata fuit Anna filia willelmi skypwith armigeri'.
                                            Another hand has written '1518' in the margin next to the idiosynctatic 'xiix'.)</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="29r" to="29r">29r</locus>: Ursula Skipwith daughter of Lyon Skipwith esq. was born
                                            the 30th of May 1563. ('Ursula Skypwith daughter of Lyon Skypwith esquyre was borne the xxx<hi
                                                rend="superscript">h</hi> day of maye in the yere of oure Lord god a m ccccc lxiij').</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="29v" to="29v">29v</locus>: On the 11th June 1519 John Skipwith and his sister
                                            Margaret were born. ('Undecimo die Junij anno domini m<hi rend="superscript">o</hi> ccccc xix<hi
                                                rend="superscript">o</hi> nati sunt Johannes Skypwith et Margareta soror eius').</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="30r" to="30r">30r</locus>: Katheryn Skipwith daughter of Lyon Skipwith esquyer born
                                            10 July 1555 the dominical letter F. ('Katheryne Skypwith daughter of Lyon skypwith esquyer was borne the
                                                x<hi rend="superscript">th</hi> day of July in the yere of our Lorde god a m ccccclv the Dominicall
                                            letter ff'). </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="31r" to="31r">31r</locus>: Henry Skipwith son of William Skipwith esq. born the first
                                            day of this month [September] in the twenty-fourthth year of the reign of King Henry VIII [1532].
                                            ('Henricus Skipwithe filius Willelmi Skipwithe armigeri Natus fuit primo die huius Mensis anno Regni Regis
                                            Henrici octaui vicesimo quarto').</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="31r" to="31r">31r</locus>: William Skipwith son of Lyon Skipwith esq. was born 12
                                            September 1566. ('Willelmi Skypwith sone of Lyon Skypwith Esquyer was borne the xij<hi rend="superscript"
                                                >th</hi> day of Septembre in y<hi rend="superscript">e</hi> yere of ower Lorde god a m ccccc
                                            lxvj').</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="31v" to="31v">31v</locus>: Jane Skipwith daughter of William Skipwith esq. was born
                                            26 October in the 8th year of the reign of King Henry VIII [1516]. ('Jane Skipwith dogther vnto Willelmi
                                            Skipwith Esquier borne the xxvj<hi rend="superscript">ti</hi> day of October in the yere of the Reyne of
                                            Kyng Henry the Viij<hi rend="superscript">th</hi> the Viij<hi rend="superscript">th</hi> yere'). </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="32r" to="32r">32r</locus>: George Skipwith son of Lyon Skipwith esq. was born 4
                                            November 1567. ('George Skypwyth sonne of Lyon Skypwith esquyer was borne the fourth day of November in
                                            the yeare of ower lorde god A mccccclxvij').</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="32r" to="32r">32r</locus>: George Skipwith son of William Skipwith esq. was born the
                                            last day of November [30th] in 1529, the 21st year of the reign of King Henry VIII. ('Georgius Skipwithe
                                            filius Willelmi Skipwithe armigeri Natus fuit Ultimo die Nouembris Anno domini m<hi rend="superscript"
                                                >o</hi> quingentesi<hi rend="superscript">o</hi> Vicesimo no<hi rend="superscript">o</hi> ac anno
                                            regni regis henrici octaui uicesimo primo').</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="32v" to="32v">32v</locus>: Leo [Lyon] Skipwith son of William Skipwith esq. born 3
                                            December 1517, dominical letter d. ('Leo skypwith filius willelmi skypwith armiger natus erat tertio die
                                            mensis decembris Anno domini m<hi rend="superscript">lio</hi> ccccc decimo Septimo littera dominicalis
                                            d'). </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="32v" to="32v">32v</locus>: Katheryn Skipwith daughter to William Skipwith esq. was
                                            born 6 December of the 15th year of the reign of King Henry VIII [1523]. ('Katryn Skypwith dogther to
                                            William Skipwith esquyer was borne the vj day of December the xv yere of the Regne of King Henry the
                                                Viij<hi rend="superscript">th</hi>'). </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="32v" to="32v">32v</locus>: On this day was born George Skipwith son of William
                                            Skipwith esq. of Ormsby in the 18th year of the reign of King H[enry] VIII [1526]. ('Hac die nata fuit .
                                            Georgius Skipwith . filius Willelmi Skipwith armiger de Ormysby Anno Regni regis .H. Octaui Decimo
                                            octauo'). </item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="32v" to="32v">32v</locus>: John Skipwith son of Lyon Skipwith esq. was born 9 March
                                            1573 and the fifteenth [regnal] year of Elizabeth. ('Johannes Skipwith filius Leoni Skipwith armigeri
                                            natus fuit nono die marcij anno domini 1573 annoque Elizabeth decimo quinto'. Depsite the March date of
                                            birth, this entry appears on the calendar page for December. </item>
                                    </list></p>
                                <p>Skipwith family additions at the end of the main text on ff. <locus from="128r" to="129v">128r-129v</locus>: <list>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="128r" to="128r">128r</locus>: My daughter Jane was borne the thirde day of November
                                            being a fryday , betweene iij and iiij of the clocke in the after nonne , anno domini 1587</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="128r" to="128r">128r</locus>: My daughter Ann was borne the xxiijth of January beinge
                                            thursday betwene iij and iiij a clocke in the afternoone Anno Domini 1588</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="128v" to="128v">128v</locus>: My sonne Henry Skipwith was borne the xxj of March Anno
                                            Domini 1590</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="128v" to="128v">128v</locus>: My sonne <sic>Gorge</sic> Skipwith was borne the xij of
                                            february <sic>Annon</sic> Domini 1591</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="128v" to="128v">128v</locus>: My daughter Elizabeth Skipwith was borne the xj<hi
                                                rend="superscript">th</hi> of february Anno Domini 1592</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="128v" to="128v">128v</locus>: My sonne Thomas Skipwith was borne the vi<hi
                                                rend="superscript">th</hi> day of Auguste being a tuesdaye betweene fyue and syxe of the clocke in the
                                            after noone . Anno Domyno 1594</item>
                                        <item>The records of the births on ff. <locus from="128r" to="128v">128rv</locus> are signed in the lower
                                            margin of each page 'William Skipwith'</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="129r" to="129r">129r</locus>: My sonne William was borne on Fryday the xxv<hi
                                                rend="superscript">th</hi> of February att a quarter past one of the Clocke in <hi rend="superscript"
                                                >the</hi> after noone . Anno Domyne 1613 Henry Skipwith</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="129r" to="129r">129r</locus>: My sonne Henry was borne on Saturday the xvi<hi
                                                rend="superscript">th</hi> of December betweene eyght and nine in the morninge . Anno Domyne 1615 .
                                            Henry Skipwith</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="129r" to="129r">129r</locus>: My daughter Elizabeth was borne on Munday the vj<hi
                                                rend="superscript">th</hi> of October betweene ten and elevene of the clocke in the night . Anno
                                            Domyne 1617 . Henry Skipwith</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="129r" to="129r">129r</locus>: My sonne Thomas was borne on Tuesday y<hi
                                                rend="superscript">e</hi> 30<hi rend="superscript">th</hi> of march betweene 4 and 5 of the clocke in
                                            the morning in the yeare of our Lord 1618 . Henry Skipwith</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="129r" to="129r">129r</locus>: My daughter Diana was borne on Sunday the 27<hi
                                                rend="superscript">th</hi> of may betweene <hi rend="superscript">ȝe</hi> houres of 3 and 4 of y<hi
                                                rend="superscript">e</hi> clocke in after noone in the yeare of our Lorde 1621 . Henry Skipwith</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="129v" to="129v">129v</locus>: Graye Skipwith my sonne was borne the 23<hi
                                                rend="superscript">th</hi> of Januarij beinge Thursday betweene one and tooe of y<hi
                                                rend="superscript">e</hi> clocke in y<hi rend="superscript">e</hi> morninge . Anno: Dom: 1622 . Henry
                                            Skipwith</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="129v" to="129v">129v</locus>: Anne Skipwith my daughter was borne on munday the 23<hi
                                                rend="superscript">th</hi> of Februarie a little before a eleuen of the clocke in the morninge Anno
                                            Dom: 1623 . Henry Skipwith</item>
                                    </list></p>
                            </note>
                            <note><p>A note in ink on f. <locus from="ii recto" to="ii recto">ii recto</locus> in ink in a medieval hand written
                                    upside down relative to the orientation of the volume, 'voor en'. There are further pen trials in the same hand
                                    below.</p></note>
                        </additions>

                        <bindingDesc>
                            <binding notAfter="1912" notBefore="1800">
                                <p>19th-century binding. Fully bound in red leather over wood boards with bevelled edges, with similar decoration to
                                        <locus from="outside front cover" to="outside front cover">front</locus> and <locus from="outside rear cover"
                                        to="outside rear cover">rear</locus> covers. Covers are decorated with a gilded single-fillet frame inset from
                                    the perimeter of the boards by c. 15 mm. Decorative inlay work within the gilded fillet frame consisting of pieces
                                    of painted parchment arranged in a centre-and-corner style and inlaid into the leather of the cover. The inlaid
                                    parchment corners are painted with a simplified floral and foliate motif in pink, green, and blue, perhaps
                                    modelled after the floral and foliate borders found within the manuscript. The centrepiece of the front cover is a
                                    crucifix with four further points at the intercardinals painted gold, with a medalion in the centre with the
                                    nominum sacrum for Jesus, 'ihs' written in dark blue ink. The centrepiece of the rear cover is a lobed rectangle
                                    with a crucifix painted in red with a gold-painted ring piercing the arms of the cross around their central
                                    intersection. The perimeters of the centre-and-corner parchment inlays are outlined with a gilded single
                                    fillet.</p>
                                <p>Four raised bands on <locus from="spine" to="spine">spine</locus>, each bisected with a gilded single fillet. Spine
                                    is decorated with gilded double-fillets across the width of the spine at the upper and lower perimeter of each
                                    compartment and a gilded fleuron in the centre of each compartment. Decorative head and tail bands wound in
                                    alternate segments of blue and yellow yarn. Burgundy ?silk bookribbon anchored in the head band. </p>
                                <p>Gilded decorative roll around the turn ins. The remains of a former blind-panel-stamp binding (c. 1490-1550) fixed
                                    to the inner faces of the front and rear boards with an adhesive.</p>
                                <p>Large decorative metal fastening set at the centre of the fore edge of the volume; the other half of the fastening
                                    missing from the rear cover. </p>
                                <p>Top, fore, and lower edges of the bookblock gilt and gauffered.</p>
                                <p>Folios <locus from="[a] recto" to="[a] verso">[a]</locus> and <locus from="vi recto" to="vi verso">vi</locus> are
                                    leaves contemporary with the current binding, their faces closest to the inner board (i.e., ff. [a] recto and vi
                                    verso) covered with blue watered silk to protect the remains of the earlier binding now pasted to the inner faces
                                    of the boards. The perimeters of the watered silk leaves are decorated with a gilded roll. </p>
                                <p>Paper endleaves contemporary with the present binding as follows (ff. [a] and i at the front of the volume and v
                                    and vi at the rear of the volume): <list>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="[a] recto" to="[a] recto">[a] recto</locus>: overlaid with blue watered silk fixed to
                                            the recto with an adhesive</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="[a] verso" to="[a] verso">[a] verso</locus>: the number '89' in pencil; a note '126
                                            leaves of writing' in pencil; a Frank McClean engraved bookplate fixed to the leaf with an adhesive; the
                                            number '79' in pencil</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="i recto" to="i recto">i recto</locus>: blank</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="i verso" to="i verso">i verso</locus>: the word 'Sarum' in pencil</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="v recto" to="v recto">v recto</locus>: blank</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="v verso" to="v verso">v verso</locus>: blank</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="vi recto" to="vi recto">vi recto</locus>: collation note in pencil<lb/> '3+ 134
                                            ff<lb/> Nov.9.08<lb/> H.A.C'</item>
                                        <item>Folio <locus from="vi verso" to="vi verso">vi verso</locus>: overlaid with blue watered silk fixed to
                                            the verso with an adhesive</item>
                                    </list>
                                </p>
                            </binding>

                            <binding notAfter="1550" notBefore="1490">
                                <p>Remains of a former panel-stamp binding from the last decade of the fifteenth century or the first half of the
                                    sixteenth century now bound with the volume. The former decorative panels have been trimmed significantly and are
                                    fixed to the inner <locus from="inside front cover" to="inside front cover">front</locus> and <locus
                                        from="inside rear cover" to="inside rear cover">rear</locus> covers with an adhesive and both measure
                                    approximately (L x W) 170 x 100 mm. This type of panel-stamp binding design now preserved withn MS McClean 89 was
                                    popular in England and Flanders c. 1490-1550. The remains of the panel-stamp binding now fixed to the inside
                                        <locus from="inside rear cover" to="inside rear cover">rear</locus> cover exhibit significant damage, and the
                                    damage has been repaired with similar, but undecorated leather. </p>
                                <p> The design of the panel stamp binding consisted of a small rectangular panel-stamp (L x W) c. 85 x 50mm, repeated
                                    in two rows and two columns, to form a larger design. The panel stamp has a text-frame rendered in a northern
                                    textualis formata (read clockwise from bottom right corner): 'Adoramus te xpe | et benedicamus tibi quia | per
                                    sanctam crucem | tuam redemisti mundum' (We adore you O Christ and we praise you because by your holy cross you
                                    have redeemed the world). Within the text-frame the stamp is divided vertically into two narrow panels, each with
                                    four roundels stacked vertically, and the space within the roundels filled with foliage. The roundels are filled
                                    top-to-bottom left-to-right with the following figures:<list>
                                        <item>bestial quadruped with long neck, facing right</item>
                                        <item>bird with webbed feet, body facing right, head facing left</item>
                                        <item>humanoid figure perching on a branch, body facing left, head facing right</item>
                                        <item>humanoid figure (perhaps a satyr) genuflecting on one knee, facing right and blowing a pipe</item>
                                        <item>large bird facing right</item>
                                        <item>bestial biped, body facing left, head facing right</item>
                                        <item>bestial biped with long neck facing left, head bent to ground</item>
                                        <item>humanoid figure facing left, crouching and kicking a leg forward, perhaps dancing </item>
                                    </list></p>
                                <p>Not in J. B. Oldham, <hi rend="italic">Blind Panels of English Binders</hi> (1958) </p>

                            </binding>
                        </bindingDesc>

                    </physDesc>

                    <history>
                        <origin>
                            <origDate calendar="Gregorian" cert="medium" notAfter="1500" notBefore="1475">Last quarter of the 15th century, perhaps
                                early 1490s. </origDate>
                            <origPlace cert="medium" key="place_g7024097">Probably Flanders. </origPlace>
                            <p>Date and place of production assigned based on palaeographical and artistic features of the manuscript. Nicholas Rogers
                                has suggested a date in the 'early 1490's' for the production of this manuscript, but did not provide further
                                elaboration.</p>
                            <p>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>N. Rogers, 'Books of Hours Produced in the Low Countries for the English Market in the Fifteenth Century', 2
                                        vols (unpublished M.Litt., University of Cambridge, 1984) II.374</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </p>
                        </origin>

                        <provenance when="1515">
                            <seg type="para">Cambridge, Fitzwilliam Museum, MS McClean 89 (hereafter MS McClean 89) is a Book of Hours made in
                                Flanders in the late 15th century for the English book market. The manuscript was in England by 1515 at the latest,
                                since several generations of the Skipwith family of South Ormsby in Lincolnshire added birth records to the calendar
                                (ff. <locus from="27r" to="32v">27r-32v</locus>) and to some of the endleaves (ff. <locus from="128r" to="129v"
                                    >128r-129v</locus>). The Skipwith family were minor gentry, and several members of the family were involved in
                                local and national politics and also married into socially powerful families. </seg>
                            <seg type="para">The birth records in MS McClean 89 are worth close examination, not only as a primary source of new
                                biographical information about several socially and politically important figures in England in the 16th and 17th
                                centuries, but also because the records allow us to trace the transfer of the volume from one generation to another
                                through four generations of the Skipwith family. In addition, the birth records are especially important as a way to
                                highlight the family of Lyon (also known as Leo, Lionel) Skipwith, eldest son of the marriage between Sir William
                                Skipwith and Alice Dymoke, whose children seem to have been erroneously attributed to his younger brother Henry
                                Skipwith in many accounts of the family history (more information below).</seg>
                            <seg type="para">The first member of the Skipwith family to use MS McClean 89 was <name key="person_" role="fmo scr">
                                    <persName type="display">Sir William Skipwith (b. ?1488, d. 1547)</persName>
                                    <persName type="standard">Sir William Skipwith, b. ?1488, d. 1547</persName>
                                </name>, High Sheriff of Lincolnshire 1526-1527, MP for Lincolnshire in 1529 and 1539 (see <ref
                                    target="https://www.historyofparliamentonline.org/volume/1509-1558/member/skipwith-william-1487-1547">History of
                                    Parliament entry</ref> for further details), and son of Sir John Skipwith (d. ?1518), High Sheriff of Lincolnshire
                                1493 and Katherine Skipwith (née Fitzwilliam). Sir William was married twice, first to Elizabeth Tyrwhitt, by whom he
                                had one son, also named William (born c. 1510) (for whom also see <ref
                                    target="https://www.historyofparliamentonline.org/volume/1509-1558/member/skipwith-sir-william-1510-86">History of
                                    Parliament entry</ref>) before Elizabeth's death in or before the year 1514. Sir William then married Alice
                                Dymoke, daughter of Sir Lionel Dymoke; the date is not recorded, but the marriage probably took place in or before
                                mid-1514, since William recorded the births of his children with Alice Dymoke in MS McClean 89, beginning with Marie
                                (Mary), who was born 15 March 1515. Records in a number of hands record the births of a further twelve of his children
                                in the manuscript's calendar pages, summarised as follows in chronological order (for full transcriptions and
                                interpretations, see Additions): <list>
                                    <item>Marie (Mary), born 15 March 1515</item>
                                    <item>Jane, born 26 October 1516</item>
                                    <item>Lyon (also known as Leo and Lionel), born 3 December 1517</item>
                                    <item>Anna, born 30 March 1518</item>
                                    <item>John and Margaret, born 11 June 1519</item>
                                    <item>Brigida (Bridget), born 2 February 1521</item>
                                    <item>Katryn (Katheryn, Katherine), born 6 December 1523</item>
                                    <item>Elisabeth (Elizabeth), born 20 January 1524</item>
                                    <item>George, born 12 December 1526</item>
                                    <item>Dorothea, born 6 February 1527</item>
                                    <item>George, born 30 November 1529</item>
                                    <item>Henry, born 1 September 1532</item>
                                </list></seg>
                            <seg type="para">There are a number of unresolved complexities in this list of births. In three instances, it appears that
                                births occur too close together for Alice Dymoke to be the mother of both children: Lyon on 3 December 1517 and Anna
                                on 30 March 1518; Katryn on 6 December 1523 and Elisabeth on 20 January 1524; and George on 12 December 1526 and
                                Dorothea on 6 February 1527. The manner in which the dates are recorded in the manuscript varies: by regnal years,
                                calendar years, or some combination thereof. There were also at this time differing practices in reckoning the start
                                of the year: the calendar/Christian year began on 1 January, but the legal year on 25 March. The impossibly short gap
                                between the births of Katryn and Elisabeth, and between George and Dorothea, might be explained by confusion arising
                                from these different systems, if Katryn were born on 6 December 1522 not 1523, and if George were born on 6 February
                                1528, not 1527. However, no such resolution is possible for Lyon and Anna, since their birth dates are too closely
                                pre- and post-dated by their siblings Jane and twins John and Margaret. One possibility is that some of these children
                                were born out of wedlock to another mother, though the naming of Lyon (presumably in honour of his maternal
                                grandfather) and the descent of the manuscript to him suggests that he was legitimate (further details below). A
                                further question hangs over the two children named George: perhaps the first died in infancy. Further research is
                                needed to place all of these observations on firmer evidential ground. </seg>
                            <seg type="para">It is notable that the birth of Sir William's first child (William, b. ?1510), by his first wife
                                Elizabeth, is not recorded here. Furthermore, the book passed not to this William, but to the oldest son, Lyon (b.
                                1517), of Sir William's second marriage to Alice. This suggests the possibility that MS McClean 89 came into the
                                Skipwith family via Alice herself, and who wished it to remain in her side of the family. Lyon was married twice,
                                first to Margaret Barnardiston, daughter of John Barnardiston, and second to Jane Bracebridge, daughter of William
                                Bracebridge. The births of seven of his children were recorded in MS McClean 89, all in the same hand, which might
                                indicate that Lyon added the entries himself. The children of Lyon Skipwith as recorded in MS McClean 89 are as
                                follows: <list>
                                    <item>Katheryne (Katherine), born 10 July 1555</item>
                                    <item>Margaret, born 8 March 1561 (or 1562)</item>
                                    <item>Elizabeth, born 15 February 1562</item>
                                    <item>Ursula, born 30 May 1563</item>
                                    <item>William, born 12 September 1566</item>
                                    <item>George, born 4 November 1567</item>
                                    <item>John, born 9 March 1573</item>
                                </list></seg>
                            <seg type="para">Lyon Skipwith has not left a substantial trace in the historical record, and as a result some sources
                                appear to conflate details of his life with those of his youngest brother, Henry (b. 1 September 1532). For instance,
                                in <hi rend="italic">Burke's Peerage, Knightage and Baronetage</hi> ((2003), III.3641), Henry is said to have had
                                twelve children (William, Francis, Henry, George, Ursula, Catherine, Anne, Jane, Bridget, Dorothy, Elizabeth,
                                Margaret), but the records added to MS McClean 89 indicate that some of these are Lyon's children. Further suggestive
                                evidence is provided by the descent of the manuscript, which passed to William (b. 1566), since it is more likely that
                                he inherited it as Lyon's son, rather than as his nephew. </seg>
                            <seg type="para"><name key="person_" role="fmo scr">
                                    <persName type="display">William Skipwith (b. 1566, d. 1610)</persName>
                                    <persName type="standard">William Skipwith, 1566-1610</persName>
                                </name> was Sheriff of Leicestershire c. 1598, and MP for Leicestershire in 1601 and for Leicester in 1604 (see <ref
                                    target="https://www.historyofparliamentonline.org/volume/1604-1629/member/skipwith-sir-william-1564-1610">History
                                    of Parliament entry</ref>). He was knighted in 1603 and was married twice, first to Margaret Cave and second to
                                Jane Roberts, the daughter of John Roberts of Wollaston. Like his antecedents, he recorded the births of six children
                                on ff. <locus from="128r" to="128v">128r-128v</locus>, as follows: <list>
                                    <item>Jane, born 3 November 1587</item>
                                    <item>Anne, born 23 January 1588</item>
                                    <item>Henry, born 21 March 1590</item>
                                    <item>George, born 12 February 1591</item>
                                    <item>Elizabeth, born 11 February 1592</item>
                                    <item>Thomas, born 6 August 1594</item>
                                </list>
                            </seg>
                            <seg type="para">MS McClean 89 passed to William's eldest male child, <name key="person_" role="fmo scr">
                                    <persName type="display">Henry Skipwith (b. 1590)</persName>
                                    <persName type="standard">Henry Skipwith, b. 1590</persName>
                                </name>. Henry was knighted in 1609 and was married twice, first to Anne Kempe, daughter of Sir Thomas Kempe and
                                second to Blandina Pennen, daughter of John Pennen of Badgeworth, Somerset. He too recorded the births of seven
                                children on ff. <locus from="129r" to="129v">129r-129v</locus>, as follows: <list>
                                    <item>William, born 25 February 1613</item>
                                    <item>Henry, born 16 December 1615</item>
                                    <item>Elizabeth, born 6 October 1617</item>
                                    <item>Thomas, born 30 March 1618</item>
                                    <item>Diana, born 27 May 1621</item>
                                    <item>Graye, born 23 January 1622</item>
                                    <item>Anne, born 23 February 1623</item>
                                </list>
                            </seg>
                            <seg type="para">There are no further Skipwith births recorded in MS McClean 89 after this last entry, and the subsequent
                                ownership of the manuscript is unknown.</seg>
                        </provenance>

                        <!-- PROBLEM - unclear evidence for where/how Frank McClean obtained MS McClean 89  - pay close attention to use of name St(r)afford below.
                            
                            - The stub catalogue on the Fitzwilliam Museum website says 'Lord Strafford’s sale, Christie’s, London, 28 July 1885, lot 51'
                            - M. R. James says 'Purchased at Christie's at Lord Strafford's Sale' without any further info
                            - Kari-Anne Rand in IMEP XVII says 'James says "Purchased at Christie's at lord Stafford's sale". this was not the Stafford sale
                            of 27 May 1885, which contained no MSS. Lord Stafford died 1884 [...].' KAR usually has excellent provenance info, so I'm unsure if
                            KAR made a typo here or if she is correcting one made by MRJ.
                            
                            QUESTION - did McClean buy the book from Lord Stafford or Lord Strafford. There are two plausible candidates, both known to have collected
                            art/furniture/books.
                              - Lord Stafford would be Henry Valentine Stafford-Jerningham, who died 30 November 1884 and seems to have had a good book collection
                            and possibly even owned some manuscripts, but I cannot find any reference of him or his family selling through Christies at all.
                            - Lord Strafford would be George Stevens Byng, 2nd Earl of Strafford (also
                                styled Lord Strafford), who died 29 October 1886 and sold (or his family sold) paintings and furniture via Christie's in the late 19th century.
                          
                            
                            I (Sarah Gilbert) asked the Fitz for any provenance info available while I was writing this catalogue record, but the people I corresponded
                            with don't know where the sale info of '28 July 1885 lot 51' came from, nor do they have a copy of the sale catalogue in their collection.
                            I asked to see any correspondence and paraphernalia kept with the manuscript when I went to the Fitz to catalogue the MS, but there was no
                            sale catalogue or any further provenance info in the correspondence. I emailed the FitzMus Ref Library and asked if they had any Christie's Sale Catalogues for
                            May or July 1885 for a 'Stafford' or a 'Strafford' that might not show up on iDiscover, but they said they didn't have any sale
                            catalogues for May or July 1885 for either of those names. The Fitz Mus Ref Library has a huge (but not complete) collection of English
                            auction catalogues, so just because they don't have it doesn't mean it doesn't exist.
                            
                            I've written two provenance entries, one for Lord Stafford and one for Lord Strafford in the hope that more info will come to light and we
                            can add the correct provenance entries in at some point and delete the incorrect one.
                            
                            LORD STAFFORD
                         <provenance notAfter="1885-07-28">
                            <p>Acquired by <name key="person_" role="fmo">
                                <persName type="display">Henry Valentine Stafford-Jerningham</persName>
                                <persName type="standard">Henry Valentine Stafford-Jerningham</persName>
                            </name> (b. 2 January 1802, d. 30 November 1884), 9th Baron Stafford by unknown means. </p>
                        </provenance>
                        
                        <provenance when="1885-07-28"><p>Purchased at the sale of items belonging to <name key="person_" role="fmo">
                            <persName type="display">Henry Valentine Stafford-Jerningham</persName>
                            <persName type="standard">Henry Valentine Stafford-Jerningham</persName>
                        </name>(b. 2 January 1802, d. 30 November 1884), 9th Baron Stafford at Christie’s, London, 28 July 1885, lot 51 by <name key="person_v64786305" role="fmo">
                                <persName type="display">Frank McClean (1837-1904)</persName>
                                <persName type="standard">Frank McClean, 1837-1904</persName>
                            </name>. </p>
                        </provenance>                         
                         
                           LORD STRAFFORD
                      <provenance notBefore="1806" notAfter="1885-07-28"><p>Acquired by <name key="" role="fmo"><persName>George Stevens Byng
                                        (1806-1886)</persName><persName type="standard">George Stevens Byng, 1806-1886</persName></name>, 2nd Earl of
                                Strafford (also styled Lord Strafford) by unknown means. </p></provenance>

                        <provenance when="1885-07-28"><p>Purchased at the sale of items belonging to George Stevens Byng, 2nd Earl of Strafford (also
                                styled Lord Strafford), Christie’s, London, 28 July 1885, lot 51 by <name key="person_v64786305" role="fmo">
                                    <persName type="display">Frank McClean (1837-1904)</persName>
                                    <persName type="standard">Frank McClean, 1837-1904</persName>
                                </name></p>
                        </provenance>
                        
                        -->

                        <acquisition when="1904">Bequeathed to the Fitzwilliam Museum by the British astronomer <name key="person_v64786305"
                                role="dnr">
                                <persName type="display">Frank McClean (1837-1904)</persName>
                                <persName type="standard">Frank McClean, 1837-1904</persName>
                            </name> in 1904. McClean bookplate present on f. <locus from="[a] verso" to="[a] verso">[a] verso</locus>
                        </acquisition>

                    </history>

                    <additional>
                        <adminInfo>
                            <recordHist>
                                <source>This catalogue entry draws on <bibl>M.R. James, <hi rend="italic">A descriptive catalogue of the McClean
                                            collection of manuscripts in the Fitzwilliam Museum</hi> (Cambridge, 1912), no. 89</bibl>
                                </source>
                            </recordHist>

                            <availability status="restricted">
                                <p>Visitors to the Fitzwilliam Museum who wish to consult Collection material are required to apply to the Museum in
                                    advance of their visit. For information on eligibility and admission procedures see: <ref
                                        target="https://fitzmuseum.cam.ac.uk/research/study-room">Fitzwilliam Museum: Study Room</ref>.</p>
                            </availability>


                        </adminInfo>

                        <listBibl type="WRAPPER">
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/JQ7UEBFL" type="book" xml:id="James1912">
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="m">A descriptive catalogue of the McClean collection of manuscripts in the Fitzwilliam
                                        museum</title>
                                    <author><forename>M.R.</forename><surname>James</surname></author>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
                                        <publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
                                        <date>1912</date>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                                <note>pp. 197-200 </note>
                            </biblStruct>
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/CNXP35MV" type="thesis" xml:id="Rogers1984">
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="m">Books of Hours produced in the Low Countries for the English market in the fifteenth
                                        century</title>
                                    <author><forename>Nicholas</forename><surname>Rogers</surname></author>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
                                        <date>1984</date>
                                        <note type="thesisType">M.Litt.</note>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                                <note>2 vols. </note>
                                <note>II.374 </note>
                            </biblStruct>
                        </listBibl>
                    </additional>

                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass default="false">
                <keywords scheme="#LCSH">
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <term key="subject_sh85062530">Book of Hours</term>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc status="draft">
            <change status="draft" when="20240725">2024-07-25: Draft catalogue record prepared by <persName>Dr Sarah Gilbert</persName>, Project
                Cataloguer for the Curious Cures in Cambridge Libraries project </change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <facsimile>
        <graphic decls="#document-thumbnail" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00001"/>
        <surface n="outside front cover" xml:id="page-surface-1">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00001"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="inside front cover" xml:id="page-surface-2">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00002"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="[a] recto" xml:id="page-surface-3">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00003"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="[a] verso" xml:id="page-surface-4">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00004"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="i recto" xml:id="page-surface-5">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00005"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="i verso" xml:id="page-surface-6">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00006"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="ii recto" xml:id="page-surface-7">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00007"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="ii verso" xml:id="page-surface-8">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6754px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00008"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="iii recto" xml:id="page-surface-9">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00009"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="iii verso" xml:id="page-surface-10">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00010"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="iv recto" xml:id="page-surface-11">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00011"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="iv verso" xml:id="page-surface-12">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00012"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="1r" xml:id="page-surface-13">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00013"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="1v" xml:id="page-surface-14">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00014"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="2r" xml:id="page-surface-15">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00015"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="2v" xml:id="page-surface-16">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00016"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="3r" xml:id="page-surface-17">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00017"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="3v" xml:id="page-surface-18">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00018"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="4r" xml:id="page-surface-19">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00019"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="4v" xml:id="page-surface-20">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00020"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="5r" xml:id="page-surface-21">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00021"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="5v" xml:id="page-surface-22">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00022"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="6r" xml:id="page-surface-23">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00023"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="6v" xml:id="page-surface-24">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00024"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="7r" xml:id="page-surface-25">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00025"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="7v" xml:id="page-surface-26">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00026"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="8r" xml:id="page-surface-27">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00027"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="8v" xml:id="page-surface-28">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00028"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="9r" xml:id="page-surface-29">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00029"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="9v" xml:id="page-surface-30">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00030"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="10r" xml:id="page-surface-31">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00031"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="10v" xml:id="page-surface-32">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00032"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="11r" xml:id="page-surface-33">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00033"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="11v" xml:id="page-surface-34">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00034"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="12r" xml:id="page-surface-35">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00035"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="12v" xml:id="page-surface-36">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00036"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="13r" xml:id="page-surface-37">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00037"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="13v" xml:id="page-surface-38">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00038"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="14r" xml:id="page-surface-39">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00039"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="14v" xml:id="page-surface-40">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00040"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="15r" xml:id="page-surface-41">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00041"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="15v" xml:id="page-surface-42">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00042"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="16r" xml:id="page-surface-43">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6828px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00043"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="16v" xml:id="page-surface-44">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00044"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="17r" xml:id="page-surface-45">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00045"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="17v" xml:id="page-surface-46">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00046"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="18r" xml:id="page-surface-47">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00047"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="18v" xml:id="page-surface-48">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00048"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="19r" xml:id="page-surface-49">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00049"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="19v" xml:id="page-surface-50">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00050"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="20r" xml:id="page-surface-51">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00051"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="20v" xml:id="page-surface-52">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00052"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="21r" xml:id="page-surface-53">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00053"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="21v" xml:id="page-surface-54">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00054"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="22r" xml:id="page-surface-55">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00055"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="22v" xml:id="page-surface-56">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00056"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="23r" xml:id="page-surface-57">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00057"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="23v" xml:id="page-surface-58">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00058"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="24r" xml:id="page-surface-59">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00059"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="24v" xml:id="page-surface-60">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00060"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="25r" xml:id="page-surface-61">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00061"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="25v" xml:id="page-surface-62">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00062"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="26r" xml:id="page-surface-63">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00063"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="26v" xml:id="page-surface-64">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00064"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="27r" xml:id="page-surface-65">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00065"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="27v" xml:id="page-surface-66">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00066"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="28r" xml:id="page-surface-67">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00067"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="28v" xml:id="page-surface-68">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00068"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="29r" xml:id="page-surface-69">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00069"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="29v" xml:id="page-surface-70">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00070"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="30r" xml:id="page-surface-71">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00071"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="30v" xml:id="page-surface-72">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00072"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="31r" xml:id="page-surface-73">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00073"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="31v" xml:id="page-surface-74">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00074"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="32r" xml:id="page-surface-75">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00075"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="32v" xml:id="page-surface-76">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6754px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00076"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="33r" xml:id="page-surface-77">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00077"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="33v" xml:id="page-surface-78">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00078"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="34r" xml:id="page-surface-79">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00079"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="34v" xml:id="page-surface-80">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00080"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="35r" xml:id="page-surface-81">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00081"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="35v" xml:id="page-surface-82">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00082"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="36r" xml:id="page-surface-83">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00083"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="36v" xml:id="page-surface-84">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00084"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="37r" xml:id="page-surface-85">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00085"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="37v" xml:id="page-surface-86">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00086"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="38r" xml:id="page-surface-87">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00087"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="38v" xml:id="page-surface-88">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00088"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="39r" xml:id="page-surface-89">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00089"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="39v" xml:id="page-surface-90">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00090"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="40r" xml:id="page-surface-91">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00091"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="40v" xml:id="page-surface-92">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00092"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="41r" xml:id="page-surface-93">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00093"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="41v" xml:id="page-surface-94">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00094"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="42r" xml:id="page-surface-95">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00095"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="42v" xml:id="page-surface-96">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00096"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="43r" xml:id="page-surface-97">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00097"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="43v" xml:id="page-surface-98">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00098"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="44r" xml:id="page-surface-99">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00099"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="44v" xml:id="page-surface-100">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00100"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="45r" xml:id="page-surface-101">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00101"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="45v" xml:id="page-surface-102">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6754px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00102"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="46r" xml:id="page-surface-103">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00103"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="46v" xml:id="page-surface-104">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00104"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="47r" xml:id="page-surface-105">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00105"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="47v" xml:id="page-surface-106">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00106"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="48r" xml:id="page-surface-107">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00107"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="48v" xml:id="page-surface-108">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00108"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="49r" xml:id="page-surface-109">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00109"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="49v" xml:id="page-surface-110">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00110"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="50r" xml:id="page-surface-111">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00111"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="50v" xml:id="page-surface-112">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00112"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="51r" xml:id="page-surface-113">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00113"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="51v" xml:id="page-surface-114">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00114"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="52r" xml:id="page-surface-115">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00115"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="52v" xml:id="page-surface-116">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00116"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="53r" xml:id="page-surface-117">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6753px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00117"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="53v" xml:id="page-surface-118">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00118"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="54r" xml:id="page-surface-119">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00119"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="54v" xml:id="page-surface-120">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00120"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="55r" xml:id="page-surface-121">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00121"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="55v" xml:id="page-surface-122">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00122"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="56r" xml:id="page-surface-123">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00123"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="56v" xml:id="page-surface-124">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00124"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="57r" xml:id="page-surface-125">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00125"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="57v" xml:id="page-surface-126">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00126"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="58r" xml:id="page-surface-127">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00127"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="58v" xml:id="page-surface-128">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00128"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="59r" xml:id="page-surface-129">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00129"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="59v" xml:id="page-surface-130">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00130"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="60r" xml:id="page-surface-131">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00131"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="60v" xml:id="page-surface-132">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00132"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="61r" xml:id="page-surface-133">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00133"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="61v" xml:id="page-surface-134">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00134"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="62r" xml:id="page-surface-135">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00135"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="62v" xml:id="page-surface-136">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00136"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="63r" xml:id="page-surface-137">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00137"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="63v" xml:id="page-surface-138">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00138"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="64r" xml:id="page-surface-139">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00139"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="64v" xml:id="page-surface-140">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00140"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="65r" xml:id="page-surface-141">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00141"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="65v" xml:id="page-surface-142">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00142"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="66r" xml:id="page-surface-143">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00143"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="66v" xml:id="page-surface-144">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00144"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="67r" xml:id="page-surface-145">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00145"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="67v" xml:id="page-surface-146">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00146"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="68r" xml:id="page-surface-147">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6754px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00147"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="68v" xml:id="page-surface-148">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00148"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="69r" xml:id="page-surface-149">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00149"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="69v" xml:id="page-surface-150">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00150"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="70r" xml:id="page-surface-151">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00151"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="70v" xml:id="page-surface-152">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00152"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="71r" xml:id="page-surface-153">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00153"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="71v" xml:id="page-surface-154">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00154"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="72r" xml:id="page-surface-155">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00155"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="72v" xml:id="page-surface-156">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00156"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="73r" xml:id="page-surface-157">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00157"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="73v" xml:id="page-surface-158">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00158"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="74r" xml:id="page-surface-159">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00159"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="74v" xml:id="page-surface-160">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00160"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="75r" xml:id="page-surface-161">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00161"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="75v" xml:id="page-surface-162">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00162"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="76r" xml:id="page-surface-163">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00163"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="76v" xml:id="page-surface-164">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00164"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="77r" xml:id="page-surface-165">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00165"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="77v" xml:id="page-surface-166">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00166"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="78r" xml:id="page-surface-167">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00167"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="78v" xml:id="page-surface-168">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00168"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="79r" xml:id="page-surface-169">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00169"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="79v" xml:id="page-surface-170">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00170"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="80r" xml:id="page-surface-171">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00171"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="80v" xml:id="page-surface-172">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00172"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="81r" xml:id="page-surface-173">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00173"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="81v" xml:id="page-surface-174">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00174"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="82r" xml:id="page-surface-175">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00175"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="82v" xml:id="page-surface-176">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00176"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="83r" xml:id="page-surface-177">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00177"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="83v" xml:id="page-surface-178">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00178"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="84r" xml:id="page-surface-179">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00179"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="84v" xml:id="page-surface-180">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00180"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="85r" xml:id="page-surface-181">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00181"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="85v" xml:id="page-surface-182">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00182"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="86r" xml:id="page-surface-183">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00183"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="86v" xml:id="page-surface-184">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00184"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="87r" xml:id="page-surface-185">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00185"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="87v" xml:id="page-surface-186">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00186"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="88r" xml:id="page-surface-187">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00187"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="88v" xml:id="page-surface-188">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00188"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="89r" xml:id="page-surface-189">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00189"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="89v" xml:id="page-surface-190">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00190"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="90r" xml:id="page-surface-191">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00191"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="90v" xml:id="page-surface-192">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00192"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="91r" xml:id="page-surface-193">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00193"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="91v" xml:id="page-surface-194">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00194"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="92r" xml:id="page-surface-195">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00195"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="92v" xml:id="page-surface-196">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00196"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="93r" xml:id="page-surface-197">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00197"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="93v" xml:id="page-surface-198">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00198"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="94r" xml:id="page-surface-199">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00199"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="94v" xml:id="page-surface-200">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00200"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="95r" xml:id="page-surface-201">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00201"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="95v" xml:id="page-surface-202">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00202"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="96r" xml:id="page-surface-203">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00203"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="96v" xml:id="page-surface-204">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00204"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="97r" xml:id="page-surface-205">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00205"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="97v" xml:id="page-surface-206">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00206"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="98r" xml:id="page-surface-207">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00207"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="98v" xml:id="page-surface-208">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00208"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="99r" xml:id="page-surface-209">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00209"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="99v" xml:id="page-surface-210">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00210"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="100r" xml:id="page-surface-211">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00211"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="100v" xml:id="page-surface-212">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00212"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="101r" xml:id="page-surface-213">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00213"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="101v" xml:id="page-surface-214">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00214"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="102r" xml:id="page-surface-215">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6754px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00215"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="102v" xml:id="page-surface-216">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00216"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="103r" xml:id="page-surface-217">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00217"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="103v" xml:id="page-surface-218">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00218"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="104r" xml:id="page-surface-219">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00219"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="104v" xml:id="page-surface-220">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00220"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="105r" xml:id="page-surface-221">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00221"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="105v" xml:id="page-surface-222">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00222"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="106r" xml:id="page-surface-223">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00223"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="106v" xml:id="page-surface-224">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00224"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="107r" xml:id="page-surface-225">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00225"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="107v" xml:id="page-surface-226">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00226"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="108r" xml:id="page-surface-227">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6754px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00227"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="108v" xml:id="page-surface-228">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00228"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="109r" xml:id="page-surface-229">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00229"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="109v" xml:id="page-surface-230">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00230"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="110r" xml:id="page-surface-231">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00231"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="110v" xml:id="page-surface-232">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00232"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="111r" xml:id="page-surface-233">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00233"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="111v" xml:id="page-surface-234">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00234"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="112r" xml:id="page-surface-235">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00235"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="112v" xml:id="page-surface-236">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00236"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="113r" xml:id="page-surface-237">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00237"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="113v" xml:id="page-surface-238">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00238"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="114r" xml:id="page-surface-239">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6754px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00239"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="114v" xml:id="page-surface-240">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00240"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="115r" xml:id="page-surface-241">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00241"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="115v" xml:id="page-surface-242">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00242"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="116r" xml:id="page-surface-243">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00243"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="116v" xml:id="page-surface-244">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00244"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="117r" xml:id="page-surface-245">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00245"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="117v" xml:id="page-surface-246">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00246"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="118r" xml:id="page-surface-247">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00247"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="118v" xml:id="page-surface-248">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00248"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="119r" xml:id="page-surface-249">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00249"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="119v" xml:id="page-surface-250">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00250"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="120r" xml:id="page-surface-251">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00251"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="120v" xml:id="page-surface-252">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00252"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="121r" xml:id="page-surface-253">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00253"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="121v" xml:id="page-surface-254">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00254"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="122r" xml:id="page-surface-255">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00255"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="122v" xml:id="page-surface-256">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00256"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="123r" xml:id="page-surface-257">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00257"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="123v" xml:id="page-surface-258">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00258"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="124r" xml:id="page-surface-259">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00259"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="124v" xml:id="page-surface-260">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00260"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="125r" xml:id="page-surface-261">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00261"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="125v" xml:id="page-surface-262">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00262"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="126r" xml:id="page-surface-263">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00263"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="126v" xml:id="page-surface-264">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00264"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="127r" xml:id="page-surface-265">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00265"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="127v" xml:id="page-surface-266">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00266"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="128r" xml:id="page-surface-267">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00267"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="128v" xml:id="page-surface-268">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00268"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="129r" xml:id="page-surface-269">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00269"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="129v" xml:id="page-surface-270">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00270"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="130r" xml:id="page-surface-271">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00271"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="130v" xml:id="page-surface-272">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00272"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="131r" xml:id="page-surface-273">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00273"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="131v" xml:id="page-surface-274">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00274"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="132r" xml:id="page-surface-275">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00275"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="132v" xml:id="page-surface-276">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00276"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="133r" xml:id="page-surface-277">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00277"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="133v" xml:id="page-surface-278">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00278"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="134r" xml:id="page-surface-279">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00279"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="134v" xml:id="page-surface-280">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00280"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="v recto" xml:id="page-surface-281">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00281"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="v verso" xml:id="page-surface-282">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00282"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="vi recto" xml:id="page-surface-283">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00283"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="vi verso" xml:id="page-surface-284">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00284"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="inside rear cover" xml:id="page-surface-285">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00285"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="outside rear cover" xml:id="page-surface-286">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6757px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00286"
                width="5335px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="spine" xml:id="page-surface-287">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="6755px" rend="portrait" url="MS-FITZWILLIAM-MCCLEAN-00089-000-00287"
                width="5313px"/>
        </surface>
    </facsimile>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-1" n="outside front cover" xml:id="page-pb-1"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-2" n="inside front cover" xml:id="page-pb-2"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-3" n="[a] recto" xml:id="page-pb-3"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-4" n="[a] verso" xml:id="page-pb-4"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-5" n="i recto" xml:id="page-pb-5"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-6" n="i verso" xml:id="page-pb-6"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-7" n="ii recto" xml:id="page-pb-7"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-8" n="ii verso" xml:id="page-pb-8"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-9" n="iii recto" xml:id="page-pb-9"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-10" n="iii verso" xml:id="page-pb-10"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-11" n="iv recto" xml:id="page-pb-11"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-12" n="iv verso" xml:id="page-pb-12"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-13" n="1r" xml:id="page-pb-13"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-14" n="1v" xml:id="page-pb-14"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-15" n="2r" xml:id="page-pb-15"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-16" n="2v" xml:id="page-pb-16"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-17" n="3r" xml:id="page-pb-17"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-18" n="3v" xml:id="page-pb-18"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-19" n="4r" xml:id="page-pb-19"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-20" n="4v" xml:id="page-pb-20"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-21" n="5r" xml:id="page-pb-21"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-22" n="5v" xml:id="page-pb-22"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-23" n="6r" xml:id="page-pb-23"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-24" n="6v" xml:id="page-pb-24"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-25" n="7r" xml:id="page-pb-25"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-26" n="7v" xml:id="page-pb-26"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-27" n="8r" xml:id="page-pb-27"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-28" n="8v" xml:id="page-pb-28"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-29" n="9r" xml:id="page-pb-29"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-30" n="9v" xml:id="page-pb-30"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-31" n="10r" xml:id="page-pb-31"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-32" n="10v" xml:id="page-pb-32"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-33" n="11r" xml:id="page-pb-33"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-34" n="11v" xml:id="page-pb-34"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-35" n="12r" xml:id="page-pb-35"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-36" n="12v" xml:id="page-pb-36"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-37" n="13r" xml:id="page-pb-37"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-38" n="13v" xml:id="page-pb-38"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-39" n="14r" xml:id="page-pb-39"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-40" n="14v" xml:id="page-pb-40"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-41" n="15r" xml:id="page-pb-41"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-42" n="15v" xml:id="page-pb-42"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-43" n="16r" xml:id="page-pb-43"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-44" n="16v" xml:id="page-pb-44"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-45" n="17r" xml:id="page-pb-45"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-46" n="17v" xml:id="page-pb-46"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-47" n="18r" xml:id="page-pb-47"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-48" n="18v" xml:id="page-pb-48"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-49" n="19r" xml:id="page-pb-49"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-50" n="19v" xml:id="page-pb-50"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-51" n="20r" xml:id="page-pb-51"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-52" n="20v" xml:id="page-pb-52"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-53" n="21r" xml:id="page-pb-53"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-54" n="21v" xml:id="page-pb-54"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-55" n="22r" xml:id="page-pb-55"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-56" n="22v" xml:id="page-pb-56"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-57" n="23r" xml:id="page-pb-57"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-58" n="23v" xml:id="page-pb-58"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-59" n="24r" xml:id="page-pb-59"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-60" n="24v" xml:id="page-pb-60"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-61" n="25r" xml:id="page-pb-61"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-62" n="25v" xml:id="page-pb-62"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-63" n="26r" xml:id="page-pb-63"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-64" n="26v" xml:id="page-pb-64"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-65" n="27r" xml:id="page-pb-65"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-66" n="27v" xml:id="page-pb-66"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-67" n="28r" xml:id="page-pb-67"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-68" n="28v" xml:id="page-pb-68"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-69" n="29r" xml:id="page-pb-69"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-70" n="29v" xml:id="page-pb-70"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-71" n="30r" xml:id="page-pb-71"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-72" n="30v" xml:id="page-pb-72"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-73" n="31r" xml:id="page-pb-73"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-74" n="31v" xml:id="page-pb-74"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-75" n="32r" xml:id="page-pb-75"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-76" n="32v" xml:id="page-pb-76"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-77" n="33r" xml:id="page-pb-77"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-78" n="33v" xml:id="page-pb-78"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-79" n="34r" xml:id="page-pb-79"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-80" n="34v" xml:id="page-pb-80"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-81" n="35r" xml:id="page-pb-81"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-82" n="35v" xml:id="page-pb-82"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-83" n="36r" xml:id="page-pb-83"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-84" n="36v" xml:id="page-pb-84"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-85" n="37r" xml:id="page-pb-85"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-86" n="37v" xml:id="page-pb-86"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-87" n="38r" xml:id="page-pb-87"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-88" n="38v" xml:id="page-pb-88"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-89" n="39r" xml:id="page-pb-89"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-90" n="39v" xml:id="page-pb-90"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-91" n="40r" xml:id="page-pb-91"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-92" n="40v" xml:id="page-pb-92"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-93" n="41r" xml:id="page-pb-93"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-94" n="41v" xml:id="page-pb-94"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-95" n="42r" xml:id="page-pb-95"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-96" n="42v" xml:id="page-pb-96"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-97" n="43r" xml:id="page-pb-97"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-98" n="43v" xml:id="page-pb-98"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-99" n="44r" xml:id="page-pb-99"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-100" n="44v" xml:id="page-pb-100"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-101" n="45r" xml:id="page-pb-101"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-102" n="45v" xml:id="page-pb-102"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-103" n="46r" xml:id="page-pb-103"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-104" n="46v" xml:id="page-pb-104"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-105" n="47r" xml:id="page-pb-105"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-106" n="47v" xml:id="page-pb-106"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-107" n="48r" xml:id="page-pb-107"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-108" n="48v" xml:id="page-pb-108"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-109" n="49r" xml:id="page-pb-109"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-110" n="49v" xml:id="page-pb-110"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-111" n="50r" xml:id="page-pb-111"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-112" n="50v" xml:id="page-pb-112"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-113" n="51r" xml:id="page-pb-113"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-114" n="51v" xml:id="page-pb-114"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-115" n="52r" xml:id="page-pb-115"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-116" n="52v" xml:id="page-pb-116"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-117" n="53r" xml:id="page-pb-117"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-118" n="53v" xml:id="page-pb-118"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-119" n="54r" xml:id="page-pb-119"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-120" n="54v" xml:id="page-pb-120"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-121" n="55r" xml:id="page-pb-121"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-122" n="55v" xml:id="page-pb-122"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-123" n="56r" xml:id="page-pb-123"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-124" n="56v" xml:id="page-pb-124"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-125" n="57r" xml:id="page-pb-125"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-126" n="57v" xml:id="page-pb-126"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-127" n="58r" xml:id="page-pb-127"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-128" n="58v" xml:id="page-pb-128"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-129" n="59r" xml:id="page-pb-129"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-130" n="59v" xml:id="page-pb-130"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-131" n="60r" xml:id="page-pb-131"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-132" n="60v" xml:id="page-pb-132"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-133" n="61r" xml:id="page-pb-133"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-134" n="61v" xml:id="page-pb-134"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-135" n="62r" xml:id="page-pb-135"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-136" n="62v" xml:id="page-pb-136"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-137" n="63r" xml:id="page-pb-137"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-138" n="63v" xml:id="page-pb-138"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-139" n="64r" xml:id="page-pb-139"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-140" n="64v" xml:id="page-pb-140"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-141" n="65r" xml:id="page-pb-141"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-142" n="65v" xml:id="page-pb-142"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-143" n="66r" xml:id="page-pb-143"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-144" n="66v" xml:id="page-pb-144"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-145" n="67r" xml:id="page-pb-145"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-146" n="67v" xml:id="page-pb-146"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-147" n="68r" xml:id="page-pb-147"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-148" n="68v" xml:id="page-pb-148"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-149" n="69r" xml:id="page-pb-149"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-150" n="69v" xml:id="page-pb-150"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-151" n="70r" xml:id="page-pb-151"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-152" n="70v" xml:id="page-pb-152"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-153" n="71r" xml:id="page-pb-153"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-154" n="71v" xml:id="page-pb-154"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-155" n="72r" xml:id="page-pb-155"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-156" n="72v" xml:id="page-pb-156"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-157" n="73r" xml:id="page-pb-157"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-158" n="73v" xml:id="page-pb-158"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-159" n="74r" xml:id="page-pb-159"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-160" n="74v" xml:id="page-pb-160"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-161" n="75r" xml:id="page-pb-161"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-162" n="75v" xml:id="page-pb-162"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-163" n="76r" xml:id="page-pb-163"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-164" n="76v" xml:id="page-pb-164"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-165" n="77r" xml:id="page-pb-165"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-166" n="77v" xml:id="page-pb-166"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-167" n="78r" xml:id="page-pb-167"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-168" n="78v" xml:id="page-pb-168"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-169" n="79r" xml:id="page-pb-169"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-170" n="79v" xml:id="page-pb-170"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-171" n="80r" xml:id="page-pb-171"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-172" n="80v" xml:id="page-pb-172"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-173" n="81r" xml:id="page-pb-173"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-174" n="81v" xml:id="page-pb-174"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-175" n="82r" xml:id="page-pb-175"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-176" n="82v" xml:id="page-pb-176"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-177" n="83r" xml:id="page-pb-177"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-178" n="83v" xml:id="page-pb-178"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-179" n="84r" xml:id="page-pb-179"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-180" n="84v" xml:id="page-pb-180"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-181" n="85r" xml:id="page-pb-181"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-182" n="85v" xml:id="page-pb-182"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-183" n="86r" xml:id="page-pb-183"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-184" n="86v" xml:id="page-pb-184"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-185" n="87r" xml:id="page-pb-185"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-186" n="87v" xml:id="page-pb-186"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-187" n="88r" xml:id="page-pb-187"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-188" n="88v" xml:id="page-pb-188"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-189" n="89r" xml:id="page-pb-189"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-190" n="89v" xml:id="page-pb-190"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-191" n="90r" xml:id="page-pb-191"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-192" n="90v" xml:id="page-pb-192"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-193" n="91r" xml:id="page-pb-193"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-194" n="91v" xml:id="page-pb-194"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-195" n="92r" xml:id="page-pb-195"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-196" n="92v" xml:id="page-pb-196"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-197" n="93r" xml:id="page-pb-197"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-198" n="93v" xml:id="page-pb-198"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-199" n="94r" xml:id="page-pb-199"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-200" n="94v" xml:id="page-pb-200"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-201" n="95r" xml:id="page-pb-201"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-202" n="95v" xml:id="page-pb-202"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-203" n="96r" xml:id="page-pb-203"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-204" n="96v" xml:id="page-pb-204"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-205" n="97r" xml:id="page-pb-205"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-206" n="97v" xml:id="page-pb-206"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-207" n="98r" xml:id="page-pb-207"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-208" n="98v" xml:id="page-pb-208"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-209" n="99r" xml:id="page-pb-209"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-210" n="99v" xml:id="page-pb-210"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-211" n="100r" xml:id="page-pb-211"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-212" n="100v" xml:id="page-pb-212"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-213" n="101r" xml:id="page-pb-213"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-214" n="101v" xml:id="page-pb-214"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-215" n="102r" xml:id="page-pb-215"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-216" n="102v" xml:id="page-pb-216"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-217" n="103r" xml:id="page-pb-217"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-218" n="103v" xml:id="page-pb-218"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-219" n="104r" xml:id="page-pb-219"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-220" n="104v" xml:id="page-pb-220"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-221" n="105r" xml:id="page-pb-221"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-222" n="105v" xml:id="page-pb-222"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-223" n="106r" xml:id="page-pb-223"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-224" n="106v" xml:id="page-pb-224"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-225" n="107r" xml:id="page-pb-225"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-226" n="107v" xml:id="page-pb-226"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-227" n="108r" xml:id="page-pb-227"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-228" n="108v" xml:id="page-pb-228"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-229" n="109r" xml:id="page-pb-229"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-230" n="109v" xml:id="page-pb-230"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-231" n="110r" xml:id="page-pb-231"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-232" n="110v" xml:id="page-pb-232"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-233" n="111r" xml:id="page-pb-233"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-234" n="111v" xml:id="page-pb-234"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-235" n="112r" xml:id="page-pb-235"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-236" n="112v" xml:id="page-pb-236"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-237" n="113r" xml:id="page-pb-237"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-238" n="113v" xml:id="page-pb-238"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-239" n="114r" xml:id="page-pb-239"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-240" n="114v" xml:id="page-pb-240"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-241" n="115r" xml:id="page-pb-241"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-242" n="115v" xml:id="page-pb-242"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-243" n="116r" xml:id="page-pb-243"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-244" n="116v" xml:id="page-pb-244"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-245" n="117r" xml:id="page-pb-245"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-246" n="117v" xml:id="page-pb-246"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-247" n="118r" xml:id="page-pb-247"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-248" n="118v" xml:id="page-pb-248"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-249" n="119r" xml:id="page-pb-249"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-250" n="119v" xml:id="page-pb-250"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-251" n="120r" xml:id="page-pb-251"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-252" n="120v" xml:id="page-pb-252"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-253" n="121r" xml:id="page-pb-253"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-254" n="121v" xml:id="page-pb-254"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-255" n="122r" xml:id="page-pb-255"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-256" n="122v" xml:id="page-pb-256"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-257" n="123r" xml:id="page-pb-257"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-258" n="123v" xml:id="page-pb-258"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-259" n="124r" xml:id="page-pb-259"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-260" n="124v" xml:id="page-pb-260"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-261" n="125r" xml:id="page-pb-261"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-262" n="125v" xml:id="page-pb-262"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-263" n="126r" xml:id="page-pb-263"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-264" n="126v" xml:id="page-pb-264"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-265" n="127r" xml:id="page-pb-265"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-266" n="127v" xml:id="page-pb-266"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-267" n="128r" xml:id="page-pb-267"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-268" n="128v" xml:id="page-pb-268"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-269" n="129r" xml:id="page-pb-269"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-270" n="129v" xml:id="page-pb-270"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-271" n="130r" xml:id="page-pb-271"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-272" n="130v" xml:id="page-pb-272"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-273" n="131r" xml:id="page-pb-273"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-274" n="131v" xml:id="page-pb-274"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-275" n="132r" xml:id="page-pb-275"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-276" n="132v" xml:id="page-pb-276"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-277" n="133r" xml:id="page-pb-277"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-278" n="133v" xml:id="page-pb-278"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-279" n="134r" xml:id="page-pb-279"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-280" n="134v" xml:id="page-pb-280"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-281" n="v recto" xml:id="page-pb-281"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-282" n="v verso" xml:id="page-pb-282"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-283" n="vi recto" xml:id="page-pb-283"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-284" n="vi verso" xml:id="page-pb-284"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-285" n="inside rear cover" xml:id="page-pb-285"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-286" n="outside rear cover" xml:id="page-pb-286"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-287" n="spine" xml:id="page-pb-287"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
