<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/msDesc/consolidated-tei-schema/master/msdesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/msDesc/consolidated-tei-schema/master/msdesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="manuscript_1">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Cambridge, Peterhouse, MS 251</title>
                <funder>Wellcome</funder>
                <principal>James Freeman</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Cambridge University Library</publisher>

                <availability status="restricted" xml:id="displayImageRights">
                    <p>Zooming image © University Library, All rights reserved.</p>
                </availability>
                <availability status="restricted" xml:id="downloadImageRights">
                    <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/">Images made available for download are licensed under a Creative
                        Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 3.0 Unported License (CC BY-NC 3.0)</licence>
                </availability>
                <availability status="restricted" xml:id="metadataRights">
                    <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/">This metadata is licensed under a Creative Commons
                        Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivs 3.0 Unported License.</licence>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="watermark" status="restricted">
                    <licence>Peterhouse, Cambridge (CC BY-NC 4.0)</licence>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <msDesc xml:id="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251" xml:lang="en">

                    <msIdentifier>
                        <institution>Peterhouse</institution>
                        <repository>Perne Library: on long-term deposit at Cambridge University Library</repository>
                        <collection>Medieval Manuscripts</collection>
                        <idno type="shelfmark">Cambridge, Peterhouse, MS 251</idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <head>Medical compendium</head>

                    <msContents>
                        <summary>
                            <seg type="para">This manuscript is a composite volume with its Parts deriving from 9 separate original sources written in
                                England and Italy between the 11th and 15th centuries. Part 1 is a set of medieval endleaves with notes, annotations,
                                and lists of the contents, Parts 2-8 contain medical treatises in Latin, and Part 9 is another set of medieval
                                endleaves that preserve damaged copies of letters from a Carmelite foundation in England as well as a number of
                                smaller and more informal annotations. </seg>
                            <seg type="para">Peterhouse MS 251 appears to have reached its current composite form after two distinct phases of
                                compilation, the first of which seems to have brought together Parts 1-7, and the second of which seems to have added
                                Parts 8-9 to Parts 1-7. Precisely how and when Peterhouse MS 251 Parts 1-7 were brought together is unknown, but they
                                seem to have been together by <date when="1330-12-08">8 December 1330</date>, the date of a <hi rend="italic"
                                    >Caucio</hi> note on f. <locus from="i verso" to="i verso">i verso</locus> (a medieval endleaf). This note is
                                partly illegible due to rubbing, but the remaining text can be read as 'Caucio Walteri de Wasten exponitur ciste
                                Batulfi <unclear>...</unclear> concepionis beate Marie anno Domini M<hi rend="superscript">o</hi> CCC<hi
                                    rend="superscript">o</hi> xxx', i.e., the book was pledged as surety for a loan and placed in Botolph's chest on 8
                                December 1330 by Walter de Wasten. <hi rend="italic">Caucio</hi> inscriptions in manuscripts reflect a practice common
                                (but not limited) to Oxford and Cambridge in the 14th and 15th centuries, where borrowers could pledge books or other
                                high-value items in exchange for a monetary loan. The lender would add a description of the loan to the item (or
                                presumably add a label to non-codex pledges) usually beginning with the word 'Caucio' or 'Cautio' (pledge/security)
                                followed by details such as the date, the amount loaned, and the original owner of the item, and would then store the
                                deposit in a chest for the duration of the loan, which borrowers could redeem on repayment. The loan chests and their
                                funds were often initially supplied by a single benefactor, and the chest that they endowed usually bore their name
                                thereafter. In this example, 'ciste Batulfi' is probably a reference to 'St Botoloph's Chest', which was established
                                by Thomas de St Botolph, parson of South Dalton in Yorkshire and personal clerk to John le Romeyn (d. 1296),
                                archbishop of York. Thomas was still alive in 1293 and the chest was probably founded at some point afterwards. It
                                operated until at least 1347. If this identification is correct, it places at least some parts of Peterhouse MS 251 in
                                Cambridge in 1330. The <hi rend="italic">Caucio</hi> inscription on f. <locus from="i verso" to="i verso">i
                                    verso</locus> is briefly discussed in Thomson's <hi rend="italic">Catalogue</hi>, p. 158; Thomson does not mention
                                the location of Botolph's Chest in Cambridge, but he makes a Cambridge connection for the <hi rend="italic"
                                    >Caucio</hi> inscription as he suggests that 'Walteri de Wasten' may be the Walter de Weston in Emden <hi
                                    rend="italic">BRUC</hi>, p. 631, a cleric of Cambridge who complained about the violence from the mayor and
                                townspeople of Cambridge in 1322 as recorded in <hi rend="italic">Calendar of the Patent Rolls preserved in the Public
                                    Record Office 1216-1509</hi> (1891-1916). </seg>
                            <seg type="para">Underneath the <hi rend="italic">Caucio</hi> inscription on f. <locus from="i verso" to="i verso">i
                                    verso</locus> and in a late 14th- or 15th-century hand is a medieval list of the contents of the volume. This
                                enumerates 12 items, the final one of which - 'liber de ffebribus' - was added by another, probably 15th-century hand
                                and almost certainly refers to the texts on ff. <locus from="106r" to="191v">106-191</locus> (i.e., Part 8). The work
                                now known as Galen's <hi rend="italic">Ad glauconem de medendi methodo</hi> (not to be confused with the larger
                                Galenic text now known as the <hi rend="italic">Therapeutica</hi> or <hi rend="italic">De methodo medendi</hi>, which
                                in the Middle Ages was usually known as the <hi rend="italic">Ars magna</hi> or the <hi rend="italic">Megategni</hi>),
                                was a treatise on fevers addressed to Galen's nephew or friend Glauco(n), and was often known in the Middle Ages by
                                the title 'Liber de febribus' or 'De febribus ad Glauconem'. On folio <locus from="106r" to="106r">106r</locus>, in
                                the upper margin, a late 14th or early 15th century hand has also added a title for the text,'liber de ffebribus'. The
                                last original entry in the medieval list of the contents then is 'Pronostica ypocratis incompletus', which seems to be
                                a reference to the <hi rend="italic">Prognostica</hi> of Hippocrates on ff. <locus from="102v" to="105r"
                                    >102v-105r</locus>, which is complete, but which is immediately followed by an incomplete copy of Theophilus' <hi
                                    rend="italic">De urinis</hi>, which begins near the bottom of a column of text on f. 105r with a rubric similar in
                                size and distinction to the internal subheadings in the preceding text. As such, it seems to have been read by the
                                main compiler of the medieval list of the contents of the volume as an incomplete final section of the <hi
                                    rend="italic">Prognostica</hi>. </seg>
                            <seg type="para">It seems likely that Parts 8-9 joined Parts 1-7 at Peterhouse during the 15th century. Part 9 is a
                                medieval bifolium that preserves copies of two letters by a single scribe, one of which is dated to 1400 in the text.
                                Part 9 is badly damaged through rubbing and use as a pastedown and endleaves, but in addition to the copies of the
                                letters, it also preserves several informal annotations including names and accompanying 15th century dates. It is
                                possible that Part 9 was added by itself to the volume, perhaps for a late 15th-century or 16th-century rebinding, but
                                given that the 'liber de ffebribus' entry in the medieval table of contents on f. <locus from="i verso" to="i verso">i
                                    verso</locus> is in a different (?15th century) hand, it seems probable that Parts 8 and 9 were joined to Parts
                                1-7 in the 15th century, with Part 8 added due to the similarity of its content to Parts 2-7 and Part 9 as a
                                protective wrapper for the new end of the volume. </seg>
                            <seg type="para">A portion of the manuscript (almost certainly Parts 1-7) were given to Peterhouse in <date when="1385"
                                    >1385</date> by <name key="person_" role="dnr">
                                    <persName type="display">William Irby</persName>
                                    <persName type="standard">William Irby</persName>
                                </name>, a Fellow of Peterhouse; Irby's donation is recorded in the upper margin of f. <locus from="1r" to="1r"
                                    >1r</locus> - 'Memorandum quod magister Willelmus Irby socius domus Sancti Petri contulit istum librum eidem domui
                                anno Domini MCCC lxxxv<hi rend="superscript">to</hi>' (Memorandum that master William Irby fellow of Peterhouse
                                brought this book to the same house in A.D. 1385). Parts 8 and 9 must have joined the rest of the volume after Parts
                                1-7 had been absorbed into the Peterhouse library collection, and so it seems likely that Parts 8 and 9 were also
                                donated by a member of the Peterhouse community. </seg>
                            <seg type="para">All of the Parts of this manuscript are interesting in their own right as well as when they are
                                considered in their composite arrangement, but Dr Debby Banham has discussed the specific significance of Part 8 (ff.
                                    <locus from="106r" to="191v">106r-191v</locus> for the study of the history of medicine in England, and in
                                particular within the context of the reception of Classical medical texts in medieval England. Dr Banham described the
                                contents of Part 8 as 'the nearest thing to a standard medical textbook in early medieval Europe', i.e., for the study
                                of medicine in Europe before it became a profession studied and researched at the new universities. Dr Banham has also
                                pointed out that Peterhouse MS 251, ff. <locus from="106r" to="191v">106r-191v</locus> contains the 'earliest
                                surviving English manuscript of Galen's <hi rend="italic">Ad Glauconem de methodo medendi</hi>, and also of the
                                pseudo-Galenic <hi rend="italic">Liber tertius</hi> which travels with it, and of the <hi rend="italic">Libri
                                    Aurelii</hi> and <hi rend="italic">Esculapii</hi>, two works frequently found with the Galen complex, as here.'
                                Although the origin of Part 8 has not been established with total certainty, in all likelihood, Peterhouse MS 251 Part
                                8 (ff. <locus from="106r" to="191v">106r-191v</locus>) was copied at the abbey of St Augustine's in Canterbury, and
                                the quires are emblematic of a new style of medical study and enquiry in England that was to become a feature of the
                                standard of scientific learning available at the wealthiest monastic houses in England in the 12th and 13th centuries. </seg>
                            <seg type="para">Dr Sarah Gilbert<lb/> Project Cataloguer for the Curious Cures Project<lb/> Cambridge University
                                Library</seg>
                            <seg type="para">
                                <hi rend="bold">References</hi>: <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>CPR: <hi rend="italic">Calendar of the Patent Rolls preserved in the Public Record Office 1216-1509</hi>, 54
                                        vols (1891-1916)</bibl>
                                    <bibl>Graham Pollard, 'Medieval loan chests at Camrbidge', <hi rend="italic">Historical Research</hi> 17 (1940),
                                        113-160</bibl>
                                    <bibl>BRUC: A. B. Emden, <hi rend="italic">A Biographical Register of the University of Cambridge to 1500</hi>
                                        (Cambridge, 1963)</bibl>
                                    <bibl>P. Kibre, I. A. Kelter, 'Galen's "Methodus medendi" in the Middle Ages', <hi rend="italic">History and
                                            Philosophy of the Life Sciences</hi> 9.1 (1987), pp. 17-36</bibl>
                                    <bibl>D. Banham, 'Medicine at Bury in the Time of Abbot Baldwin', in <hi rend="italic">Bury St Edmunds and the
                                            Norman Conquest</hi>, ed. by T. Licence (Boydell &amp; Brewer, 2014), pp. 226–46, esp. pp. 227-228</bibl>
                                    <bibl>R. M. Thomson, <hi rend="italic">A Descriptive Catalogue of the Medieval Manuscripts in the Library of
                                            Peterhouse, Cambridge</hi> (2016)</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </seg>
                        </summary>

                    </msContents>



                    <physDesc>

                        <p>
                            <secFol>
                                <locus from="2r" to="2r">2r</locus>: apparet ei colorano </secFol>
                        </p>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc material="perg">
                                <support> All medieval leaves parchment; modern handmade-paper pastedowns and endleaves added in 2023. </support>

                                <extent>
                                    <seg type="object">Codex: </seg>
                                    <seg type="leaf">
                                        <measure quantity="2" type="laterEndleaf">ii</measure> + <measure quantity="2" type="endleaf">2</measure> |
                                            <measure quantity="6" type="leaf">6</measure> | <measure quantity="5" type="leaf">5</measure> | <measure
                                            quantity="15" type="leaf">15</measure> | <measure quantity="22" type="leaf">22</measure> | <measure
                                            quantity="43" type="leaf">43</measure> | <measure quantity="14" type="leaf">14</measure> | <measure
                                            quantity="86" type="leaf">86</measure> + <measure quantity="2" type="endleaf">2</measure> + <measure
                                            quantity="2" type="laterEndleaf">ii</measure> leaves. </seg>
                                </extent>

                                <foliation notAfter="2000" notBefore="1900">
                                    <p>20th century foliation</p>
                                    <p>[a]-[b] + [ia] recto - i | 1-6 | 7-11 | 12-26 | 27-48 | 49-91 | 92-105 | 106-191 | 192-[193] + [c]-[d]</p>
                                    <note>Foliated in the upper outer corner of each recto in pencil in Hindu-Arabic numerals, ff. i + 1-192. The
                                        outermost medieval parchment flyleaves (ff. [ia] and [193] were pastedowns until <date when="2023-09"
                                            >September 2023</date> and as such were not included in the folio designation scheme present in the
                                        volume; these leaves have been assigned temporary designations in order to produce a functional TEI-XML
                                        catalogue record, and those designtions are enclosed in [square brackets] throughout this record. The modern
                                        handmade paper flyleaves added to the beginning and end of the volume as part of the 2023 conservation and
                                        rebinding work have been assigned temporary designations ff. [a]-[b] and ff. [c]-[d] respectively. Note that
                                        the modern paper endleaves ff. [a]-[b] and [c]-[d] do not appear in the digital image set for Peterhouse MS
                                        251. </note>
                                </foliation>


                                <collation mainStructures="8 6"> A composite manuscript comprised of nine originally separate parts arranged in the
                                    following way: <list>
                                        <item>Medieval parchment bifolium (ff. <locus from="[ia] recto" to="i verso">[ia]-i</locus>) | </item>
                                        <item>Quire 1<hi rend="superscript">8-2</hi> (ff. <locus from="1r" to="6v">1r-6v</locus>; 1st and 7th leaves
                                            cancelled) | </item>
                                        <item>Quire 2<hi rend="superscript">8-3</hi> (ff. <locus from="7r" to="11v">7-11</locus>; 1st missing, 7th and
                                            8th leaves cancelled) | </item>
                                        <item>Quire 3<hi rend="superscript">10</hi> (ff. <locus from="12r" to="21v">12-21</locus>) </item>
                                        <item>Quire 4<hi rend="superscript">6-2(+1)</hi> (ff. <locus from="22r" to="26v">22-26</locus>; 5th and 6th
                                            leaves missing, a mutilated singleton after the 4th extant leaf) |</item>
                                        <item>Quires 5-6<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> (ff. <locus from="27r" to="42v">27-42</locus>)</item>
                                        <item>Quire 7<hi rend="superscript">6</hi> (ff. <locus from="43r" to="48v">43-48</locus>) |</item>
                                        <item>Quires 8-12<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> (ff. <locus from="49r" to="88v">49-88</locus>)</item>
                                        <item>Quire 13<hi rend="superscript">4-1</hi> (ff. <locus from="89r" to="91v">89-91</locus>; 4th leaf missing)
                                            |</item>
                                        <item>Quire 14<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> (ff. <locus from="92r" to="99v">92-99</locus>)</item>
                                        <item>Quire 15<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> (ff. <locus from="100r" to="105v">100-105</locus>; 7th and 8th
                                            leaves missing)|</item>
                                        <item>Quire 16<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> (ff. <locus from="106r" to="113v">106-113</locus>)</item>
                                        <item>Quire 17<hi rend="superscript">6</hi> (ff. <locus from="114r" to="119v">114-119</locus>)</item>
                                        <item>Quires 18-26<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> (ff. <locus from="120r" to="191v">120-191</locus>) |</item>
                                        <item>Medieval parchment bifolium (ff. <locus from="192r" to="[193] verso">192-[193]</locus>) </item>
                                    </list>
                                    <formula> Medieval endleaves ff. [ia]-i | 1<hi rend="superscript">8-2</hi> (1st and 7th cancelled) | 2<hi
                                            rend="superscript">8-3</hi> (1st missing, 7th and 8th cancelled) | 3<hi rend="superscript">10</hi> 4<hi
                                            rend="superscript">6-2(+1)</hi> (5th and 6th missing, a mutilated singleton after the 4th extant leaf) |
                                            5-6<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> 7<hi rend="superscript">6</hi> | 8-12<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> 13<hi
                                            rend="superscript">4-1</hi> (4th missing) | 14<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> 15<hi rend="superscript"
                                            >8</hi> (7th and 8th missing) | 16<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> 17<hi rend="superscript">6</hi> 18-26<hi
                                            rend="superscript">8</hi> | medieval endleaves ff. 192-[193] </formula>
                                    <signatures type="leaf"><p>No leaf signatures common to the entire manuscript. </p></signatures>
                                    <signatures type="quire"><p>Quires have 20th century alphabetical designations in pencil in the lower outer corner
                                            of the first recto of each quire: a-i, k-t, v, x-z, aa-cc.</p>
                                    </signatures>
                                    <catchwords><seg type="para">No catchwords common to the entire manuscript. </seg></catchwords>
                                </collation>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>

                        <additions>
                            <note>
                                <p>A note on f. <locus from="i recto" to="i recto">i recto</locus>, partially erased: 'liber florum et Regularum
                                    Magistri aflaticii de monte pesulano breuiter gyl[?]'. The note refers to the text on ff. <locus from="27r"
                                        to="48v">27r-48v</locus>, which is attributed to a Magister Afratisius/Alfacius of Monte Pesulano
                                    (Montpellier) in the incipits and explicits supplied with the text now known as the <hi rend="italic"
                                        >Practica</hi> sometimes attributed to Copho.</p>
                            </note>
                        </additions>

                        <bindingDesc>
                            <binding notBefore="2023-09">
                                <p>Rebound in September 2023 by James Cassels. Tawed goat skin over quarter-sawn oak boards. Two silver pin-and-ring
                                    fore edge fastenings with tawed goatskin and vellum straps. Four raised bands on <locus from="spine" to="spine"
                                        >spine</locus>; double linen cords fitted to the medieval sewing stations. Head and tail bands of linen and
                                    finished with decorative sewing of alternate blue and cream segments. </p>
                                <p>Handmade paper <locus from="inside left cover" to="inside left cover">pastedowns</locus> pasted over the turn ins.
                                    Two handmade paper endleaves (unphotographed) added at each end of the volume, ff. [a]-[b] and [c]-[d]
                                    respectively, all blank. </p>
                                <p>Medieval parchment pastedowns lifted; the newly free leaves assigned the designations ff. [ia] and [163]
                                    respectively. </p>
                                <p>Peterhouse MS 251 is now stored in an archival box made from acid free mill board, covered with archival buckram,
                                    and lined with museum board. The box also contains an archival folder which contains the remains of the 18th
                                    century binding and a printed description by James Cassels of the conservation and rebinding work undertaken in
                                    2023. </p>
                                <p>Binding dimensions (L x W x D): 255 x 180 x 55 mm</p>
                            </binding>
                            <binding notAfter="2023-09" notBefore="1700">
                                <p>18th century binding preserved in an archival folder stored in the manuscript box after the September 2023
                                    rebinding. Undecorated parchment cover over thin rope fibre boards. Boards attached to text block by laced in
                                    cords glued into 3 deep saw-cuts across the spine.</p>
                                <p>List of the contents of the volume written in ink on the spine in an 18th century hand, now badly rubbed and
                                    partially illegible. A former ?shelfmark or designation in ink on the in the same hand as the 18th century list of
                                    the contents on the spine: '2-5-2'. Faint note in pencil 'James 210' for the catalogue number of this volume in
                                    the <hi rend="italic">Ecloga</hi> of Thomas James (1600). Small printed paper label fixed to spine bearing the
                                    shelfmark designation '251'.</p>
                            </binding>
                            <binding notAfter="1800">
                                <p>Traces of pre-18th century binding(?s) still visible in the volume. </p>
                                <p>Four raised bands made for an earlier binding visible on spine; double-twisted tawed leather supports cut at the
                                    joints. </p>
                                <p>Traces of fittings for a former fastening or chain staple visible in the centre of the tail edge of ff. <locus
                                        from="[ia] recto" to="i verso">[ia]-i</locus> and <locus from="192r" to="[193] verso">192-[193]</locus>. </p>
                            </binding>
                        </bindingDesc>
                    </physDesc>

                    <history>
                        <acquisition cert="medium" when="1385"> Some Parts of this manuscript (probably Parts 1-7) given by fellow of Peterhouse,
                            William (de) Irby (Venn ACAD no. IRBY374W) in 1385. The donation is recorded on f. <locus from="1r" to="1r">1r</locus>:
                                <q>Memorandum quod magister Willelmus Irby socius domus Sancti Petri contulit istum librum eidem domui anno Domini
                                MCCC lxxxv<hi rend="superscript">to</hi></q> (Memorandum that master William Irby fellow of Peterhouse brought this
                            book to the same house in A.D. 1385). Parts 8 and 9 probably added after 1400 through an unknown donation. </acquisition>
                    </history>

                    <additional>
                        <adminInfo>

                            <recordHist>
                                <source>This catalogue entry draws on M. R. James, <hi rend="italic">A descriptive catalogue of the manuscripts in the
                                        library of Peterhouse</hi> (1899), and R. M. Thomson, <hi rend="italic">A Descriptive Catalogue of the
                                        Medieval Manuscripts in the Library of Peterhouse, Cambridge</hi> (2016) by kind permission of the author.
                                    Readers of this record are encouraged to consult Thomson's <hi rend="italic">Catalogue</hi> for further
                                    information about this manuscript.</source>
                            </recordHist>

                            <availability status="restricted">
                                <p>The manuscripts of Peterhouse are stored on long-term deposit at Cambridge University Library. Readers wishing to
                                    consult a Peterhouse manuscript in-person will need to visit the University Library. Entry to read in Cambridge
                                    University Library is permitted only on presentation of a valid reader's card. For information on eligibility and
                                    admissions procedures, see <ref target="https://www.lib.cam.ac.uk/using-library/joining-library">Joining the
                                        Library</ref>). For further information on the availability of the manuscript, please contact the <ref
                                        target="mss@lib.cam.ac.uk">Manuscripts Reading Room</ref>.</p>
                            </availability>

                            <custodialHist>
                                <custEvent when="1418-12-24">Recorded in the catalogue of Peterhouse books for 24 December 1418. See CBMLC vol. 10,
                                    UC48.291. </custEvent>
                            </custodialHist>
                        </adminInfo>

                        <listBibl type="WRAPPER">
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/MGHK5HIU" type="book" xml:id="James1899">
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="m">A descriptive catalogue of the manuscripts in the library of Peterhouse</title>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>M. R.</forename>
                                        <surname>James</surname>
                                    </author>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
                                        <publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
                                        <date>1899</date>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                                <note>pp. 307-310</note>
                            </biblStruct>
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/M98ZHR83" type="journalArticle" xml:id="Creutz1941">
                                <analytic>
                                    <title level="a">Der Magister Copho und seine Stellung im Hochsalerno Aus M. p. med. Q 2 (saec. XIII) fol. 85 a
                                        -103 a Würzburg</title>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>Rudolf</forename>
                                        <surname>Creutz</surname>
                                    </author>
                                </analytic>
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="j">Sudhoffs Archiv für Geschichte der Medizin und der Naturwissenschaften</title>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
                                        <biblScope unit="issue">5/6</biblScope>
                                        <biblScope unit="page">249-338</biblScope>
                                        <date>1941</date>
                                        <note type="url">https://www.jstor.org/stable/20774081</note>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                            </biblStruct>
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/IRACR2XX" type="journalArticle" xml:id="Bishop1955">
                                <analytic>
                                    <title level="a">Notes on Cambridge Manuscripts, Part II</title>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>T.A.M.</forename>
                                        <surname>Bishop</surname>
                                    </author>
                                </analytic>
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="j">Transactions of the Cambridge Bibliographical Society</title>
                                    <idno type="ISSN">0068-6611</idno>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
                                        <biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
                                        <biblScope unit="page">185-192</biblScope>
                                        <date>1955</date>
                                        <note type="url">http://www.jstor.org/stable/41154356</note>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                                <note>p. 189 </note>
                            </biblStruct>
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/4VZ7SQBD" type="journalArticle" xml:id="Bishop1959">
                                <analytic>
                                    <title level="a">Notes on Cambridge manuscripts, Part V: MSS. connected with St Augustine's Canterbury,
                                        Continued</title>
                                    <title type="short">Notes on Cambridge Manuscripts V (cont'd)</title>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>T.A.M.</forename>
                                        <surname>Bishop</surname>
                                    </author>
                                </analytic>
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="j">Transactions of the Cambridge Bibliographical Society</title>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
                                        <biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
                                        <biblScope unit="page">93-95</biblScope>
                                        <date>1959</date>
                                        <note type="url">https://www.jstor.org/stable/41154383</note>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                                <note>p. 95</note>
                            </biblStruct>
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/Z3G93NSX" type="bookSection" xml:id="Lawrence1982">
                                <analytic>
                                    <title level="a">Manuscripts of early Anglo-Norman Canterbury</title>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>A.</forename>
                                        <surname>Lawrence</surname>
                                    </author>
                                </analytic>
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="m">Medieval art and architecture of Canterbury before 1220</title>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <pubPlace>s.l.</pubPlace>
                                        <biblScope unit="page">101-111</biblScope>
                                        <publisher>British Archaeological Association</publisher>
                                        <date>1982</date>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                                <series>
                                    <title level="s">British Archaeological Association Conference Transactions</title>
                                    <biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
                                </series>
                                <note>p. 102</note>
                            </biblStruct>
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/I2DT23L3" type="journalArticle" xml:id="Cameron1990">
                                <analytic>
                                    <title level="a">Bald's Leechbook and cultural interactions in Anglo-Saxon England</title>
                                    <idno type="DOI">10.1017/S0263675100001563</idno>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>M. L.</forename>
                                        <surname>Cameron</surname>
                                    </author>
                                </analytic>
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="j">Anglo-Saxon England</title>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
                                        <biblScope unit="page">5-12</biblScope>
                                        <date>1990</date>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                                <note>pp. 162-63 and nn. 38-42 </note>
                            </biblStruct>
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/UI9GPY7V" type="book" xml:id="Cameron1993">
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="m">Anglo-Saxon medicine.</title>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>M.L.</forename>
                                        <surname>Cameron</surname>
                                    </author>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
                                        <publisher>University Press</publisher>
                                        <date>1993</date>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                                <series>
                                    <title level="s">Cambridge studies in Anglo-Saxon England</title>
                                    <biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
                                </series>
                                <note>p. 71 and n. 21 </note>
                            </biblStruct>
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/D4R2PTK2" type="bookSection" xml:id="Eales1995">
                                <analytic>
                                    <title level="a">English manuscript art in the late eleventh century: Canterbury and its context</title>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>Richard</forename>
                                        <surname>Gameson</surname>
                                    </author>
                                </analytic>
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="m">Canterbury and the Norman conquest: churches, saints, and scholars, 1066-1109</title>
                                    <editor>
                                        <forename>R. G.</forename>
                                        <surname>Eales</surname>
                                    </editor>
                                    <editor>
                                        <forename>Richard</forename>
                                        <surname>Sharpe</surname>
                                    </editor>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
                                        <biblScope unit="page">95-144</biblScope>
                                        <publisher>Hambledon Press</publisher>
                                        <date>1995</date>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                                <note>p. 102 n. 28</note>
                            </biblStruct>
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/R53ST4F5" type="book" xml:id="Gameson1999">
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="m">The manuscripts of early Norman England (c.1066-1130)</title>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>Richard</forename>
                                        <surname>Gameson</surname>
                                    </author>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <pubPlace>Oxford</pubPlace>
                                        <publisher>Published for the British Academy by Oxford University Press</publisher>
                                        <date>1999</date>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                                <note>no. 117 </note>
                            </biblStruct>
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/JYM2YPVP" type="book" xml:id="Langslow2006">
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="m">The Latin Alexander Trallianus: the text and transmission of a late Latin medical book</title>
                                    <title type="short">The Latin Alexander Trallianus</title>
                                    <idno type="ISBN">978-0-907764-32-8</idno>
                                    <idno type="callNumber">B A3.7 4, T520.b.3.410</idno>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>D.R.</forename>
                                        <surname>Langslow</surname>
                                    </author>
                                    <respStmt>
                                        <resp>contributor</resp>
                                        <persName>
                                            <forename>of Tralles</forename>
                                            <surname>Alexander</surname>
                                        </persName>
                                    </respStmt>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
                                        <publisher>Society for the Promotion of Roman Studies</publisher>
                                        <date>2006</date>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                                <series>
                                    <title level="s">Journal of Roman studies monographs</title>
                                    <biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
                                </series>
                                <note>p. 89 n. 100, 93</note>
                            </biblStruct>
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/MY7GD8K7" type="bookSection" xml:id="Lendinara2007">
                                <analytic>
                                    <title level="a">Instructional manuscripts in England: the tenth- and eleventh-century codices and the early
                                        Norman ones</title>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>Patrizia</forename>
                                        <surname>Lendinara</surname>
                                    </author>
                                </analytic>
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="m">Form and content of instruction in Anglo-Saxon England in the light of contemporary manuscript
                                        evidence: papers presented at the international conference, Udine, 6-8 April 2006</title>
                                    <idno type="ISBN">978-2-503-52591-4</idno>
                                    <idno type="callNumber">E 199 LEN, Z.5.LEN, 240:2.c.200.1137</idno>
                                    <editor>
                                        <forename>Patrizia</forename>
                                        <surname>Lendinara</surname>
                                    </editor>
                                    <editor>
                                        <forename>Loredana</forename>
                                        <surname>Lazzari</surname>
                                    </editor>
                                    <editor>
                                        <forename>M. A.</forename>
                                        <surname>D'Aronco</surname>
                                    </editor>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <pubPlace>Turnhout</pubPlace>
                                        <biblScope unit="page">59-113</biblScope>
                                        <publisher>Brepols</publisher>
                                        <date>2007</date>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                                <series>
                                    <title level="s">Textes et études du moyen âge</title>
                                    <biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
                                </series>
                                <note>pp. 102, 113 </note>
                            </biblStruct>
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/D78XCBBX" type="book" xml:id="Barker-Benfield2008">
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="m">St Augustine's Abbey, Canterbury</title>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>B.C.</forename>
                                        <surname>Barker-Benfield</surname>
                                    </author>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
                                        <publisher>British Library in association with the British Academy</publisher>
                                        <date>2008</date>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                                <series>
                                    <title level="s">Corpus of British medieval library catalogues</title>
                                    <biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
                                </series>
                                <note>pp. 516, 1230, 1261, 1820 </note>
                            </biblStruct>
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/VTJREGSP" type="book" xml:id="Gameson2008">
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="m">The earliest books of Canterbury Cathedral: manuscripts and fragments to c.1200</title>
                                    <title type="short">The earliest books of Canterbury Cathedral</title>
                                    <idno type="ISBN">978-0-7123-5008-2</idno>
                                    <idno type="callNumber">LL 119 G 103</idno>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>Richard</forename>
                                        <surname>Gameson</surname>
                                    </author>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
                                        <publisher>Bibliographical Society</publisher>
                                        <date>2008</date>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                                <note>pp. 192, 203-04</note>
                            </biblStruct>
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/P3I55LWX" type="book" xml:id="Morgan2013">
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="m">A catalogue of western book illumination in the Fitzwilliam Museum and the Cambridge
                                        colleges</title>
                                    <editor>
                                        <forename>Nigel</forename>
                                        <surname>Morgan</surname>
                                    </editor>
                                    <editor>
                                        <forename>Stella</forename>
                                        <surname>Panayotova</surname>
                                    </editor>
                                    <respStmt>
                                        <resp>contributor</resp>
                                        <persName>
                                            <forename>Rebecca</forename>
                                            <surname>Rushforth</surname>
                                        </persName>
                                    </respStmt>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
                                        <biblScope unit="volume">1: Insular and Anglo-Saxon manuscripts, c. 700-c. 1100</biblScope>
                                        <publisher>Harvey Miller</publisher>
                                        <date>2013</date>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                                <series>
                                    <title level="s">Illuminated manuscripts in Cambridge</title>
                                    <biblScope unit="volume">4: The British Isles</biblScope>
                                </series>
                                <note>cited cat. nos. 58, 63</note>
                            </biblStruct>
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/KCC37QDG" type="book" xml:id="Gneuss2014">
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="m">Anglo-Saxon manuscripts: a bibliographical handlist of manuscripts and manuscript fragments
                                        written or owned in England up to 1100</title>
                                    <title type="short">Anglo-Saxon manuscripts</title>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>Helmut</forename>
                                        <surname>Gneuss</surname>
                                    </author>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>Michael</forename>
                                        <surname>Lapidge</surname>
                                    </author>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <pubPlace>Toronto</pubPlace>
                                        <publisher>University of Toronto Press</publisher>
                                        <date>2014</date>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                                <series>
                                    <title level="s">Toronto Anglo-Saxon series</title>
                                    <biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
                                </series>
                                <note>no. 145</note>
                            </biblStruct>
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/FLCX862U" type="bookSection" xml:id="Banham2014">
                                <analytic>
                                    <title level="a">Medicine at Bury in the Time of Abbot Baldwin</title>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>Debby</forename>
                                        <surname>Banham</surname>
                                    </author>
                                </analytic>
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="m">Bury St Edmunds and the Norman Conquest</title>
                                    <editor>
                                        <forename>Tom</forename>
                                        <surname>Licence</surname>
                                    </editor>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <biblScope unit="page">226-246</biblScope>
                                        <publisher>Boydell &amp; Brewer</publisher>
                                        <date>2014</date>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                                <note>pp. 227-228 </note>
                            </biblStruct>
                            <biblStruct corresp="http://zotero.org/groups/276440/items/5W9ZZKNM" type="thesis" xml:id="Knight2015">
                                <monogr>
                                    <title level="m">The De podagra (On Gout): a pre-Gariopontean treatise excerpted from the Latin translation of the
                                        Greek Therapeutica by Alexander of Tralles</title>
                                    <author>
                                        <forename>Valerie</forename>
                                        <surname>Knight</surname>
                                    </author>
                                    <imprint>
                                        <pubPlace>Manchester</pubPlace>
                                        <date>2015</date>
                                        <note type="url">https://pure.manchester.ac.uk/ws/portalfiles/portal/54569823/FULL_TEXT.PDF</note>
                                        <note type="thesisType">PhD</note>
                                    </imprint>
                                </monogr>
                            </biblStruct>
                        </listBibl>

                    </additional>

                    <msPart n="1">
                        <msIdentifier>
                            <idno>Cambridge, Peterhouse MS 251, ff. [ia]-i</idno>
                            <msName>Part 1 - medieval flyleaves</msName>

                        </msIdentifier>

                        <msContents>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>

                            <msItem n="1">
                                <locus from="i verso" to="i verso">i verso</locus>
                                <title key="">Caucio note</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <note><p>Full transcription: 'Caucio Walteri de Wasten exponitur ciste Batulfi <unclear>...</unclear> concepionis
                                        beate Marie anno Domini M CCC xxx'. See Provenance for further discussion. </p></note>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="2">
                                <locus from="i verso" to="i verso">i verso</locus>
                                <title key="">Note on medieval weights and measures</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="3">
                                <locus from="i verso" to="i verso">i verso</locus>
                                <title key="">Medieval list of the contents of the volume</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <note><p> Full transcription:<lb/> In hoc libro continentur <lb/> Quedam expo super pronostica ypocratis <lb/> Versus
                                        super pulsus egidii incompleti <lb/> Tractatus de urinis glossatus <lb/> Quidam tractatus cuiusdam magister de
                                        montepessulano <lb/> Quoddam commentum <unclear>optimum</unclear> super Iohannitum <lb/>
                                            Co<unclear>nstantinum</unclear> super aphorismos ypocratis secundum eundem <lb/> Constantinum super urinas
                                        teophili secundum eundem <lb/> Commentum super librum pulsuum philareti <lb/> Ysagogi Iohanitii ad tegni
                                        Galieni <lb/> Aphorismi ypocratis <lb/> Pronostica ypocratis incompletus <lb/> Liber de ffebribus </p>
                                    <p>Part of the entry for 'Pronostica ypocratis incompletus' is overwritten in another medieval hand, this hand
                                        also added 'Liber de ffebribus' to the end of the list. </p></note>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="4">
                                <locus from="i verso" to="i verso">i verso</locus>
                                <title key="">List of the contents of the volume in an early modern hand</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <note>
                                    <p> Petrus Musandia in prognostica Hippocr. Hunc quod de Musandina vocat <lb/>
                                        <add place="margin">imperfect .</add> Ægidius Monachus Bened. <unclear>...</unclear> de pulsibus .x.
                                            <unclear>...</unclear>
                                        <lb/> Tract. de urina cum com. <lb/> Afratitius de Monte pessulano de morbis . <lb/> Joanicii <hi
                                            rend="strikethrough">introductio in</hi> Galeni artem paruam cum co. <lb/> Aphorismi Hippocr. cum com.
                                        <lb/> Com. in Theophilum de vrinis <lb/> Com. im Philaretum de pulsibus <lb/> Joanicii Isagogi sine com. <lb/>
                                        Aphor. Hippocr. <lb/> Progn. Hippocr. <lb/> Theophilus de urinis <unclear>sine</unclear> co.<lb/> De morbis
                                        Libri sex. </p>
                                </note>
                            </msItem>

                        </msContents>



                        <physDesc>
                            <objectDesc form="codex">
                                <supportDesc material="perg">
                                    <support>
                                        <material>Parchment (<term type="disposition">FHHF</term>)</material>
                                    </support>
                                    <extent>
                                        <seg type="object">Codex: </seg>
                                        <seg type="leaf">
                                            <measure quantity="2" type="endleaf">2</measure>2 parchment endleaves. </seg>
                                    </extent>

                                    <collation>
                                        <p>Medieval parchment bifolium (ff. <locus from="[ia] recto" to="i verso">[ia]-i</locus>) </p>
                                        <signatures type="leaf"><p>No leaf signatures particular to this Part. </p></signatures>
                                        <signatures type="quire"><p>No quire signatures particular to this Part. </p></signatures>
                                        <catchwords><seg type="para">No catchwords particular to this Part. </seg></catchwords>
                                    </collation>

                                    <condition> Folio <locus from="[ia] recto" to="[ia] verso">[ia]</locus> was a pastedown until September 2023 when
                                        it was lifted and repaired as part of conservation and rebinding work undertaken by James Cassels. The text on
                                        f. <locus from="[ia] recto" to="[ia] recto">[ia] recto</locus> is difficult to read due to rubbing and
                                        adhesive residue. Repair to f. <locus from="[ia] recto" to="[ia] verso">[ia]</locus> by Cassels in 2023 using
                                        strong Japanese paper. </condition>

                                </supportDesc>

                                <layoutDesc>
                                    <layout><p>
                                            <seg type="ruling"> Folios <locus from="[ia] recto" to="i verso">[ia]- i</locus> have an informal and
                                                unruled mise-en-page. </seg></p>
                                    </layout>
                                </layoutDesc>
                            </objectDesc>

                            <handDesc>
                                <handNote>
                                    <p>Endleaf annotations by several hands dating from the 13th-18th centuries. </p>
                                </handNote>
                            </handDesc>

                            <decoDesc>
                                <decoNote type="none">
                                    <p>No significant decorative features in this Part. </p>
                                </decoNote>
                            </decoDesc>


                            <additions>
                                <p>Folio <locus from="[ia] recto" to="[ia] recto">[ia] recto</locus>: illegible text including some medical notes in
                                    at least two hands, probably datable to the 13th century. Text badly damaged due to the use of this leaf as a
                                    pastedown in the pre-2023 binding. </p>
                                <p>Folio <locus from="[ia] verso" to="[ia] verso">[ia] verso</locus> contains: <list>
                                        <item>A note, 'M R James 251' in pencil</item>
                                        <item>'James 210' in ink - this refers to the manuscript's designation in the <hi rend="italic">Ecloga
                                                Oxonio-Cantabrigiensis</hi> by Thomas James (1600).</item>
                                    </list></p>
                                <p>Folio <locus from="i recto" to="i recto">i recto</locus> contains a faded tabular diagram and a small string tie
                                    pierced through the centre of the fore edge, probably part of a medieval bookmark.</p>
                                <p>Folio <locus from="i verso" to="i verso">i verso</locus> contains a 'Caucio' inscription, see the Provenance
                                    section for the volume for further discussion. </p>
                            </additions>

                            <bindingDesc>
                                <binding notAfter="1800">
                                    <p>Evidence of a metal fastening on a pre-18th century binding visible as damage and metal-oxide staining along
                                        the tail edge of ff. <locus from="[ia] recto" to="i verso">[ia]- i</locus>. </p>
                                </binding>
                            </bindingDesc>
                        </physDesc>

                        <history>
                            <origin>
                                <origDate calendar="Gregorian" cert="high" notAfter="1330" notBefore="1150"> The oldest annotations on these leaves
                                    probably date from the 13th century or perhaps the late 12th. The <hi rend="italic">Caucio</hi> inscription on f.
                                        <locus from="i verso" to="i verso">i verso</locus> is dated '1330' and so ff. <locus from="[ia] recto"
                                        to="i verso">[ia]- i</locus> were almost certainly with some of the remainder of the volume as endleaves by
                                    that date. </origDate>
                                <origPlace cert="high" key="place_g7002445"> Probably written in England. There is a <hi rend="italic">Caucio</hi>
                                    inscription on f. <locus from="i verso" to="i verso">i verso</locus> which refers to a loan chest located in
                                    Cambridge. </origPlace>
                            </origin>

                            <provenance when="1330-12-08">
                                <p>A note on f. <locus from="i verso" to="i verso">i verso</locus>, badly rubbed: 'Caucio Walteri de Wasten exponitur
                                    ciste Batulfi <unclear>...</unclear> concepionis beate Marie anno Domini M<hi rend="superscript">o</hi> CCC<hi
                                        rend="superscript">o</hi> xxx', i.e., the book was pledged as surety for a loan and placed in Botolph's chest
                                    on 8 December 1330 by Walter de Wasten. <hi rend="italic">Caucio</hi> inscriptions in manuscripts reflect a
                                    practice common (but not limited) to Oxford and Cambridge in the 14th and 15th centuries where borrowers could
                                    pledge books or other high-value items in exchange for a monetary loan supplied by a lender who would store the
                                    manuscript in a chest for the duration of the loan. The loan chests and their funds were often supplied by a
                                    single benefactor whose name became associated with the chest long after their death and became incorporated into
                                    the <hi rend="italic">Caucio</hi> inscriptions usually in the form 'ciste [name]'; in this case, the 'ciste
                                    Batulfi' probably refers to a loan-chest in Cambridge known as 'Botoloph's Chest', which, if that identification
                                    is correct, places at least some parts of Peterhouse MS 251 in Cambridge in December 1330. 'Botolph's Chest' was
                                    supposedly endowed by a Thomas de St Botolph, chaplain to John Le Romeyn, archbishop of York, see Fuller and
                                    Billingfield, 'Section IV' in <hi rend="italic">The History of the University of Cambridge</hi>, esp. p. 130. </p>
                                <p>This <hi rend="italic">Caucio</hi> note is briefly discussed in Thomson's <hi rend="italic">Catalogue</hi>, p. 158;
                                    Thomson suggests that 'Walteri de Wasten' may be the Walter de Weston in Emden <hi rend="italic">BRUC</hi>, p.
                                    631, a cleric of Cambridge who complained about the violence from the mayor and townspeople of Cambridge in 1322
                                    as recorded in <hi rend="italic">Calendar of the Patent Rolls preserved in the Public Record Office
                                    1216-1509</hi>, 54 vols (1891-1916). </p>
                                <p>The <hi rend="italic">Caucio</hi> note is also briefly discussed in CBMLC 10 UC48.291 where the note is transcribed
                                    as follows: 'Caucio Walter de Kasten exspositus ciste Botulph' Concepionis beate Marie anno Domini M<hi
                                        rend="superscript">o</hi> ccc<hi rend="superscript">o</hi> xxx'</p>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>T. Fuller and R. Billingfield, ‘SECTION IV’, in M. Prickett and T. Wright (eds.), <hi rend="italic">The
                                            History of the University of Cambridge: From the Conquest to the Year 1634</hi>, (Cambridge, rpr 2009),
                                        pp. 126–42 </bibl>
                                    <bibl>R. M. Thomson, <hi rend="italic">A Descriptive Catalogue of the Medieval Manuscripts in the Library of
                                            Peterhouse, Cambridge</hi> (2016)</bibl>
                                    <bibl>BRUC: A. B. Emden, <hi rend="italic">A Biographical Register of the University of Cambridge to 1500</hi>
                                        (Cambridge, 1963)</bibl>
                                    <bibl>CPR: <hi rend="italic">Calendar of the Patent Rolls preserved in the Public Record Office 1216-1509</hi>, 54
                                        vols (1891-1916)</bibl>
                                    <bibl>CBMLC 10 UC48.291</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </provenance>
                        </history>

                    </msPart>

                    <msPart n="2">
                        <msIdentifier>
                            <idno>Cambridge, Peterhouse MS 251, ff. 1r-6v</idno>
                            <msName>Part 2 (Thomson Part I)</msName>

                        </msIdentifier>

                        <msContents>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>

                            <msItem n="1">
                                <locus from="1r" to="6v">1r-6v</locus>
                                <title key="work_6468">Commentary on Hippocrates, Prognostica [Latin]</title>
                                <author key="person_v7777663">Petrus Musandius</author>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <rubric>
                                    <locus from="1r" to="1r">1r</locus> Incipit commentum super Pronostica secundum Petrum Musandia </rubric>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="1r" to="1r">1r</locus> Quoniam humana corpora</incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="6v" to="6v">6v</locus> quia hec sunt certiora signa</explicit>
                                <finalRubric>
                                    <locus from="6v" to="6v">6v</locus> Explicit liber pronosticorum Ypocratis</finalRubric>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>eTK ?1277D ?1619N</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>
                        </msContents>

                        <physDesc>
                            <p><secFol>
                                    <locus from="2r" to="2r">2r</locus> apparet ei coloratio</secFol>
                            </p>

                            <objectDesc form="codex">
                                <supportDesc material="perg">
                                    <support>
                                        <material>Parchment (<term type="disposition">HFFH</term>).</material>
                                    </support>

                                    <extent>
                                        <seg type="object">Codex: </seg>
                                        <seg type="leaf">
                                            <measure quantity="6" type="leaf">6</measure> leaves. </seg>
                                        <seg type="dimensions">
                                            <dimensions type="leaf" unit="mm">
                                                <height quantity="240">240</height>
                                                <width quantity="160">170</width>
                                            </dimensions>
                                        </seg>
                                    </extent>

                                    <collation mainStructures="8">
                                        <p>
                                            <list>
                                                <item>Quire 1<hi rend="superscript">8-2</hi> (ff. <locus from="1r" to="6v">1-6</locus>; 1st and 7th
                                                    leaves cancelled)</item>
                                            </list>
                                        </p>
                                    </collation>

                                    <condition> Thick parchment. </condition>

                                </supportDesc>

                                <layoutDesc>
                                    <layout columns="2" rulingMedium="leadpoint" topLine="above" writtenLines="53">
                                        <dimensions type="written" unit="mm">
                                            <height quantity="195">195</height>
                                            <width quantity="120">120</width>
                                        </dimensions>
                                        <seg type="ruling"> Ruled in double-column format in (faint) leadpoint, frame and lines. Typically 53 lines to
                                            the column, written above top line. </seg>
                                    </layout>
                                </layoutDesc>


                            </objectDesc>

                            <handDesc>
                                <handNote script="minusculeCaroline">
                                    <p>Written in a late and compressed Caroline minuscule of Italian appearance. </p>
                                </handNote>
                            </handDesc>

                            <decoDesc>
                                <decoNote type="flourInit">
                                    <p>Opening initial on f. <locus from="1r" to="1r">1r</locus> is a gold initial with red flourishing. Other major
                                        initials are blue with red flourishing.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                                <decoNote type="plainInit">
                                    <p>Minor initials plain; red or blue</p>
                                </decoNote>
                                <decoNote type="rubrication"><p>Rubrication (red only) for chapter headings.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                                <decoNote type="other"><p>Paraphs in red or blue touched with red.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                            </decoDesc>

                        </physDesc>

                        <history>
                            <origin>
                                <origDate calendar="Gregorian" cert="medium" notAfter="1225" notBefore="1150"> Written in the second half of the 12th
                                    century, or perhaps early 13th century. Date of origin suggested based on palaeographical features. </origDate>
                                <origPlace cert="medium" key="place_g1000080">Probably written in Italy. Place of origin suggested based on
                                    palaeographical features. </origPlace>
                            </origin>
                        </history>

                    </msPart>

                    <msPart n="3">
                        <msIdentifier>
                            <idno>Cambridge, Peterhouse MS 251, ff. 7-11</idno>
                            <msName>Part 3 (Thomson Part II)</msName>

                        </msIdentifier>

                        <msContents>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>

                            <msItem n="1">
                                <locus from="7r" to="11r">7r-11r</locus>
                                <title key="work_1748">De pulsibus with gloss [Latin]</title>
                                <author key="person_v71543640">Aegidius Corbeiensis (Giles of Corbeil)</author>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <incipit defective="true">
                                    <locus from="7r" to="7r">7r</locus> cum relique species aliquo mediante ligentur</incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="11r" to="11r">11r</locus> Iam sterilis cultum Philareti nominis horret</explicit>
                                <finalRubric>
                                    <locus from="11r" to="11r">11r</locus> Explicit liber pulsuum Egidii</finalRubric>
                                <note>
                                    <p>Prologue (eTK 820) added in single-column format in a blank space after the final rubric on f. <locus
                                            from="11r" to="11r">11r</locus>. </p>
                                    <p>Additions in later (?14th century) hands in empty spaces on ff. <locus from="11r" to="11v">11rv</locus>. </p>
                                    <p>Text edited (not from this MS) by L. Choulant (Leipzing, 1828), pp. 21-43. </p></note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>eTK 744</bibl>
                                    <bibl>WIC 9332</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>
                        </msContents>

                        <physDesc>
                            <p><secFol>
                                    <locus from="8r" to="8r">8r</locus>: Spumum feruor uis</secFol>
                            </p>
                            <objectDesc form="codex">
                                <supportDesc material="perg">
                                    <support>
                                        <material>Parchment (<term type="disposition">HFFH</term>).</material>
                                    </support>

                                    <extent>
                                        <seg type="object">Codex: </seg>
                                        <seg type="leaf">
                                            <measure quantity="5" type="leaf">5</measure> leaves. </seg>
                                        <seg type="dimensions">
                                            <dimensions type="leaf" unit="mm">
                                                <height quantity="240">240</height>
                                                <width quantity="160">170</width>
                                            </dimensions>
                                        </seg>
                                    </extent>

                                    <collation mainStructures="8">
                                        <p>
                                            <list>
                                                <item>Quire 2<hi rend="superscript">8-3</hi> (ff. <locus from="7r" to="11v">7-11</locus>; 1st missing,
                                                    7th and 8th leaves cancelled) </item>
                                            </list>
                                        </p>
                                    </collation>

                                    <condition> Text is a little rubbed and difficult to read in places. Large brown stain and small tear on f. <locus
                                            from="9r" to="9r">9r</locus>. </condition>

                                </supportDesc>

                                <layoutDesc>
                                    <layout columns="1" rulingMedium="leadpoint" topLine="above" writtenLines="36">
                                        <dimensions type="written" unit="mm">
                                            <height quantity="165">165</height>
                                            <width quantity="60">60</width>
                                        </dimensions>
                                        <seg type="ruling"> Written in a single narrow column in the typical later medieval format for metrical texts.
                                            Ruled in leadpoint, frame and lines, main text is typically 36 lines to the page, written above top line.
                                            Text has an interlinear gloss, and occasional marginal glosses. </seg>
                                    </layout>
                                </layoutDesc>
                            </objectDesc>

                            <handDesc>
                                <handNote script="textualisSouthern">
                                    <p>Written in a southern European <term type="script">textualis rotunda</term> bookhand.</p>
                                </handNote>
                            </handDesc>

                        </physDesc>

                        <history>
                            <origin>
                                <origDate calendar="Gregorian" cert="medium" notAfter="1300" notBefore="1200">Probably written in the 13th century.
                                    Date of origin suggested based on palaeographical features. </origDate>
                                <origPlace cert="medium" key="place_g1000080">Probably written in Italy. Place of origin suggested based on
                                    palaeographical features. </origPlace>
                            </origin>

                        </history>
                    </msPart>

                    <msPart n="4">
                        <msIdentifier>
                            <idno>Cambridge, Peterhouse MS 251, ff. 12r-26v</idno>
                            <msName>Part 4 (Thomson Part III)</msName>

                        </msIdentifier>

                        <msContents>

                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>

                            <msItem n="1">
                                <locus from="12r" to="25v">12r-26r</locus>
                                <title key="work_7387">Commentary on Giles of Corbeil's De urinis [Latin]</title>
                                <author key="person_v98417711">?Gentilis Fulginas (d. 1348)</author>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <rubric>
                                    <locus from="12r" to="12r">12r</locus> Hic incipit tractatus urinarum </rubric>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="12r" to="12r">12r</locus> Dicitur urina quia formatur generatur et discernitur et si est primo
                                    substantiam et colorem </incipit>
                                <explicit defective="true">
                                    <locus from="26r" to="26r">26r</locus> tenuem substantiam singnificat dolorem in sinistro latere pocius habundare
                                    quam in dextro </explicit>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>eTK 0422E</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="2">
                                <locus from="26r" to="26v">26rv</locus>
                                <title>Medical notes</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <incipit defective="true">
                                    <locus from="26r" to="26r">26r</locus> ad queritur <unclear>ss</unclear> ex succus plantus succi serpentarum
                                    sanguis alius oleum uiolaceum </incipit>
                                <explicit defective="true">
                                    <locus from="26v" to="26v">26v</locus> ita dicit que<unclear>d ana</unclear>
                                </explicit>
                                <note><p>Notes in different contemporary hands. </p></note>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="3">
                                <locus from="26v" to="26v">26v</locus>
                                <title>Note about a legal dispute</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="26v" to="26v">26v</locus>
                                    <unclear reason="rubbing">...</unclear> excipiendo proposuit contra bartolomeum le noreys exceptioni rei judicate </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="26v" to="26v">26v</locus> contra beneficiatum </explicit>
                                <note><p>Description of a legal process against a Bartolomeus le Noreys where he pleaded benefit of the clergy. See
                                        Thomson (2016). </p></note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>Thomson, <hi rend="italic">Peterhouse</hi> (2016), no. 251</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>
                        </msContents>



                        <physDesc>
                            <p><secFol>
                                    <locus from="13r" to="13r">13r</locus>: Lauacrum . ad differentiam balneorum </secFol>
                            </p>
                            <objectDesc form="codex">
                                <supportDesc material="perg">

                                    <support>
                                        <material>Parchment (<term type="disposition">HFFH</term>).</material>
                                    </support>

                                    <extent>
                                        <seg type="object">Codex: </seg>
                                        <seg type="leaf">
                                            <measure quantity="15" type="leaf">15</measure> leaves. </seg>
                                        <seg type="dimensions">
                                            <dimensions type="leaf" unit="mm">
                                                <height quantity="240">240</height>
                                                <width max="170" min="165">165-170</width>
                                            </dimensions>
                                        </seg>
                                    </extent>



                                    <collation mainStructures="10 6">
                                        <p>
                                            <list>
                                                <item>Quire 3<hi rend="superscript">10</hi> (ff. <locus from="12r" to="21v">12-21</locus>) </item>
                                                <item>Quire 4<hi rend="superscript">6-2(+1)</hi> (ff. <locus from="22r" to="26v">22-26</locus>; 5th
                                                    and 6th leaves missing, a mutilated singleton after the 4th extant leaf)</item>
                                            </list>
                                        </p>
                                    </collation>

                                    <condition> Folio 26 is a tipped-in leaf that has been mutilated; the middle third (dividing the leaf horizontally
                                        into 3) has been cut away with losses to text on the remaining upper-third of the leaf. </condition>
                                </supportDesc>

                                <layoutDesc>
                                    <layout columns="1" rulingMedium="leadpoint" topLine="above" writtenLines="42">
                                        <dimensions type="written" unit="mm">
                                            <height quantity="200">200</height>
                                            <width quantity="120">120</width>
                                        </dimensions>
                                        <seg type="ruling"> Ruled in pencil, in single-column format, frame and lines. Typically 42 lines to the page,
                                            written above top line. </seg>
                                    </layout>
                                </layoutDesc>


                            </objectDesc>

                            <handDesc>
                                <handNote script="textualisSouthern">
                                    <p>Written in a southern European <term type="script">textualis rotunda</term> bookhand.</p>
                                </handNote>
                            </handDesc>

                            <decoDesc>
                                <decoNote type="plainInit">
                                    <p>Plain red initial at the opening of the text on f. <locus from="12r" to="12r">12r</locus></p>
                                </decoNote>
                                <decoNote type="other">
                                    <p>Occasional paraph marks and occasional underlining for emphasis in red.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                            </decoDesc>
                        </physDesc>

                        <history>
                            <origin>
                                <origDate calendar="Gregorian" cert="medium" notAfter="1300" notBefore="1250"> Probably written in the second half of
                                    the 13th century. Date of origin suggested based on palaeographical features. </origDate>
                                <origPlace cert="medium" key="place_g1000080">Probably written in Italy. Place of origin suggested based on
                                    palaeographical features. </origPlace>
                            </origin>

                        </history>
                    </msPart>

                    <msPart n="5">
                        <msIdentifier>
                            <idno>Cambridge, Peterhouse MS 251, ff. 27r-48v</idno>
                            <msName>Part 5 (Thomson Part IV)</msName>

                        </msIdentifier>

                        <msContents>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>

                            <msItem n="1">
                                <locus from="27r" to="48v">27r-48v</locus>
                                <title>Practica</title>
                                <author>?Copho</author>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <rubric>
                                    <locus from="27r" to="27r">27r</locus> Incipit liber <sic>frorum</sic> et regularum a magistro Afratisio de Monte
                                    Pesulano colectarum et complehenssarum breuiter </rubric>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="27r" to="27r">27r</locus> Cum unius cuiusque humani corporis natura iiii ad sui conseruationem exigat
                                    humores </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="48r" to="48r">48r</locus> puluis fuliginis piretri ana dimidium i succi ciclaminis et olei quod .s. </explicit>
                                <finalRubric>
                                    <locus from="48r" to="48r">48r</locus> Explicit liber magistri aflaticii feliciter</finalRubric>
                                <note>The text is attributed to a Magister Afratisius/Alfacius of Monte Pesulano (Montpellier) in the
                                    manuscript.</note>
                                <note>
                                    <p>Edited by R. Creutz based on a manuscript now in Wurzburg in <hi rend="italic">Sudhoffs Archiv für Geschichte
                                            der Medizin und der Naturwissenschaften</hi>, Bd. 33, H. 5/6 (Juli 1941), pp. 249-338</p>
                                </note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>Creutz (1941)</bibl>
                                    <bibl>eTK 0349G</bibl>
                                    <bibl>Renzi, vol. 4, pp. 439-505</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="2">
                                <locus from="48r" to="48v">48rv</locus>
                                <title>Medical recipes</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="48r" to="48r">48r</locus> Contra dolorem dentium de qui nos annua lu<supplied>na</supplied>
                                    apollinaris tui pontificis solempnitate </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="48v" to="48v">48v</locus> aqua ponita spiritus calligantiam quam habent utraque cum
                                        esse<supplied>t</supplied> diantibus duobus neruis </explicit>
                                <note><p>Written by at least two scribes writing an <term type="script">anglicana</term> script of the late-14th
                                        century.</p></note>
                            </msItem>
                        </msContents>

                        <physDesc>
                            <p><secFol>
                                    <locus from="28r" to="28r">28r</locus> tritis in coloquintidam pone </secFol>
                            </p>
                            <objectDesc form="codex">
                                <supportDesc material="perg">
                                    <support>
                                        <material>Parchment (<term type="disposition">HFFH</term>).</material>
                                    </support>

                                    <extent>
                                        <seg type="object">Codex: </seg>
                                        <seg type="leaf">
                                            <measure quantity="22" type="leaf">22</measure> leaves. </seg>
                                        <seg type="dimensions">
                                            <dimensions type="leaf" unit="mm">
                                                <height quantity="240">240</height>
                                                <width max="170" min="165">165-170</width>
                                            </dimensions>
                                        </seg>
                                    </extent>

                                    <collation mainStructures="8 6">
                                        <p>
                                            <list>
                                                <item>Quires 5-6<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> (ff. <locus from="27r" to="42v">27-42</locus>)</item>
                                                <item>Quire 7<hi rend="superscript">6</hi> (ff. <locus from="43r" to="48v">43-48</locus>)</item>
                                            </list>
                                        </p>
                                    </collation>

                                    <condition> Sewn repair to small tear on f. 39. Peterhouse stamp (purple ink) on ff. 41 and 42. Portions of the
                                        outer margins of ff. 46 and 47 cut away. Sewn repair to f. 48 - sewn after writing. </condition>
                                </supportDesc>

                                <layoutDesc>
                                    <layout columns="2" rulingMedium="leadpoint" topLine="mixed" writtenLines="38">
                                        <dimensions type="written" unit="mm">
                                            <height quantity="170">170</height>
                                            <width max="115" min="110">110-115</width>
                                        </dimensions>
                                        <seg type="ruling">Ruled in two-column format, in pencil, frame and lines. Typically 38 lines to the column,
                                            usually, but not always written below top line. </seg>
                                    </layout>
                                </layoutDesc>
                            </objectDesc>

                            <handDesc>
                                <handNote script="textualisSouthern">
                                    <p>Main text is written in a southern textualis bookhand. </p>
                                </handNote>

                                <handNote script="cursivaAntiquior">
                                    <p>Medical recipes on ff. <locus from="48r" to="48v">48rv</locus> written in <term type="script">anglicana</term>
                                        script by more than one scribe.</p>
                                </handNote>
                            </handDesc>

                            <decoDesc>
                                <decoNote type="flourInit">
                                    <p>Decorative initials in either red or blue with minor flourishing in the other colour at the start of most
                                        divisions of the text.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                                <decoNote type="rubrication">
                                    <p>Headings to each section of the text in red.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                                <decoNote type="other">
                                    <p>Paraph marks separating the minor divisions of the text in red or blue.</p>
                                </decoNote>

                            </decoDesc>


                            <additions>
                                <note><p> In the upper margin of f. <locus from="39v" to="39v">39v</locus>, a note, presumably by an English scribe
                                        giving an English translation of a Latin plant name: <q>betonia Wildnepe</q>.</p></note>
                            </additions>
                        </physDesc>

                        <history>
                            <origin>
                                <origDate calendar="Gregorian" cert="medium" notAfter="1250" notBefore="1200">Probably written in the first half of
                                    the 13th century. Date of origin suggested based on palaeographical features. </origDate>
                                <origPlace cert="medium" key="place_g1000080">Probably written in Italy. Place of origin suggested based on
                                    palaeographical features. </origPlace>
                            </origin>

                        </history>
                    </msPart>

                    <msPart n="6">
                        <msIdentifier>
                            <idno>Cambridge, Peterhouse, MS 251, ff. 49r-91v</idno>
                            <msName>Part 6 (Thomson Part V)</msName>

                        </msIdentifier>

                        <msContents>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>

                            <msItem n="1">
                                <locus from="49r" to="49v">49rv</locus>
                                <title>Aphorisms</title>
                                <author key="person_v19690624">Iohannitus</author>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <rubric>
                                    <locus from="49r" to="49r">49r</locus> Sapientia amorosa </rubric>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="49r" to="49r">49r</locus> Philosophia interpretatur amor sapientie </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="49v" to="49v">49v</locus> membrorum sensibilium ex fumo pertranseunte </explicit>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="2">
                                <locus from="49v" to="63v">49v-63v</locus>
                                <title key="work_2612">Isagoge ad Artem paruam Galeni (tr. Constantinus Africanus) [Latin]</title>
                                <author key="person_v19690624">Iohannitus</author>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <rubric>
                                    <locus from="49v" to="49v">49v</locus> Incipit Iohannicius </rubric>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="49v" to="49v">49v</locus> Medicina diuiditur in duo </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="63v" to="63v">63v</locus> boni maliue discretio </explicit>
                                <finalRubric>
                                    <locus from="63v" to="63v">63v</locus> Explicit liber Iohanicii cum commento </finalRubric>
                                <note><p>Gloss incipit: Cum inter omnia animalia corpus humanum <lb/> Gloss explicit: quibus non utimur in
                                        medicina</p></note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>eTK 856, 1352 </bibl>
                                    <bibl>eTK 311(gloss)</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="3">
                                <locus from="64r" to="80v">64r-80v</locus>
                                <title>Aphorismi (with gloss of Oribasius) [Latin]</title>
                                <author key="person_v287984736">Hippocrates</author>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <rubric>
                                    <locus from="64r" to="64r">64r</locus> Incipiunt aphorismi Ypocratis </rubric>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="64r" to="64r">64r</locus> Uita breuis ars uero longa </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="80v" to="80v">80v</locus> deglutire non possit mortale </explicit>
                                <note><p>Gloss incipit: Temporibus Ypocratis doctissimi uiri pro multiplici medicorum uarietate <lb/> Gloss explicit:
                                        et modo corpus attenuatur</p>
                                    <p>Printed alongside an edition of the <hi rend="italic">Articella</hi> in Padua in 1476.</p>
                                </note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>eTK 0113F</bibl>
                                    <bibl>eTK 1559 (gloss)</bibl>
                                    <bibl>Kibre, <hi rend="italic">Hippocrates Latinus</hi> (rev. ed. 1985), no 41</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="4">
                                <locus from="81r" to="86v">81r-86v</locus>
                                <title>Commentary on Theophilus, On Urines [Latin]</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <rubric>
                                    <locus from="81r" to="81r">81r</locus> Commentum super urinas a uoce Theophili </rubric>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="81r" to="81r">81r</locus> Sicut in humano corpore non simpliciter sed multiformiter fit operacio </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="86v" to="86v">86v</locus> et caloris et hec est naturalis </explicit>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>eTK 1492</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="5">
                                <locus from="86v" to="91v">86v-91v</locus>
                                <title key="work_11257">Glosae super pulsus Philareti [Latin] (Gloss on Philaretus, Pulses)</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <rubric>
                                    <locus from="86v" to="86v">86v</locus> Commentum super libro pulsuum philareti </rubric>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="87r" to="87r">87r</locus> Virtutum operationibus perficitur vita animalium et eorum corpora reguntur </incipit>
                                <explicit defective="true">
                                    <locus from="91v" to="91v">91v</locus> Duricia et mollicies </explicit>
                                <note><p>Commentary explicit (ends imperfectly): 'est Marcellinus su'</p>
                                    <p>Also in <bibl subtype="external" type="MS">Cambridge, Gonville and Caius MS 111/180</bibl>, pp. 73a-80b. </p>
                                </note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>eTK 1702H</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>
                        </msContents>



                        <physDesc>
                            <p><secFol>
                                    <locus from="50r" to="50r">50r</locus> egritudinum procedit </secFol>
                            </p>

                            <objectDesc form="codex">
                                <supportDesc material="perg">
                                    <support>
                                        <material>Parchment (<term type="disposition">HFFH</term>).</material>
                                    </support>

                                    <extent>
                                        <seg type="object">Codex: </seg>
                                        <seg type="leaf">
                                            <measure quantity="43" type="leaf">43</measure> leaves. </seg>
                                        <seg type="dimensions">
                                            <dimensions type="leaf" unit="mm">
                                                <height quantity="240">240</height>
                                                <width quantity="170">170</width>
                                            </dimensions>
                                        </seg>
                                    </extent>

                                    <collation mainStructures="8">
                                        <p>
                                            <list>
                                                <item>Quires 8-12<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> (ff. <locus from="49r" to="88v">49-88</locus>)</item>
                                                <item>Quire 13<hi rend="superscript">4-1</hi> (ff. <locus from="89r" to="91v">89-91</locus>; 4th
                                                    missing)</item>
                                            </list>
                                        </p>
                                    </collation>

                                    <condition> Very thick and rigid parchment in this section. Tight crease in f. 73. </condition>
                                </supportDesc>

                                <layoutDesc>
                                    <layout columns="2" rulingMedium="leadpoint" topLine="mixed" writtenLines="50">
                                        <dimensions type="written" unit="mm">
                                            <height quantity="185">185</height>
                                            <width quantity="115">115</width>
                                        </dimensions>
                                        <seg type="ruling"> Ruled in two-column format, frame and lines, in faint leadpoint. Typically 50 lines to the
                                            column and usually written above top line. </seg>
                                    </layout>
                                </layoutDesc>
                            </objectDesc>

                            <handDesc>
                                <handNote script="minusculeCaroline">
                                    <p>Written in a late and compressed Caroline minuscule of ?southern ?Italian appearance. For the items where there
                                        is a main text accompanied by a gloss or a commentary - the 'main' text is written in a larger and more
                                        calligraphic style, usually a few sentences at a time, and then the gloss or commentary follows underneath in
                                        a smaller and plainer style. </p>
                                </handNote>
                            </handDesc>

                            <decoDesc>
                                <decoNote type="decInit">
                                    <p>Major initials at the opening of each text: gold initials on a red and blue geometric ground, the grounds
                                        further decorated with flourishes in white, and red pen-flourishing extending from the frame of the initial
                                        along the length of the adjacent margin, e.g., f. <locus from="49v" to="49v">49v</locus>.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                                <decoNote type="plainInit">
                                    <p>Minor initials in red or blue at the minor divisions of the text, occasionally with very minor
                                        pen-flourishing.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                                <decoNote type="chrysography"><p>Some minor initials in gold, usually marking a new significant section within a text,
                                        e.g., f. <locus from="70r" to="70r">70r</locus>.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                                <decoNote type="rubrication">
                                    <p>Headings, section titles and key words in red in the main text or in the margins.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                                <decoNote type="other">
                                    <p>Paraph marks in red and blue to mark the smallest sub-divisions of the text.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                            </decoDesc>
                        </physDesc>

                        <history>
                            <origin>
                                <origDate calendar="Gregorian" cert="medium" notAfter="1200" notBefore="1150">Probably written in the late 12th
                                    century. Date of origin suggested based on palaeographical features. </origDate>
                                <origPlace cert="low" key="place_g1000080">Possibly written in ?Southern ?Italy. Place of origin suggested based on
                                    palaeographical features. </origPlace>
                            </origin>
                        </history>

                    </msPart>

                    <msPart n="7">
                        <msIdentifier>
                            <idno>Cambridge, Peterhouse MS 251, ff. 92r-105v</idno>
                            <msName>Part 7 (Thomson Part VI)</msName>

                        </msIdentifier>

                        <msContents>

                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>

                            <msItem n="1">
                                <locus from="92r" to="97r">92r-97r</locus>
                                <title key="work_2612">Isagoge ad Artem paruam Galeni (tr. Constantinus Africanus) [Latin]</title>
                                <author key="person_v19690624">Iohannitus</author>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <rubric>
                                    <locus from="92r" to="92r">92r</locus> Incipiunt ysagoge Iohanieii ad tegni Galieni </rubric>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="92r" to="92r">92r</locus>
                                    <supplied>M</supplied>edicina diuiditur in duas </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="97r" to="97r">97r</locus> a boni maliue discretione </explicit>
                                <note><p>Same text as Part 5, item 2, ff. <locus from="49v" to="63v">49v-63v</locus>, but unglossed. </p></note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>eTK 856, 1352</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="2">
                                <locus from="97v" to="102v">97v-102v</locus>
                                <title>Aphorismi [Latin]</title>
                                <author key="person_v287984736">Hippocrates</author>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <msItem n="2.1">
                                    <locus from="97v" to="97v">97v</locus>
                                    <title key="">Aphorismi (Prologue) [Latin]</title>
                                    <author key="person_v287984736">Hippocrates</author>
                                    <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                    <rubric>
                                        <locus from="97v" to="97v">97v</locus> Incipit ars prologus amphorismorum ypocratis </rubric>
                                    <incipit>
                                        <locus from="97v" to="97v">97v</locus> Aphorismorum ypocratis <supplied>h</supplied>uius noue editionis ea
                                        causa extitit quoniam <sic>atique</sic> nullum eorum que uitiosis translacionibus inesse adsolent culpe genus
                                        defuit </incipit>
                                    <explicit>
                                        <locus from="97v" to="97v">97v</locus> Sed iam tempus est ad ipsum ypocratem accedere </explicit>
                                    <finalRubric>
                                        <locus from="97v" to="97v">97v</locus> Explicit prologus </finalRubric>
                                </msItem>
                                <msItem n="2.2">
                                    <locus from="97v" to="102v">97v-102v</locus>
                                    <title>Aphorismi [Latin]</title>
                                    <author key="person_v287984736">Hippocrates</author>
                                    <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                    <rubric>
                                        <locus from="97v" to="97v">97v</locus> Incipit liber i amphorismorum ypocratis </rubric>
                                    <incipit>
                                        <locus from="97v" to="97v">97v</locus>
                                        <supplied>U</supplied>ita breuis ars uero longa </incipit>
                                    <explicit>
                                        <locus from="102v" to="102v">102v</locus> et deglutire non possit mortale </explicit>
                                    <finalRubric>
                                        <locus from="102v" to="102v">102v</locus> Explicit liber aphorismorum Ypocratis </finalRubric>
                                </msItem>
                                <note><p>Printed alongside an edition of the <hi rend="italic">Articella</hi> in Padua in 1476.</p></note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>eTK 0113F</bibl>
                                    <bibl>Kibre, <hi rend="italic">Hippocrates Latinus</hi> (rev. ed. 1985), no 41</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="3">
                                <locus from="102v" to="105r">102v-105r</locus>
                                <title key="work_2069">Prognostica (tr. Constantinus Africanus or Gerard of Cremona) [Latin]</title>
                                <author key="person_v287984736">Hippocrates</author>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <rubric>
                                    <locus from="102v" to="102v">102v</locus> Incipit liber pronosticorum ypocratis </rubric>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="102v" to="102v">102v</locus>
                                    <supplied>O</supplied>mnis qui medicine artis studio seu gloriam </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="105r" to="105r">105r</locus> exposite ordine preceptorum </explicit>
                                <finalRubric>
                                    <locus from="105r" to="105r">105r</locus> Explicit liber pronosticorum ypocratis </finalRubric>
                                <note><p>Printed alongside an edition of the <hi rend="italic">Articella</hi> in Padua in 1476.</p></note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>Kibre, <hi rend="italic">Hippocrates Latinus</hi> (rev. ed. 1985), no 203</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="4">
                                <locus from="105r" to="105v">105rv</locus>
                                <title key="work_4738">Liber urinarum [Latin]</title>
                                <author key="person_2376">Theophilus</author>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">:Latin</textLang>
                                <rubric>
                                    <locus from="105r" to="105r">105r</locus> Incipit liber urinarum a uoce theophili </rubric>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="105r" to="105r">105r</locus>
                                    <supplied>D</supplied>e urinarum differentia negocium multi ueterum medicorum agressi sunt scribere </incipit>
                                <explicit defective="true">
                                    <locus from="105v" to="105v">105v</locus> equalis colore uero ruffa autem subruffa et rubei paululum partici </explicit>
                                <note>
                                    <p>Ends imperfectly.</p>
                                    <p>Printed alongside an edition of the <hi rend="italic">Articella</hi> in Padua in 1476.</p></note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>eTK 0393L</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>
                        </msContents>

                        <physDesc>
                            <p><secFol>
                                    <locus from="93r" to="93r">93r</locus> aut exteriora deducunt </secFol>
                            </p>
                            <objectDesc form="codex">
                                <supportDesc material="perg">
                                    <support>
                                        <material>Parchment (<term type="disposition">HFFH</term>).</material>
                                    </support>

                                    <extent>
                                        <seg type="object">Codex: </seg>
                                        <seg type="leaf">
                                            <measure quantity="14" type="leaf">14</measure> leaves. </seg>
                                        <seg type="dimensions">
                                            <dimensions type="leaf" unit="mm">
                                                <height quantity="240">240</height>
                                                <width quantity="170">170</width>
                                            </dimensions>
                                        </seg>
                                    </extent>


                                    <collation mainStructures="8">
                                        <p>
                                            <list>
                                                <item>Quire 14<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> (ff. <locus from="92r" to="99v">92-99</locus>)</item>
                                                <item>Quire 15<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> (ff. <locus from="100r" target="105v">100-105</locus>; 7th
                                                    and 8th leaves missing)</item>
                                            </list>
                                        </p>
                                        <catchwords><seg type="para">Medieval catchword in ink in the lower inner corner of f. <locus from="99v"
                                                    to="99v">99v</locus>.</seg></catchwords>
                                    </collation>

                                    <condition> Trimmed with minor loss to catchword on f. <locus from="99v" to="99v">99v</locus>. </condition>

                                </supportDesc>

                                <layoutDesc>
                                    <layout columns="2" rulingMedium="leadpoint" topLine="below" writtenLines="35">
                                        <dimensions type="written" unit="mm">
                                            <height quantity="180">180</height>
                                            <width quantity="120">120</width>
                                        </dimensions>
                                        <p><seg type="ruling"> Ruled in two-column format, frame and lines, in leadpoint. 35 lines to the column
                                                written below top line ff. <locus from="92r" to="99v">92r-99v</locus>. </seg></p>
                                    </layout>

                                    <layout columns="2" rulingMedium="leadpoint" topLine="below" writtenLines="46">
                                        <dimensions type="written" unit="mm">
                                            <height quantity="180">180</height>
                                            <width quantity="120">120</width>
                                        </dimensions>
                                        <p><seg type="ruling"> Ruled in two-column format, frame and lines, in leadpoint. 46 lines to the column
                                                written below top line ff. <locus from="100r" to="105v">100r-105v</locus>. </seg></p>
                                    </layout>
                                </layoutDesc>


                            </objectDesc>

                            <handDesc>
                                <handNote script="textualisSouthern">
                                    <p>Written in a southern European <term type="script">textualis rotunda</term> bookhand.</p>
                                </handNote>
                            </handDesc>

                            <decoDesc>
                                <decoNote type="rubrication">
                                    <p>Incipits, explicits and section headings in red.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                                <decoNote type="unfilled">
                                    <p>Spaces left for decorative initials on ff. <locus from="92r" to="92r">92r</locus>, <locus from="97v" to="97v"
                                            >97v</locus>, <locus from="102v" to="102v">102v</locus>, <locus from="105v" to="105v">105v</locus>.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                            </decoDesc>
                        </physDesc>

                        <history>
                            <origin>
                                <origDate calendar="Gregorian" cert="medium" notAfter="1300" notBefore="1200">Probably written in the 13th century.
                                    Date of origin suggested based on palaeographical features. </origDate>
                                <origPlace cert="medium" key="place_g1000080">Probably written in Italy. Date of origin suggested based on
                                    palaeographical features. </origPlace>
                            </origin>
                        </history>
                    </msPart>

                    <msPart n="8">
                        <msIdentifier>
                            <idno>Cambridge, Peterhouse, MS 251, ff. 106r-191v</idno>
                            <msName>Part 8 (Thomson Part VII)</msName>

                        </msIdentifier>

                        <msContents>
                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>

                            <msItem n="1">
                                <locus from="106r" to="142v">106r-142v</locus>
                                <title key="work_1595">Ad glauconem de medendi methodo with interpolation from Ps-Soranus</title>
                                <author key="person_v44299175">Galen</author>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <msItem n="1.1">
                                    <locus from="106r" to="106v">106rv</locus>
                                    <title key="work_1595">Ad glauconem de medendi methodo</title>
                                    <author key="person_v44299175">Galen</author>
                                    <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                    <rubric>
                                        <locus from="106r" to="106r">106r</locus>
                                        <supplied>Quonia</supplied>m quidem non solum communem omnium fisin </rubric>
                                    <incipit defective="true">
                                        <locus from="106r" to="106r">106r</locus> naturam uel temperantiam corpo</incipit>
                                    <explicit>
                                        <locus from="106v" to="106v">106v</locus> sed sordida quidem est et difficilis ad curandum </explicit>
                                    <note><p>Title added in upper margin of f. <locus from="106r" to="106r">106r</locus> in a late 14th or early 15th
                                            century hand 'Liber de ffebribus'.</p>
                                        <p>Subtitle 'Liber primus' added in a late 14th or early 15th century hand to the upper margin of f. <locus
                                                from="106r" to="106r">106r</locus>.</p>
                                        <p>Initial 'Q' on f. <locus from="106r" to="106r">106r</locus> cut away.</p>
                                    </note>
                                </msItem>
                                <msItem n="1.2">
                                    <locus from="107r" to="108r">107r-108r</locus>
                                    <title>Epistula de ratione uentris uel uiscerum</title>
                                    <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                    <rubric>
                                        <locus from="107r" to="107r">107r</locus> Ne quis ignorans medicinam morituro adhibeat </rubric>
                                    <incipit>
                                        <locus from="107r" to="107r">107r</locus> Ne ignorans <sic>quisque iam</sic> medicus rationem organi uentris
                                        uel uiscerum </incipit>
                                    <explicit defective="true">
                                        <locus from="108r" to="108r">108r</locus> siquidem per omnes egritudines sua simili uarietate uexentur </explicit>
                                    <note><p>Also in <bibl subtype="external" type="MS">  <ref
                                                    target="https://medieval.bodleian.ox.ac.uk/catalog/manuscript_6595">Oxford, Bodleian Library, MS
                                                    Lat. misc. c. 73, ff. 16rv</ref>
                                            </bibl></p></note>
                                    <listBibl>
                                        <bibl>eTK 0906F</bibl>
                                        <bibl>Printed (not from this MS) as part of Ps-Soranus, <hi rend="italic">In artem medendi isagoge</hi> in <hi
                                                rend="italic">De re medica</hi> (Basel, 1528), ff. 5r-6r, chs xii-xiii </bibl>
                                    </listBibl>
                                </msItem>
                                <msItem n="1.3">
                                    <locus from="108r" to="142v">108r-142v</locus>
                                    <title key="work_1595">Ad glauconem de medendi methodo</title>
                                    <author key="person_v44299175">Galen</author>
                                    <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                    <rubric>
                                        <locus from="108v" to="108v">108v</locus> De febrium speciebus </rubric>
                                    <incipit>
                                        <locus from="108v" to="108v">108v</locus> Febrium species nemo discernere potest </incipit>
                                    <explicit>
                                        <locus from="142v" to="142v">142v</locus> possum scientia manifesta ratione conscribam </explicit>
                                    <note><p>List of capitula on f. <locus from="108r" to="108v">108rv</locus>: 'Incipit capitula Libri .I.', followed
                                            by a list of 53 numbered capitula </p>
                                        <p>List of capitula on f. <locus from="129v" to="129v">129v</locus>: 'Incipit capitula Libri Secundi',
                                            followed by a list of 25 numbered capitula </p>
                                        <p>?Medieval bookmark made from a small piece of yarn, dyed blue, and sewn through the lower outer corner of
                                            f. <locus from="130v" to="130v">130v</locus>.</p>
                                    </note>
                                </msItem>
                                <note><p><hi rend="italic">Ad glauconem de medendi methodo</hi> presented in two books, with two prologues. Book 1
                                        preceded by 53 capitula, Book 2 preceded by 25 capitula. </p></note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>eTK 1297, 553</bibl>
                                    <bibl>Edited (not from this MS) in C. G. Kühn, <hi rend="italic">Galeni opera omnia</hi>, 20 vols in 22 (Leipzig,
                                        1819–33), XI:1-146</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="2">
                                <locus from="142v" to="158r">142v-158r</locus>
                                <title key="work_v196918760">Liber tertius</title>
                                <author key="person_v44299175">Pseudo Galen</author>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <rubric>
                                    <locus from="143r" to="143r">143r</locus> Incipit Liber Tertius </rubric>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="143r" to="143r">143r</locus> Cephalea est dolor capitis </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="158r" to="158r">158r</locus> clisma austerum adhibendum est </explicit>
                                <finalRubric>
                                    <locus from="158r" to="158r">158r</locus> Explicit liber tertius </finalRubric>
                                <note><p>List of capitula on f. <locus from="142v" to="143r">142v-143r</locus>: 'Incipit capitula', followed by 68
                                        numbered items.</p>
                                    <p>?Medieval bookmark made from a small piece of yarn, dyed blue, and sewn through the lower outer corner of f.
                                            <locus from="142v" to="142v">142v</locus>.</p>
                                </note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>eTK 200</bibl>
                                    <bibl>Edited in K.-D. Fischer, <hi rend="italic">Galenismo e medi- cina tardoantica: Fonti greche, latine e arabe.
                                            Atti del seminario internazionale di Siena, Certosa di Pontignano, 9 e 10 settembre 2002</hi>, ed. I.
                                        Garofalo and A. Roselli (Naples, 2003), pp. 283–346</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="3">
                                <locus from="158v" to="167v">158v-167v</locus>
                                <title key="work_214766691">Liber Aurelii de acutis passionibus (De humoribus)</title>
                                <author key="person_v44299175">Galen</author>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <rubric>
                                    <locus from="158v" to="158v">158v</locus> De iiiiuor humoribus qualiter egritudines faciunt </rubric>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="158v" to="158v">158v</locus> Omnibus hominibus generantur egritudines ex quattuor humoribus </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="167v" to="167v">167v</locus> in omnibus uulneribus ratio exigit </explicit>
                                <finalRubric>
                                    <locus from="167v" to="167v">167v</locus> Explicit liber iiii </finalRubric>
                                <note><p>Text preceded by 28 capitula</p>
                                    <p>?Medieval bookmark made from a small piece of yarn, dyed blue, and sewn through the lower outer corner of f.
                                            <locus from="158v" to="158v">158v</locus>.</p>
                                </note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>eTK 0993</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="4">
                                <locus from="168r" to="186r">168r-186r</locus>
                                <title>Liber Esculapii de chronicis passionibus</title>
                                <author key="person_v44299175">Galen</author>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <rubric>
                                    <locus from="168r" to="168r">168r</locus> Incipit liber quintus </rubric>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="168r" to="168r">168r</locus> Cephaloponia id est capitis dolor commoto cerebro </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="186r" to="186r">186r</locus> acerrima induta fiant </explicit>
                                <finalRubric>
                                    <locus from="186r" to="186r">186r</locus> Explicit liber quintus </finalRubric>
                                <note>Text preceded by 60 capitula</note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>eTK 0200</bibl>
                                    <bibl>Edited in F. M. Cano, ‘Liber Esculapii (Anonymus Liber chro- niorum): Edición crítica y estudio’
                                        (unpublished Ph.D. thesis, Madrid, 1996)</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="5">
                                <locus from="186r" to="191v">186r-191v</locus>
                                <title key="">De Podagra</title>
                                <author key="person_v79139373">Alexander of Tralles</author>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <rubric>
                                    <locus from="186r" to="186r">186r</locus> Incipit liber sextus de podagricis </rubric>
                                <incipit>
                                    <locus from="186r" to="186r">186r</locus> Podagriorum causas scire oportet </incipit>
                                <explicit>
                                    <locus from="191v" to="191v">191v</locus> ad emigraneam et profluxum sanguinis prodest </explicit>
                                <note><p>Text preceded by 22 capitula</p>
                                    <p>?Medieval bookmark made from a small piece of yarn, dyed blue, and sewn through the lower outer corner of f.
                                            <locus from="186r" to="186r">186r</locus>.</p>
                                </note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>eTK 1056</bibl>
                                    <bibl>Edited in V. Knight, ‘The De Podagra (On Gout): A Pre-Gariopontean Treatise Excerpted from the Latin
                                        Translation of the Greek Therapeutica by Alexander of Tralles’ (unpublished PhD, Manchester, 2015) </bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>
                        </msContents>



                        <physDesc>
                            <p><secFol>
                                    <locus from="107r" to="107r">107r</locus> Ne quis ignorans medicinam morituro adhibeat . Ne ignorans quisque iam
                                    medicus rationem organi uentris </secFol>
                            </p>

                            <objectDesc form="codex">
                                <supportDesc material="perg">
                                    <support>
                                        <material>Parchment (<term type="disposition">HFFH</term>)</material>
                                    </support>

                                    <extent>
                                        <seg type="object">Codex: </seg>
                                        <seg type="leaf">
                                            <measure quantity="86" type="leaf">86</measure> leaves. </seg>
                                        <seg type="dimensions">
                                            <dimensions type="leaf" unit="mm">
                                                <height quantity="240">240</height>
                                                <width max="160" min="150">150-160</width>
                                            </dimensions>
                                        </seg>
                                    </extent>

                                    <collation mainStructures="8">
                                        <p>
                                            <list>
                                                <item>Quire 16<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> (ff. <locus from="106r" to="113v">106-113</locus>)</item>
                                                <item>Quire 17<hi rend="superscript">6</hi> (ff. <locus from="114r" to="119v">114-119</locus>)</item>
                                                <item>Quires 18-26<hi rend="superscript">8</hi> (ff. <locus from="120r" to="191v"
                                                    >120-191</locus>)</item>
                                            </list>
                                        </p>
                                        <signatures type="quire"><p>Quires 16-25 have medieval alphabetical signatures in ink A-K (J omitted) in ink
                                                in the lower margin of the last verso of each quire.</p></signatures>
                                    </collation>

                                    <condition> Parchment is irregularly shaped, not all leaves conform exactly to the measurements of the bookblock,
                                        but text conforms to the irregularities of the leaves. Damage to f. 106, a decorative initial on f. <locus
                                            from="106r" to="106r">106r</locus> has been excised. </condition>
                                </supportDesc>

                                <layoutDesc>
                                    <layout columns="1" rulingMedium="drypoint" topLine="above" writtenLines="37">
                                        <dimensions type="written" unit="mm">
                                            <height quantity="175">175</height>
                                            <width quantity="105">105</width>
                                        </dimensions>
                                        <seg type="ruling"> Ruled in single-column format with a stylus, frame and lines. Typically 37 lines to the
                                            page, written above top line. Capitulae arranged in two columns. </seg>
                                    </layout>
                                </layoutDesc>


                            </objectDesc>

                            <handDesc>
                                <handNote script="minusculeCaroline">
                                    <p>Written in a late <term type="script">Anglo-Caroline minuscule</term>. See T. A. M. Bishop, <hi rend="italic"
                                            >TCBS</hi> 2 (1954-1956), p. 189. See also, Gameson, <hi rend="italic">Earliest Books</hi> (2008), pp.
                                        191-192 and 203-204 </p>
                                </handNote>
                            </handDesc>


                            <decoDesc>
                                <decoNote type="plainInit">
                                    <p>Plain initials in red, green, blue, and lilac at the start of major and minor divisions of the text.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                                <decoNote type="rubrication">
                                    <p>Rubrication (red only) for chapter headings and most explicits.</p>
                                </decoNote>
                            </decoDesc>
                        </physDesc>

                        <history>
                            <origin>
                                <origDate calendar="Gregorian" cert="high" notAfter="1125" notBefore="1050"> Probably written in the second half of
                                    the 11th century, or first quarter of the 12th century. Date of origin for ff. <locus from="106r" to="191v"
                                        >106r-191v</locus> assigned to 'xi/xii' by Gameson in <hi rend="italic">The Manuscripts of Early Norman
                                        England (c.1066-1130)</hi>
                                    <hi rend="italic">The Manuscripts of Early Norman England (c.1066-1130)</hi>. Date of origin for ff. <locus
                                        from="106r" to="191v">106r-191v</locus> assigned to 'xi ex. or xi/xii' by Gneuss and Lapidge in <hi
                                        rend="italic">Anglo-Saxon Manuscripts: A Bibliographical Handlist of Manuscripts and Manuscript Fragments
                                        Written or Owned in England up to 1100</hi>. </origDate>
                                <origPlace cert="high" key="place_g7032648">Probably written at St Augustine's Abbey, Canterbury, England. Place of
                                    origin for ff. <locus from="106r" to="191v">106r-191v</locus> attributed to St Augustine's, Canterbury in Gameson,
                                        <hi rend="italic">The Manuscripts of Early Norman England (c.1066-1130)</hi> (no. 117), and Gneuss and
                                    Lapidge, <hi rend="italic">Anglo-Saxon Manuscripts: A Bibliographical Handlist of Manuscripts and Manuscript
                                        Fragments Written or Owned in England up to 1100</hi> (no. 145). </origPlace>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>R. Gameson, <hi rend="italic">The Manuscripts of Early Norman England (c.1066-1130)</hi> (Oxford: Published
                                        for the British Academy by Oxford University Press, 1999), Peterhouse MS 251 ff. 106-191 = no. 117</bibl>
                                    <bibl>H. Gneuss, and M. Lapidge, <hi rend="italic">Anglo-Saxon Manuscripts: A Bibliographical Handlist of
                                            Manuscripts and Manuscript Fragments Written or Owned in England up to 1100</hi>, Toronto Anglo-Saxon
                                        Series, 15 (Toronto: University of Toronto Press, 2014), Peterhouse MS 251 ff. 106-191 = no. 145</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </origin>

                        </history>
                    </msPart>

                    <msPart n="9">
                        <msIdentifier>
                            <idno>Cambridge, Peterhouse MS 251, ff. 192-[193]</idno>
                            <msName>Part 9 - Carmelite letters and pentrials</msName>

                        </msIdentifier>

                        <msContents>

                            <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>

                            <msItem n="1">
                                <locus from="192r" to="192r">192r</locus>
                                <title key="">Copy of a letter written in 1400 to John and Alicia Horssyngton from a Carmelite foundation</title>
                                <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                                <note><p>The letter greets 'John Horssyngton et Aliccie uxori sue' (John Horssyngton and Alicia his wife) and
                                        concludes with a dating clause 'Anno domini MCCCC<hi rend="superscript">o</hi>', i.e., the year 1400.</p>
                                    <p>The text of the letter is badly damaged and partly illegible due to rubbing. There is an annotation under the
                                        letter in a 15th century English cursive minuscule, now illegible due to rubbing.</p></note>
                                <listBibl>
                                    <bibl>See Thomson, <hi rend="italic">Peterhouse</hi> (2016), no. 251</bibl>
                                </listBibl>
                            </msItem>

                            <msItem n="2">
                                <locus from="[193] verso" to="[193] verso">[193] verso</locus>
                                <title key="">Copy of a letter (?from a Carmelite foundation)</title>
                                <note><p>The leaf was once used as a pastedown and most of the text is illegible due to adhesive residue and rubbing. </p>
                                    <p>The text of the letter is in the same hand as the letter on f. <locus from="192r" to="192r">192r</locus> and
                                        presumably shares some origin and context features with that letter, but names, dates, and location
                                        information in the letter are too damaged to read with any certainty.</p>
                                    <p>There is an annotation in a 15th century English cursive minuscule under the main text of the letter - this
                                        appears to be the same annotator who added a note in a similar location on f. <locus from="192r" to="192r"
                                            >192r</locus>.</p>
                                </note>
                            </msItem>

                        </msContents>



                        <physDesc>
                            <objectDesc form="codex">
                                <supportDesc material="perg">
                                    <support>
                                        <material>Parchment bifolium (<term type="disposition">HFFH</term>). </material>
                                    </support>


                                    <extent>
                                        <seg type="object">Codex: </seg>
                                        <seg type="leaf">
                                            <measure quantity="2" type="endleaf">2</measure> endleaves. </seg>
                                    </extent>

                                    <collation mainStructures="2"><p> Medieval parchment bifolium (ff. <locus from="192r" to="[193] verso"
                                                >192-[193]</locus>) </p>
                                        <signatures type="leaf"><p>No leaf signatures particular to this Part. </p></signatures>
                                        <signatures type="quire"><p>No quire signatures particular to this Part. </p></signatures>
                                        <catchwords><seg type="para">No catchwords particular to this Part. </seg></catchwords>
                                    </collation>

                                    <condition> The two leaves in this part are a bifolium. Folio <locus from="[193] verso" to="[193] verso"
                                            >[193]</locus> was used as the rear pastedown in a former binding and is coated in an adhesive residue.
                                        All surfaces in the bifolium are badly rubbed and most of the text is illegible or gone entirely. Folio 193
                                        was repaired with strong Japanaese paper in 2023 as part of a program of conservation and rebinding work. </condition>

                                </supportDesc>

                                <layoutDesc>
                                    <layout columns="1" rulingMedium="leadpoint" topLine="below" writtenLines="12"><p>
                                            <dimensions type="written" unit="mm">
                                                <height quantity="130">130</height>
                                                <width quantity="135">135</width>
                                            </dimensions>
                                            <seg type="ruling"> Ruled in leadpoint, frame and lines. Folios <locus from="192r" to="192r">192r</locus>
                                                and <locus from="[193] verso" to="[193] verso">[193] verso</locus> ruled in single-column format; the
                                                'text box' is only ruled for the number of lines necessary for the text rather than to the lower
                                                bound, so e.g., there is an unruled space of c. 45mm in the lower portion of the text box on f. <locus
                                                    from="192r" to="192r">192r</locus>. Folios <locus from="192v" to="[193] recto">192v-[193]
                                                    recto</locus> have margin ruling but no line ruling and are informally written.</seg></p>
                                    </layout>
                                </layoutDesc>


                            </objectDesc>

                            <handDesc>
                                <handNote script="textualisNorthern">
                                    <p>The copies of the letters on ff. <locus from="192r" to="192r">192r</locus> and <locus from="[193] verso"
                                            to="[193] verso">[193] verso</locus> are written in a formal northern textualis. </p>
                                </handNote>

                            </handDesc>

                            <decoDesc>
                                <decoNote type="colInit">
                                    <p>Folios <locus from="192r" to="192r">192r</locus> and <locus from="[193] verso" to="[193] verso">[193]
                                            verso</locus>: significant initials in black ink with decorative flourishes in black and red. </p>
                                </decoNote>
                            </decoDesc>


                            <additions>
                                <note>
                                    <p>Folios <locus from="192v" to="[193] recto">192v-[193] recto</locus>: informal annotations written by ?three
                                        scribes in formal northern textualis with further annotations in an informal minuscule, all of 15th century
                                        appearance. The annotations on this opening are mostly written 90° clockwise and anticlockwise relative to the
                                        'normal' orientiation of the book. Annotations as follows: <list>
                                            <item>'Dyllforde (?Dylsforde) anno domini <unclear>...</unclear>'</item>
                                            <item>'Ro<unclear>bert</unclear>o Leycester 7 Alicie <lb/>
                                                <unclear>coci consorti sue</unclear></item>
                                            <item>'Roberti de '</item>
                                            <item>'<unclear>... ...</unclear>ford Anno domini M<hi rend="superscript">o</hi> CCCC<hi
                                                    rend="superscript">mo</hi>
                                                <unclear>lxx</unclear>'</item>
                                            <item>'Johannis Banham &amp; caterine <lb/> a<unclear>nno</unclear> domini millesimo CCCC' </item>
                                            <item>'Adam Scherynt<unclear>on</unclear>
                                                <lb/>Mariana uxor ei<unclear>us</unclear></item>
                                        </list></p>
                                </note>
                            </additions>

                            <bindingDesc>
                                <binding notAfter="1800">
                                    <p>Traces of a pre-18th century binding visible as damage to ff. <locus from="192r" to="[193] verso">192r-[193]
                                            verso</locus>. Small dots of cupric oxidation visible along the fore edge of the leaves probably caused by
                                        fastenings on an old binding. Damage to upper and lower margins now repaired with conservation-paper probably
                                        caused by metal book furniture such as staples for a chained binding. </p>
                                </binding>
                            </bindingDesc>
                        </physDesc>

                        <history>
                            <origin>
                                <origDate calendar="Gregorian" cert="high" notAfter="1500" notBefore="1400">Written in the 15th century. Folio <locus
                                        from="192r" to="192r">192r</locus> contains a copy of a letter dated to 1400 and annotations on folios <locus
                                        from="192v" to="[193] recto">192v-[193] recto</locus> contain 15th century dates. </origDate>
                                <origPlace cert="high" key="place_g7002445"> Written in England. Several English names appear on the leaves.
                                </origPlace>
                            </origin>

                            <provenance>
                                <p/>
                            </provenance>

                            <acquisition notBefore="1400">It is probable that this bifolium (and perhaps other Parts of the volume) were a later
                                addition to the codex. There is a 'Caucio' inscription on f. <locus from="i verso" to="i verso">i verso</locus> dated
                                1330, so presumably the opening flyleaves and at least the first substantial Part of this volume (i.e., Part 2) were
                                together at that date. These endleaves (ff. <locus from="192r" to="[193] verso">192r-[193] verso</locus>) include a
                                copy of a letter dated to 1400 and several nearly-illegible annotations with 15th century dates, so it is likely that
                                these endleaves and perhaps some of the other Parts were added to the 1330 form of the volume after 1400.
                            </acquisition>
                        </history>

                    </msPart>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>

        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <classDecl>
                <taxonomy xml:id="LCSH">
                    <bibl>
                        <ref target="https://authorities.loc.gov/">Library of Congress Subject Headings</ref>
                    </bibl>
                </taxonomy>
            </classDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="#LCSH">
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <term key="subject_sh85083152">Medicine, medieval</term>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc status="draft">
            <!--
            <change
                status="draft"
                when="20230125">
                <persName>Dr Sarah Gilbert, Project Cataloguer, Curious Cures Project, Cambridge
                    University Library</persName>
            </change>-->
            <change status="draft" when="20240222">
                <persName>Dr Sarah Gilbert, Project Cataloguer, Curious Cures Project, Cambridge University Library</persName>
            </change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <facsimile>
        <graphic decls="#document-thumbnail" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00001"/>
        <surface n="outside left cover" xml:id="page-surface-1">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9275px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00001" width="6385px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="inside left cover" xml:id="page-surface-2">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9239px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00002" width="5979px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="[ia] recto" xml:id="page-surface-3">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8537px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00003" width="5609px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="[ia] verso" xml:id="page-surface-4">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8478px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00004" width="5428px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="i recto" xml:id="page-surface-5">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00005" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="i verso" xml:id="page-surface-6">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8617px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00006" width="5688px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="1r" xml:id="page-surface-7">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00007" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="1v" xml:id="page-surface-8">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8714px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00008" width="5332px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="2r" xml:id="page-surface-9">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00009" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="2v" xml:id="page-surface-10">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8714px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00010" width="5332px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="3r" xml:id="page-surface-11">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00011" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="3v" xml:id="page-surface-12">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8714px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00012" width="5332px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="4r" xml:id="page-surface-13">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00013" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="4v" xml:id="page-surface-14">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8714px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00014" width="5332px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="5r" xml:id="page-surface-15">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00015" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="5v" xml:id="page-surface-16">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8714px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00016" width="5332px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="6r" xml:id="page-surface-17">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00017" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="6v" xml:id="page-surface-18">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8714px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00018" width="5332px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="7r" xml:id="page-surface-19">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00019" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="7v" xml:id="page-surface-20">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8714px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00020" width="5332px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="8r" xml:id="page-surface-21">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00021" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="8v" xml:id="page-surface-22">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8714px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00022" width="5332px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="9r" xml:id="page-surface-23">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00023" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="9v" xml:id="page-surface-24">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8714px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00024" width="5332px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="10r" xml:id="page-surface-25">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00025" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="10v" xml:id="page-surface-26">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8655px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00026" width="5369px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="11r" xml:id="page-surface-27">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00027" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="11v" xml:id="page-surface-28">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8655px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00028" width="5369px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="12r" xml:id="page-surface-29">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00029" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="12v" xml:id="page-surface-30">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8655px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00030" width="5369px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="13r" xml:id="page-surface-31">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00031" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="13v" xml:id="page-surface-32">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8655px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00032" width="5369px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="14r" xml:id="page-surface-33">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00033" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="14v" xml:id="page-surface-34">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8655px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00034" width="5369px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="15r" xml:id="page-surface-35">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00035" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="15v" xml:id="page-surface-36">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8655px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00036" width="5369px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="16r" xml:id="page-surface-37">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00037" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="16v" xml:id="page-surface-38">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8655px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00038" width="5369px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="17r" xml:id="page-surface-39">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00039" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="17v" xml:id="page-surface-40">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8655px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00040" width="5369px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="18r" xml:id="page-surface-41">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00041" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="18v" xml:id="page-surface-42">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8655px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00042" width="5369px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="19r" xml:id="page-surface-43">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00043" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="19v" xml:id="page-surface-44">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8655px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00044" width="5369px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="20r" xml:id="page-surface-45">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00045" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="20v" xml:id="page-surface-46">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8655px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00046" width="5369px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="21r" xml:id="page-surface-47">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00047" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="21v" xml:id="page-surface-48">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8655px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00048" width="5369px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="22r" xml:id="page-surface-49">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00049" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="22v" xml:id="page-surface-50">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8655px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00050" width="5369px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="23r" xml:id="page-surface-51">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00051" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="23v" xml:id="page-surface-52">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8655px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00052" width="5369px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="24r" xml:id="page-surface-53">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00053" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="24v" xml:id="page-surface-54">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8655px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00054" width="5369px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="25r" xml:id="page-surface-55">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00055" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="25v" xml:id="page-surface-56">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8655px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00056" width="5369px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="26r" xml:id="page-surface-57">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00057" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="26v" xml:id="page-surface-58">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8655px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00058" width="5369px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="27r" xml:id="page-surface-59">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00059" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="27v" xml:id="page-surface-60">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8655px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00060" width="5369px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="28r" xml:id="page-surface-61">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00061" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="28v" xml:id="page-surface-62">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8655px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00062" width="5369px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="29r" xml:id="page-surface-63">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00063" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="29v" xml:id="page-surface-64">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8655px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00064" width="5369px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="30r" xml:id="page-surface-65">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00065" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="30v" xml:id="page-surface-66">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8655px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00066" width="5369px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="31r" xml:id="page-surface-67">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00067" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="31v" xml:id="page-surface-68">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8655px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00068" width="5369px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="32r" xml:id="page-surface-69">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00069" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="32v" xml:id="page-surface-70">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8684px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00070" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="33r" xml:id="page-surface-71">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00071" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="33v" xml:id="page-surface-72">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8684px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00072" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="34r" xml:id="page-surface-73">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00073" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="34v" xml:id="page-surface-74">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8684px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00074" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="35r" xml:id="page-surface-75">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00075" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="35v" xml:id="page-surface-76">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8684px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00076" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="36r" xml:id="page-surface-77">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00077" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="36v" xml:id="page-surface-78">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8684px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00078" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="37r" xml:id="page-surface-79">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00079" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="37v" xml:id="page-surface-80">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8684px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00080" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="38r" xml:id="page-surface-81">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00081" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="38v" xml:id="page-surface-82">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8684px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00082" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="39r" xml:id="page-surface-83">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00083" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="39v" xml:id="page-surface-84">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8684px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00084" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="40r" xml:id="page-surface-85">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00085" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="40v" xml:id="page-surface-86">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8684px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00086" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="41r" xml:id="page-surface-87">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00087" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="41v" xml:id="page-surface-88">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8684px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00088" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="42r" xml:id="page-surface-89">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00089" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="42v" xml:id="page-surface-90">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8684px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00090" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="43r" xml:id="page-surface-91">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00091" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="43v" xml:id="page-surface-92">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8684px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00092" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="44r" xml:id="page-surface-93">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00093" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="44v" xml:id="page-surface-94">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00094" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="45r" xml:id="page-surface-95">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00095" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="45v" xml:id="page-surface-96">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00096" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="46r" xml:id="page-surface-97">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00097" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="46v" xml:id="page-surface-98">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00098" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="47r" xml:id="page-surface-99">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00099" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="47v" xml:id="page-surface-100">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00100" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="48r" xml:id="page-surface-101">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00101" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="48v" xml:id="page-surface-102">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00102" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="49r" xml:id="page-surface-103">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00103" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="49v" xml:id="page-surface-104">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00104" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="50r" xml:id="page-surface-105">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00105" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="50v" xml:id="page-surface-106">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00106" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="51r" xml:id="page-surface-107">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00107" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="51v" xml:id="page-surface-108">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00108" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="52r" xml:id="page-surface-109">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00109" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="52v" xml:id="page-surface-110">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00110" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="53r" xml:id="page-surface-111">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00111" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="53v" xml:id="page-surface-112">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00112" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="54r" xml:id="page-surface-113">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00113" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="54v" xml:id="page-surface-114">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00114" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="55r" xml:id="page-surface-115">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00115" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="55v" xml:id="page-surface-116">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00116" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="56r" xml:id="page-surface-117">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00117" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="56v" xml:id="page-surface-118">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00118" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="57r" xml:id="page-surface-119">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00119" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="57v" xml:id="page-surface-120">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00120" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="58r" xml:id="page-surface-121">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00121" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="58v" xml:id="page-surface-122">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00122" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="59r" xml:id="page-surface-123">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00123" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="59v" xml:id="page-surface-124">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00124" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="60r" xml:id="page-surface-125">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00125" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="60v" xml:id="page-surface-126">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00126" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="61r" xml:id="page-surface-127">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00127" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="61v" xml:id="page-surface-128">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00128" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="62r" xml:id="page-surface-129">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00129" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="62v" xml:id="page-surface-130">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00130" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="63r" xml:id="page-surface-131">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00131" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="63v" xml:id="page-surface-132">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00132" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="64r" xml:id="page-surface-133">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00133" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="64v" xml:id="page-surface-134">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00134" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="65r" xml:id="page-surface-135">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00135" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="65v" xml:id="page-surface-136">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00136" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="66r" xml:id="page-surface-137">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00137" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="66v" xml:id="page-surface-138">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00138" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="67r" xml:id="page-surface-139">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00139" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="67v" xml:id="page-surface-140">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00140" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="68r" xml:id="page-surface-141">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00141" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="68v" xml:id="page-surface-142">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00142" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="69r" xml:id="page-surface-143">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00143" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="69v" xml:id="page-surface-144">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00144" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="70r" xml:id="page-surface-145">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00145" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="70v" xml:id="page-surface-146">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00146" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="71r" xml:id="page-surface-147">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00147" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="71v" xml:id="page-surface-148">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00148" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="72r" xml:id="page-surface-149">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00149" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="72v" xml:id="page-surface-150">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00150" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="73r" xml:id="page-surface-151">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00151" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="73v" xml:id="page-surface-152">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00152" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="74r" xml:id="page-surface-153">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00153" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="74v" xml:id="page-surface-154">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00154" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="75r" xml:id="page-surface-155">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00155" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="75v" xml:id="page-surface-156">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00156" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="76r" xml:id="page-surface-157">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00157" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="76v" xml:id="page-surface-158">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00158" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="77r" xml:id="page-surface-159">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00159" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="77v" xml:id="page-surface-160">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00160" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="78r" xml:id="page-surface-161">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00161" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="78v" xml:id="page-surface-162">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00162" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="79r" xml:id="page-surface-163">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00163" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="79v" xml:id="page-surface-164">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00164" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="80r" xml:id="page-surface-165">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00165" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="80v" xml:id="page-surface-166">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00166" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="81r" xml:id="page-surface-167">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00167" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="81v" xml:id="page-surface-168">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00168" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="82r" xml:id="page-surface-169">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00169" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="82v" xml:id="page-surface-170">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00170" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="83r" xml:id="page-surface-171">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00171" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="83v" xml:id="page-surface-172">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00172" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="84r" xml:id="page-surface-173">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00173" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="84v" xml:id="page-surface-174">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00174" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="85r" xml:id="page-surface-175">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00175" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="85v" xml:id="page-surface-176">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00176" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="86r" xml:id="page-surface-177">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00177" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="86v" xml:id="page-surface-178">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00178" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="87r" xml:id="page-surface-179">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00179" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="87v" xml:id="page-surface-180">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00180" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="88r" xml:id="page-surface-181">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00181" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="88v" xml:id="page-surface-182">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00182" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="89r" xml:id="page-surface-183">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00183" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="89v" xml:id="page-surface-184">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00184" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="90r" xml:id="page-surface-185">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00185" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="90v" xml:id="page-surface-186">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00186" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="91r" xml:id="page-surface-187">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00187" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="91v" xml:id="page-surface-188">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00188" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="92r" xml:id="page-surface-189">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00189" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="92v" xml:id="page-surface-190">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00190" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="93r" xml:id="page-surface-191">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00191" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="93v" xml:id="page-surface-192">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00192" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="94r" xml:id="page-surface-193">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00193" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="94v" xml:id="page-surface-194">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00194" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="95r" xml:id="page-surface-195">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00195" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="95v" xml:id="page-surface-196">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00196" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="96r" xml:id="page-surface-197">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00197" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="96v" xml:id="page-surface-198">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00198" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="97r" xml:id="page-surface-199">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00199" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="97v" xml:id="page-surface-200">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00200" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="98r" xml:id="page-surface-201">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00201" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="98v" xml:id="page-surface-202">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00202" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="99r" xml:id="page-surface-203">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00203" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="99v" xml:id="page-surface-204">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00204" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="100r" xml:id="page-surface-205">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00205" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="100v" xml:id="page-surface-206">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00206" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="101r" xml:id="page-surface-207">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00207" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="101v" xml:id="page-surface-208">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00208" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="102r" xml:id="page-surface-209">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00209" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="102v" xml:id="page-surface-210">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00210" width="5416px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="103r" xml:id="page-surface-211">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00211" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="103v" xml:id="page-surface-212">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00212" width="5230px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="104r" xml:id="page-surface-213">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00213" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="104v" xml:id="page-surface-214">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00214" width="5250px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="105r" xml:id="page-surface-215">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00215" width="5578px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="105v" xml:id="page-surface-216">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8766px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00216" width="5250px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="106r" xml:id="page-surface-217">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00217" width="4944px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="106v" xml:id="page-surface-218">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8585px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00218" width="4906px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="107r" xml:id="page-surface-219">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00219" width="4944px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="107v" xml:id="page-surface-220">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8585px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00220" width="4906px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="108r" xml:id="page-surface-221">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00221" width="4944px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="108v" xml:id="page-surface-222">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8585px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00222" width="4906px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="109r" xml:id="page-surface-223">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00223" width="4944px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="109v" xml:id="page-surface-224">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8623px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00224" width="4906px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="110r" xml:id="page-surface-225">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00225" width="4944px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="110v" xml:id="page-surface-226">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00226" width="4906px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="111r" xml:id="page-surface-227">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00227" width="4944px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="111v" xml:id="page-surface-228">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00228" width="4906px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="112r" xml:id="page-surface-229">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00229" width="4944px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="112v" xml:id="page-surface-230">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00230" width="4906px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="113r" xml:id="page-surface-231">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00231" width="4944px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="113v" xml:id="page-surface-232">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00232" width="4763px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="114r" xml:id="page-surface-233">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00233" width="4944px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="114v" xml:id="page-surface-234">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00234" width="4763px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="115r" xml:id="page-surface-235">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00235" width="4944px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="115v" xml:id="page-surface-236">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00236" width="4763px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="116r" xml:id="page-surface-237">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00237" width="4944px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="116v" xml:id="page-surface-238">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00238" width="4763px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="117r" xml:id="page-surface-239">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00239" width="4944px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="117v" xml:id="page-surface-240">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00240" width="4763px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="118r" xml:id="page-surface-241">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00241" width="4944px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="118v" xml:id="page-surface-242">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00242" width="4763px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="119r" xml:id="page-surface-243">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00243" width="4944px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="119v" xml:id="page-surface-244">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00244" width="4763px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="120r" xml:id="page-surface-245">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00245" width="4944px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="120v" xml:id="page-surface-246">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00246" width="4763px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="121r" xml:id="page-surface-247">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00247" width="4944px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="121v" xml:id="page-surface-248">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00248" width="4763px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="122r" xml:id="page-surface-249">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00249" width="4944px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="122v" xml:id="page-surface-250">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00250" width="4813px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="123r" xml:id="page-surface-251">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00251" width="4944px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="123v" xml:id="page-surface-252">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00252" width="4813px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="124r" xml:id="page-surface-253">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00253" width="4944px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="124v" xml:id="page-surface-254">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00254" width="4813px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="125r" xml:id="page-surface-255">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00255" width="4944px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="125v" xml:id="page-surface-256">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00256" width="4813px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="126r" xml:id="page-surface-257">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00257" width="4944px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="126v" xml:id="page-surface-258">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00258" width="4770px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="127r" xml:id="page-surface-259">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00259" width="4944px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="127v" xml:id="page-surface-260">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00260" width="4925px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="128r" xml:id="page-surface-261">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00261" width="5022px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="128v" xml:id="page-surface-262">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00262" width="4951px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="129r" xml:id="page-surface-263">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00263" width="5022px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="129v" xml:id="page-surface-264">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00264" width="4903px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="130r" xml:id="page-surface-265">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00265" width="5022px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="130v" xml:id="page-surface-266">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00266" width="4903px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="131r" xml:id="page-surface-267">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00267" width="5022px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="131v" xml:id="page-surface-268">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00268" width="4903px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="132r" xml:id="page-surface-269">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00269" width="5022px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="132v" xml:id="page-surface-270">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00270" width="4903px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="133r" xml:id="page-surface-271">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00271" width="5022px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="133v" xml:id="page-surface-272">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00272" width="4882px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="134r" xml:id="page-surface-273">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00273" width="5022px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="134v" xml:id="page-surface-274">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00274" width="4903px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="135r" xml:id="page-surface-275">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00275" width="5022px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="135v" xml:id="page-surface-276">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00276" width="4903px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="136r" xml:id="page-surface-277">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00277" width="5022px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="136v" xml:id="page-surface-278">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00278" width="4903px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="137r" xml:id="page-surface-279">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00279" width="5022px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="137v" xml:id="page-surface-280">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00280" width="4903px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="138r" xml:id="page-surface-281">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00281" width="4951px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="138v" xml:id="page-surface-282">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00282" width="4903px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="139r" xml:id="page-surface-283">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00283" width="4951px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="139v" xml:id="page-surface-284">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00284" width="4735px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="140r" xml:id="page-surface-285">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00285" width="4951px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="140v" xml:id="page-surface-286">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00286" width="4735px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="141r" xml:id="page-surface-287">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00287" width="4951px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="141v" xml:id="page-surface-288">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00288" width="4863px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="142r" xml:id="page-surface-289">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00289" width="4951px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="142v" xml:id="page-surface-290">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00290" width="4863px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="143r" xml:id="page-surface-291">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00291" width="4951px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="143v" xml:id="page-surface-292">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00292" width="4863px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="144r" xml:id="page-surface-293">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00293" width="4951px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="144v" xml:id="page-surface-294">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00294" width="4863px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="145r" xml:id="page-surface-295">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00295" width="4951px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="145v" xml:id="page-surface-296">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00296" width="4863px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="146r" xml:id="page-surface-297">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00297" width="4951px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="146v" xml:id="page-surface-298">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00298" width="4968px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="147r" xml:id="page-surface-299">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00299" width="4951px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="147v" xml:id="page-surface-300">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00300" width="4968px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="148r" xml:id="page-surface-301">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00301" width="4951px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="148v" xml:id="page-surface-302">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00302" width="4968px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="149r" xml:id="page-surface-303">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00303" width="4951px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="149v" xml:id="page-surface-304">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00304" width="4968px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="150r" xml:id="page-surface-305">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00305" width="4951px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="150v" xml:id="page-surface-306">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00306" width="4968px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="151r" xml:id="page-surface-307">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00307" width="4951px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="151v" xml:id="page-surface-308">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00308" width="4968px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="152r" xml:id="page-surface-309">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00309" width="5188px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="152v" xml:id="page-surface-310">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00310" width="5059px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="153r" xml:id="page-surface-311">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00311" width="5188px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="153v" xml:id="page-surface-312">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00312" width="5059px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="154r" xml:id="page-surface-313">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00313" width="5188px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="154v" xml:id="page-surface-314">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00314" width="5059px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="155r" xml:id="page-surface-315">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00315" width="5188px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="155v" xml:id="page-surface-316">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00316" width="5059px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="156r" xml:id="page-surface-317">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00317" width="5188px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="156v" xml:id="page-surface-318">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00318" width="5059px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="157r" xml:id="page-surface-319">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00319" width="5188px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="157v" xml:id="page-surface-320">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00320" width="5059px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="158r" xml:id="page-surface-321">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00321" width="5188px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="158v" xml:id="page-surface-322">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00322" width="5059px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="159r" xml:id="page-surface-323">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00323" width="5188px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="159v" xml:id="page-surface-324">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00324" width="5059px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="160r" xml:id="page-surface-325">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00325" width="5188px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="160v" xml:id="page-surface-326">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00326" width="5059px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="161r" xml:id="page-surface-327">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00327" width="5188px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="161v" xml:id="page-surface-328">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00328" width="5059px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="162r" xml:id="page-surface-329">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00329" width="5188px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="162v" xml:id="page-surface-330">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00330" width="5059px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="163r" xml:id="page-surface-331">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00331" width="5188px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="163v" xml:id="page-surface-332">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00332" width="5093px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="164r" xml:id="page-surface-333">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00333" width="5188px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="164v" xml:id="page-surface-334">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00334" width="5093px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="165r" xml:id="page-surface-335">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00335" width="5229px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="165v" xml:id="page-surface-336">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00336" width="5093px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="166r" xml:id="page-surface-337">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00337" width="5229px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="166v" xml:id="page-surface-338">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00338" width="5093px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="167r" xml:id="page-surface-339">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00339" width="5229px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="167v" xml:id="page-surface-340">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00340" width="5093px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="168r" xml:id="page-surface-341">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00341" width="5229px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="168v" xml:id="page-surface-342">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00342" width="5093px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="169r" xml:id="page-surface-343">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00343" width="5229px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="169v" xml:id="page-surface-344">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00344" width="5093px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="170r" xml:id="page-surface-345">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00345" width="5229px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="170v" xml:id="page-surface-346">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00346" width="5093px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="171r" xml:id="page-surface-347">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00347" width="5229px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="171v" xml:id="page-surface-348">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00348" width="5093px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="172r" xml:id="page-surface-349">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00349" width="5229px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="172v" xml:id="page-surface-350">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00350" width="5093px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="173r" xml:id="page-surface-351">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00351" width="5229px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="173v" xml:id="page-surface-352">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00352" width="5093px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="174r" xml:id="page-surface-353">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00353" width="5229px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="174v" xml:id="page-surface-354">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00354" width="5093px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="175r" xml:id="page-surface-355">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00355" width="5229px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="175v" xml:id="page-surface-356">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00356" width="5093px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="176r" xml:id="page-surface-357">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00357" width="5229px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="176v" xml:id="page-surface-358">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00358" width="5093px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="177r" xml:id="page-surface-359">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00359" width="5333px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="177v" xml:id="page-surface-360">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00360" width="5208px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="178r" xml:id="page-surface-361">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00361" width="5312px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="178v" xml:id="page-surface-362">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00362" width="5208px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="179r" xml:id="page-surface-363">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00363" width="5312px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="179v" xml:id="page-surface-364">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00364" width="5208px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="180r" xml:id="page-surface-365">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00365" width="5312px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="180v" xml:id="page-surface-366">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00366" width="5208px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="181r" xml:id="page-surface-367">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00367" width="5312px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="181v" xml:id="page-surface-368">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00368" width="5208px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="182r" xml:id="page-surface-369">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00369" width="5312px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="182v" xml:id="page-surface-370">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00370" width="5208px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="183r" xml:id="page-surface-371">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00371" width="5312px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="183v" xml:id="page-surface-372">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00372" width="5208px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="184r" xml:id="page-surface-373">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00373" width="5292px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="184v" xml:id="page-surface-374">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00374" width="5208px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="185r" xml:id="page-surface-375">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00375" width="5292px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="185v" xml:id="page-surface-376">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00376" width="5208px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="186r" xml:id="page-surface-377">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00377" width="5292px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="186v" xml:id="page-surface-378">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00378" width="5208px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="187r" xml:id="page-surface-379">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00379" width="5292px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="187v" xml:id="page-surface-380">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00380" width="5208px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="188r" xml:id="page-surface-381">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00381" width="5292px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="188v" xml:id="page-surface-382">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00382" width="5208px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="189r" xml:id="page-surface-383">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00383" width="5292px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="189v" xml:id="page-surface-384">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00384" width="5208px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="190r" xml:id="page-surface-385">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00385" width="5292px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="190v" xml:id="page-surface-386">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00386" width="5208px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="191r" xml:id="page-surface-387">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00387" width="5292px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="191v" xml:id="page-surface-388">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00388" width="5208px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="192r" xml:id="page-surface-389">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00389" width="5515px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="192v" xml:id="page-surface-390">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00390" width="5325px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="[193] recto" xml:id="page-surface-391">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8703px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00391" width="5515px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="[193] verso" xml:id="page-surface-392">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8663px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00392" width="5263px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="inside right cover" xml:id="page-surface-393">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9455px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00393" width="7460px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="outside right cover" xml:id="page-surface-394">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="9353px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00394" width="7713px"/>
        </surface>
        <surface n="spine" xml:id="page-surface-395">
            <graphic decls="#downloadImageRights #download" height="8280px" rend="portrait" url="MS-PETERHOUSE-00251-000-00395" width="3143px"/>
        </surface>
    </facsimile>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-1" n="outside left cover" xml:id="page-pb-1"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-2" n="inside left cover" xml:id="page-pb-2"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-3" n="[ia] recto" xml:id="page-pb-3"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-4" n="[ia] verso" xml:id="page-pb-4"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-5" n="i recto" xml:id="page-pb-5"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-6" n="i verso" xml:id="page-pb-6"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-7" n="1r" xml:id="page-pb-7"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-8" n="1v" xml:id="page-pb-8"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-9" n="2r" xml:id="page-pb-9"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-10" n="2v" xml:id="page-pb-10"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-11" n="3r" xml:id="page-pb-11"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-12" n="3v" xml:id="page-pb-12"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-13" n="4r" xml:id="page-pb-13"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-14" n="4v" xml:id="page-pb-14"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-15" n="5r" xml:id="page-pb-15"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-16" n="5v" xml:id="page-pb-16"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-17" n="6r" xml:id="page-pb-17"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-18" n="6v" xml:id="page-pb-18"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-19" n="7r" xml:id="page-pb-19"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-20" n="7v" xml:id="page-pb-20"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-21" n="8r" xml:id="page-pb-21"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-22" n="8v" xml:id="page-pb-22"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-23" n="9r" xml:id="page-pb-23"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-24" n="9v" xml:id="page-pb-24"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-25" n="10r" xml:id="page-pb-25"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-26" n="10v" xml:id="page-pb-26"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-27" n="11r" xml:id="page-pb-27"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-28" n="11v" xml:id="page-pb-28"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-29" n="12r" xml:id="page-pb-29"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-30" n="12v" xml:id="page-pb-30"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-31" n="13r" xml:id="page-pb-31"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-32" n="13v" xml:id="page-pb-32"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-33" n="14r" xml:id="page-pb-33"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-34" n="14v" xml:id="page-pb-34"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-35" n="15r" xml:id="page-pb-35"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-36" n="15v" xml:id="page-pb-36"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-37" n="16r" xml:id="page-pb-37"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-38" n="16v" xml:id="page-pb-38"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-39" n="17r" xml:id="page-pb-39"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-40" n="17v" xml:id="page-pb-40"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-41" n="18r" xml:id="page-pb-41"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-42" n="18v" xml:id="page-pb-42"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-43" n="19r" xml:id="page-pb-43"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-44" n="19v" xml:id="page-pb-44"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-45" n="20r" xml:id="page-pb-45"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-46" n="20v" xml:id="page-pb-46"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-47" n="21r" xml:id="page-pb-47"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-48" n="21v" xml:id="page-pb-48"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-49" n="22r" xml:id="page-pb-49"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-50" n="22v" xml:id="page-pb-50"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-51" n="23r" xml:id="page-pb-51"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-52" n="23v" xml:id="page-pb-52"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-53" n="24r" xml:id="page-pb-53"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-54" n="24v" xml:id="page-pb-54"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-55" n="25r" xml:id="page-pb-55"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-56" n="25v" xml:id="page-pb-56"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-57" n="26r" xml:id="page-pb-57"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-58" n="26v" xml:id="page-pb-58"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-59" n="27r" xml:id="page-pb-59"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-60" n="27v" xml:id="page-pb-60"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-61" n="28r" xml:id="page-pb-61"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-62" n="28v" xml:id="page-pb-62"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-63" n="29r" xml:id="page-pb-63"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-64" n="29v" xml:id="page-pb-64"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-65" n="30r" xml:id="page-pb-65"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-66" n="30v" xml:id="page-pb-66"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-67" n="31r" xml:id="page-pb-67"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-68" n="31v" xml:id="page-pb-68"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-69" n="32r" xml:id="page-pb-69"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-70" n="32v" xml:id="page-pb-70"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-71" n="33r" xml:id="page-pb-71"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-72" n="33v" xml:id="page-pb-72"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-73" n="34r" xml:id="page-pb-73"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-74" n="34v" xml:id="page-pb-74"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-75" n="35r" xml:id="page-pb-75"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-76" n="35v" xml:id="page-pb-76"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-77" n="36r" xml:id="page-pb-77"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-78" n="36v" xml:id="page-pb-78"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-79" n="37r" xml:id="page-pb-79"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-80" n="37v" xml:id="page-pb-80"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-81" n="38r" xml:id="page-pb-81"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-82" n="38v" xml:id="page-pb-82"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-83" n="39r" xml:id="page-pb-83"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-84" n="39v" xml:id="page-pb-84"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-85" n="40r" xml:id="page-pb-85"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-86" n="40v" xml:id="page-pb-86"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-87" n="41r" xml:id="page-pb-87"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-88" n="41v" xml:id="page-pb-88"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-89" n="42r" xml:id="page-pb-89"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-90" n="42v" xml:id="page-pb-90"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-91" n="43r" xml:id="page-pb-91"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-92" n="43v" xml:id="page-pb-92"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-93" n="44r" xml:id="page-pb-93"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-94" n="44v" xml:id="page-pb-94"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-95" n="45r" xml:id="page-pb-95"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-96" n="45v" xml:id="page-pb-96"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-97" n="46r" xml:id="page-pb-97"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-98" n="46v" xml:id="page-pb-98"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-99" n="47r" xml:id="page-pb-99"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-100" n="47v" xml:id="page-pb-100"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-101" n="48r" xml:id="page-pb-101"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-102" n="48v" xml:id="page-pb-102"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-103" n="49r" xml:id="page-pb-103"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-104" n="49v" xml:id="page-pb-104"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-105" n="50r" xml:id="page-pb-105"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-106" n="50v" xml:id="page-pb-106"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-107" n="51r" xml:id="page-pb-107"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-108" n="51v" xml:id="page-pb-108"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-109" n="52r" xml:id="page-pb-109"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-110" n="52v" xml:id="page-pb-110"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-111" n="53r" xml:id="page-pb-111"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-112" n="53v" xml:id="page-pb-112"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-113" n="54r" xml:id="page-pb-113"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-114" n="54v" xml:id="page-pb-114"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-115" n="55r" xml:id="page-pb-115"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-116" n="55v" xml:id="page-pb-116"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-117" n="56r" xml:id="page-pb-117"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-118" n="56v" xml:id="page-pb-118"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-119" n="57r" xml:id="page-pb-119"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-120" n="57v" xml:id="page-pb-120"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-121" n="58r" xml:id="page-pb-121"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-122" n="58v" xml:id="page-pb-122"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-123" n="59r" xml:id="page-pb-123"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-124" n="59v" xml:id="page-pb-124"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-125" n="60r" xml:id="page-pb-125"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-126" n="60v" xml:id="page-pb-126"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-127" n="61r" xml:id="page-pb-127"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-128" n="61v" xml:id="page-pb-128"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-129" n="62r" xml:id="page-pb-129"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-130" n="62v" xml:id="page-pb-130"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-131" n="63r" xml:id="page-pb-131"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-132" n="63v" xml:id="page-pb-132"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-133" n="64r" xml:id="page-pb-133"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-134" n="64v" xml:id="page-pb-134"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-135" n="65r" xml:id="page-pb-135"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-136" n="65v" xml:id="page-pb-136"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-137" n="66r" xml:id="page-pb-137"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-138" n="66v" xml:id="page-pb-138"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-139" n="67r" xml:id="page-pb-139"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-140" n="67v" xml:id="page-pb-140"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-141" n="68r" xml:id="page-pb-141"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-142" n="68v" xml:id="page-pb-142"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-143" n="69r" xml:id="page-pb-143"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-144" n="69v" xml:id="page-pb-144"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-145" n="70r" xml:id="page-pb-145"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-146" n="70v" xml:id="page-pb-146"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-147" n="71r" xml:id="page-pb-147"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-148" n="71v" xml:id="page-pb-148"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-149" n="72r" xml:id="page-pb-149"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-150" n="72v" xml:id="page-pb-150"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-151" n="73r" xml:id="page-pb-151"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-152" n="73v" xml:id="page-pb-152"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-153" n="74r" xml:id="page-pb-153"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-154" n="74v" xml:id="page-pb-154"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-155" n="75r" xml:id="page-pb-155"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-156" n="75v" xml:id="page-pb-156"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-157" n="76r" xml:id="page-pb-157"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-158" n="76v" xml:id="page-pb-158"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-159" n="77r" xml:id="page-pb-159"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-160" n="77v" xml:id="page-pb-160"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-161" n="78r" xml:id="page-pb-161"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-162" n="78v" xml:id="page-pb-162"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-163" n="79r" xml:id="page-pb-163"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-164" n="79v" xml:id="page-pb-164"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-165" n="80r" xml:id="page-pb-165"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-166" n="80v" xml:id="page-pb-166"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-167" n="81r" xml:id="page-pb-167"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-168" n="81v" xml:id="page-pb-168"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-169" n="82r" xml:id="page-pb-169"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-170" n="82v" xml:id="page-pb-170"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-171" n="83r" xml:id="page-pb-171"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-172" n="83v" xml:id="page-pb-172"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-173" n="84r" xml:id="page-pb-173"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-174" n="84v" xml:id="page-pb-174"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-175" n="85r" xml:id="page-pb-175"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-176" n="85v" xml:id="page-pb-176"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-177" n="86r" xml:id="page-pb-177"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-178" n="86v" xml:id="page-pb-178"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-179" n="87r" xml:id="page-pb-179"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-180" n="87v" xml:id="page-pb-180"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-181" n="88r" xml:id="page-pb-181"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-182" n="88v" xml:id="page-pb-182"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-183" n="89r" xml:id="page-pb-183"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-184" n="89v" xml:id="page-pb-184"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-185" n="90r" xml:id="page-pb-185"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-186" n="90v" xml:id="page-pb-186"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-187" n="91r" xml:id="page-pb-187"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-188" n="91v" xml:id="page-pb-188"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-189" n="92r" xml:id="page-pb-189"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-190" n="92v" xml:id="page-pb-190"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-191" n="93r" xml:id="page-pb-191"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-192" n="93v" xml:id="page-pb-192"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-193" n="94r" xml:id="page-pb-193"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-194" n="94v" xml:id="page-pb-194"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-195" n="95r" xml:id="page-pb-195"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-196" n="95v" xml:id="page-pb-196"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-197" n="96r" xml:id="page-pb-197"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-198" n="96v" xml:id="page-pb-198"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-199" n="97r" xml:id="page-pb-199"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-200" n="97v" xml:id="page-pb-200"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-201" n="98r" xml:id="page-pb-201"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-202" n="98v" xml:id="page-pb-202"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-203" n="99r" xml:id="page-pb-203"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-204" n="99v" xml:id="page-pb-204"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-205" n="100r" xml:id="page-pb-205"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-206" n="100v" xml:id="page-pb-206"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-207" n="101r" xml:id="page-pb-207"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-208" n="101v" xml:id="page-pb-208"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-209" n="102r" xml:id="page-pb-209"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-210" n="102v" xml:id="page-pb-210"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-211" n="103r" xml:id="page-pb-211"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-212" n="103v" xml:id="page-pb-212"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-213" n="104r" xml:id="page-pb-213"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-214" n="104v" xml:id="page-pb-214"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-215" n="105r" xml:id="page-pb-215"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-216" n="105v" xml:id="page-pb-216"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-217" n="106r" xml:id="page-pb-217"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-218" n="106v" xml:id="page-pb-218"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-219" n="107r" xml:id="page-pb-219"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-220" n="107v" xml:id="page-pb-220"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-221" n="108r" xml:id="page-pb-221"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-222" n="108v" xml:id="page-pb-222"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-223" n="109r" xml:id="page-pb-223"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-224" n="109v" xml:id="page-pb-224"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-225" n="110r" xml:id="page-pb-225"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-226" n="110v" xml:id="page-pb-226"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-227" n="111r" xml:id="page-pb-227"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-228" n="111v" xml:id="page-pb-228"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-229" n="112r" xml:id="page-pb-229"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-230" n="112v" xml:id="page-pb-230"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-231" n="113r" xml:id="page-pb-231"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-232" n="113v" xml:id="page-pb-232"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-233" n="114r" xml:id="page-pb-233"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-234" n="114v" xml:id="page-pb-234"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-235" n="115r" xml:id="page-pb-235"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-236" n="115v" xml:id="page-pb-236"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-237" n="116r" xml:id="page-pb-237"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-238" n="116v" xml:id="page-pb-238"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-239" n="117r" xml:id="page-pb-239"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-240" n="117v" xml:id="page-pb-240"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-241" n="118r" xml:id="page-pb-241"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-242" n="118v" xml:id="page-pb-242"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-243" n="119r" xml:id="page-pb-243"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-244" n="119v" xml:id="page-pb-244"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-245" n="120r" xml:id="page-pb-245"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-246" n="120v" xml:id="page-pb-246"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-247" n="121r" xml:id="page-pb-247"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-248" n="121v" xml:id="page-pb-248"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-249" n="122r" xml:id="page-pb-249"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-250" n="122v" xml:id="page-pb-250"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-251" n="123r" xml:id="page-pb-251"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-252" n="123v" xml:id="page-pb-252"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-253" n="124r" xml:id="page-pb-253"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-254" n="124v" xml:id="page-pb-254"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-255" n="125r" xml:id="page-pb-255"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-256" n="125v" xml:id="page-pb-256"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-257" n="126r" xml:id="page-pb-257"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-258" n="126v" xml:id="page-pb-258"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-259" n="127r" xml:id="page-pb-259"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-260" n="127v" xml:id="page-pb-260"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-261" n="128r" xml:id="page-pb-261"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-262" n="128v" xml:id="page-pb-262"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-263" n="129r" xml:id="page-pb-263"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-264" n="129v" xml:id="page-pb-264"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-265" n="130r" xml:id="page-pb-265"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-266" n="130v" xml:id="page-pb-266"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-267" n="131r" xml:id="page-pb-267"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-268" n="131v" xml:id="page-pb-268"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-269" n="132r" xml:id="page-pb-269"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-270" n="132v" xml:id="page-pb-270"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-271" n="133r" xml:id="page-pb-271"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-272" n="133v" xml:id="page-pb-272"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-273" n="134r" xml:id="page-pb-273"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-274" n="134v" xml:id="page-pb-274"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-275" n="135r" xml:id="page-pb-275"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-276" n="135v" xml:id="page-pb-276"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-277" n="136r" xml:id="page-pb-277"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-278" n="136v" xml:id="page-pb-278"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-279" n="137r" xml:id="page-pb-279"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-280" n="137v" xml:id="page-pb-280"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-281" n="138r" xml:id="page-pb-281"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-282" n="138v" xml:id="page-pb-282"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-283" n="139r" xml:id="page-pb-283"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-284" n="139v" xml:id="page-pb-284"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-285" n="140r" xml:id="page-pb-285"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-286" n="140v" xml:id="page-pb-286"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-287" n="141r" xml:id="page-pb-287"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-288" n="141v" xml:id="page-pb-288"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-289" n="142r" xml:id="page-pb-289"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-290" n="142v" xml:id="page-pb-290"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-291" n="143r" xml:id="page-pb-291"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-292" n="143v" xml:id="page-pb-292"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-293" n="144r" xml:id="page-pb-293"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-294" n="144v" xml:id="page-pb-294"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-295" n="145r" xml:id="page-pb-295"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-296" n="145v" xml:id="page-pb-296"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-297" n="146r" xml:id="page-pb-297"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-298" n="146v" xml:id="page-pb-298"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-299" n="147r" xml:id="page-pb-299"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-300" n="147v" xml:id="page-pb-300"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-301" n="148r" xml:id="page-pb-301"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-302" n="148v" xml:id="page-pb-302"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-303" n="149r" xml:id="page-pb-303"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-304" n="149v" xml:id="page-pb-304"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-305" n="150r" xml:id="page-pb-305"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-306" n="150v" xml:id="page-pb-306"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-307" n="151r" xml:id="page-pb-307"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-308" n="151v" xml:id="page-pb-308"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-309" n="152r" xml:id="page-pb-309"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-310" n="152v" xml:id="page-pb-310"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-311" n="153r" xml:id="page-pb-311"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-312" n="153v" xml:id="page-pb-312"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-313" n="154r" xml:id="page-pb-313"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-314" n="154v" xml:id="page-pb-314"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-315" n="155r" xml:id="page-pb-315"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-316" n="155v" xml:id="page-pb-316"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-317" n="156r" xml:id="page-pb-317"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-318" n="156v" xml:id="page-pb-318"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-319" n="157r" xml:id="page-pb-319"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-320" n="157v" xml:id="page-pb-320"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-321" n="158r" xml:id="page-pb-321"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-322" n="158v" xml:id="page-pb-322"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-323" n="159r" xml:id="page-pb-323"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-324" n="159v" xml:id="page-pb-324"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-325" n="160r" xml:id="page-pb-325"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-326" n="160v" xml:id="page-pb-326"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-327" n="161r" xml:id="page-pb-327"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-328" n="161v" xml:id="page-pb-328"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-329" n="162r" xml:id="page-pb-329"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-330" n="162v" xml:id="page-pb-330"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-331" n="163r" xml:id="page-pb-331"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-332" n="163v" xml:id="page-pb-332"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-333" n="164r" xml:id="page-pb-333"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-334" n="164v" xml:id="page-pb-334"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-335" n="165r" xml:id="page-pb-335"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-336" n="165v" xml:id="page-pb-336"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-337" n="166r" xml:id="page-pb-337"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-338" n="166v" xml:id="page-pb-338"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-339" n="167r" xml:id="page-pb-339"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-340" n="167v" xml:id="page-pb-340"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-341" n="168r" xml:id="page-pb-341"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-342" n="168v" xml:id="page-pb-342"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-343" n="169r" xml:id="page-pb-343"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-344" n="169v" xml:id="page-pb-344"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-345" n="170r" xml:id="page-pb-345"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-346" n="170v" xml:id="page-pb-346"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-347" n="171r" xml:id="page-pb-347"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-348" n="171v" xml:id="page-pb-348"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-349" n="172r" xml:id="page-pb-349"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-350" n="172v" xml:id="page-pb-350"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-351" n="173r" xml:id="page-pb-351"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-352" n="173v" xml:id="page-pb-352"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-353" n="174r" xml:id="page-pb-353"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-354" n="174v" xml:id="page-pb-354"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-355" n="175r" xml:id="page-pb-355"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-356" n="175v" xml:id="page-pb-356"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-357" n="176r" xml:id="page-pb-357"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-358" n="176v" xml:id="page-pb-358"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-359" n="177r" xml:id="page-pb-359"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-360" n="177v" xml:id="page-pb-360"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-361" n="178r" xml:id="page-pb-361"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-362" n="178v" xml:id="page-pb-362"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-363" n="179r" xml:id="page-pb-363"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-364" n="179v" xml:id="page-pb-364"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-365" n="180r" xml:id="page-pb-365"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-366" n="180v" xml:id="page-pb-366"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-367" n="181r" xml:id="page-pb-367"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-368" n="181v" xml:id="page-pb-368"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-369" n="182r" xml:id="page-pb-369"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-370" n="182v" xml:id="page-pb-370"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-371" n="183r" xml:id="page-pb-371"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-372" n="183v" xml:id="page-pb-372"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-373" n="184r" xml:id="page-pb-373"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-374" n="184v" xml:id="page-pb-374"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-375" n="185r" xml:id="page-pb-375"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-376" n="185v" xml:id="page-pb-376"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-377" n="186r" xml:id="page-pb-377"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-378" n="186v" xml:id="page-pb-378"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-379" n="187r" xml:id="page-pb-379"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-380" n="187v" xml:id="page-pb-380"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-381" n="188r" xml:id="page-pb-381"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-382" n="188v" xml:id="page-pb-382"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-383" n="189r" xml:id="page-pb-383"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-384" n="189v" xml:id="page-pb-384"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-385" n="190r" xml:id="page-pb-385"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-386" n="190v" xml:id="page-pb-386"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-387" n="191r" xml:id="page-pb-387"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-388" n="191v" xml:id="page-pb-388"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-389" n="192r" xml:id="page-pb-389"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-390" n="192v" xml:id="page-pb-390"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-391" n="[193] recto" xml:id="page-pb-391"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-392" n="[193] verso" xml:id="page-pb-392"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-393" n="inside right cover" xml:id="page-pb-393"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-394" n="outside right cover" xml:id="page-pb-394"/>
                <pb facs="#page-surface-395" n="spine" xml:id="page-pb-395"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
